To simulate the modern attacks,
such as the so
called advanced persistent threats.
Penetration testing can try
to be persistent and stealth.
For example, the tester can install
a backdoor through a malware so
that there's a permanent
foothold in the network.
The malware can be placed in
a strategic place such as a proxy.
And the result can be that now
the malware can listen and
record all traffic within the network.
And by analyzing internal traffic, the
malware can capture user credentials and
find out valuable information.
These steps can be iterated and
moved from one port of the network
to the next while hiding the tracks.