As we discussed earlier, penetration
testing can include social engineering.
So now let's discuss social engineering.
We all know that users
are the weakest link in security,
so the goal here is to use social
engineering techniques to evaluate
how vulnerable your user
population really is.
In particular,
you will want to find out which user
groups are particularly vulnerable.
You will likely discover policy gaps, so
you will want to fix these policies and
develop new mechanisms including
educating and training the users.
Social engineering is effective
when the users are manipulated
into undermining the security
of their own systems.
This can be accomplished by abusing
the trust relationships among the users.
Social engineering can be very easy and
cheap for the attacker
because the attacker does not need any
specialized tools or technical skills.