Let's have an overview of what
penetration testing is all about.
Penetration testing is used to
evaluate the security of a network.
More specifically,
penetration testing is used to
evaluate all security controls.
These include the security procedures,
the operations, and the technologies.
With penetration testing, you can find
out how secure your network really is.
In particular, you can discover
security vulnerabilities.
And by actually exploiting
the vulnerabilities,
you can also demonstrate how likely
the threats can take place and
what are the likely damages
associated with these threats.
The scope of penetration testing
include not just technical or
cyber operations, it can also
include social engineering, and
also gaining physical access
to your organization.
The scale of the testing
includes the entire network.
For example, the testing may include
your mobile devices, or BYOD.