Now let's discuss social engineering
attacks that involves computers.
The first kind is popup windows.
For example, a popup window can
pretend to be a login window.
This exploit will work if the users
have not been properly trained
to tell the difference between the fake
and the legitimate login windows.
The attacker can also use IM or
IRC to fake a technical support desk.
And the users would be redirected
to a malicious site and
malware can then be downloaded.
An attacker can also check
the user to open an email and
download email attachment which
includes malicious software.
There are many ways to
hide malicious programs
in email attachments that
may appear to be legitimate.
For example, PDF files can
include executable macros and
a .exe file can be
camouflaged into a .doc file.
And of course, we are familiar
with various kinds of email scams.
the attackers can amplify the effects
of email scams using chain emails.
For example, an email can be sent
to everybody on your address book.
An attacker can create a website
that claims to offer prizes but
require the user to create login and
passwords.
The goal of the attacker is
to harvest user credentials
since many users uses same username and
password on many websites.
The attacker can then use the
credentials obtained from his website
on other websites.