Here's how we should educate users to
counter social engineering attacks.
Never disclose passwords to anybody.
Only the IT staff should discussed
details of the network and
system configurations and IT staff
should not answers survey calls.
This also check with the call
from the vendor is legitimate.
Also, we should limit information
in all auto-reply emails.
Keep information in all auto-reply
emails to a bare minimum.
We should always escort our guests.
This protects against attacks such as
attackers dressing up like repairmen or
trusted authority figure.
We should always question
people that we don't know.
We should educate all employees about
security, both physical and IT security.
We should have a central reporting and
management of all suspicious behavior.