Now, let's discuss these
steps in more details.
The first step is footprinting.
In this step, the attacker, or
tester, conducts reconnaissance and
information gathering.
The important network information
includes network IP addresses,
the namespace, and topology.
Even a phone number range can be used
for modem access or social engineering.
Such information is critical for
planning the next steps of testing or
attacks.
Example, you will need the IP addresses
to decide how to scan the network.
Here we'll list the different techniques
and the corresponding tools for
footprinting.
For example, you can use Google to
find out the company information, and
use Whois to find out the domain name
information of the name servers and
IP ranges.