Welcome to Network Security.
When we think about network security, we
need to think about ways we can protect
our most valuable network assets,
data, and access to the data.
We need to protect it from misuse,
authorized modification, and
destruction.
We need to make sure assets
is restricted only to those
who are granted access.
Sun Tzu said in the Art of War,
Know thy self, know thy enemy.
A thousand battles and
a thousand victories.
Now that may seem a little extreme but
it is not.
We are at war.
Our enemies are hackers, scammers,
and script kitties off the internet.
The battlefield is our networks and
the price is our data.
Network security requires us to use
all hardware and software means
at our disposal to protect our assets
and to effectively deploy them.
In this course, we're going to learn
about our enemies, their motivations,
methods, and attacks.
We also going to investigate how
defensive weapons and counter attacks.
Once you have completed this course, you
will have a clear understanding of who,
how, and hopefully even why
our networks are under attack.
And what you must do to prevent or
at least minimize the damage.