Address Resolution Protocol or ARP is
a protocol designed to map IP network
addresses to the hardware addresses
used by the data link protocol.
Open Shortest Path First or
OSPF is a protocol
that uses a link state routing
algorithm for interior routing.
Border Gateway Protocol or
BGP is a protocol designed to exchange
routing and reachability information
among autonomous systems or AS.
Here's an example of how op works.
Supposed a router received data
with a destination IP address
of a host within each
local area network.
It needs to know the MAC address or
the destination IP address in order
to send the data to the host.
This is because machines on the same
local area network identify each other
via MAC addresses.
Here, the router sends
an OP request asking for
the MAC address of
the specified IP address.
This request will reach all
computers on a network because
the destination MAC address is one
there's accepted by all computers.
The ARP reply essentially says, hey,
I'm the host with the IP address and
here's my MAC address.
On OSPF looks for
the lowest cost path within nodes.
In this instance, let's assume that
all the lengths are of the same cost.
What would be the shortest path
between the node R3 and R5?
Obviously, the shortest path is to
go from R3 to R4 and then, to R5.
In BPG, the autonomous systems exchange
information through peer exchanges.
In this example, each AS talks to a peer
to learn the address prefix of
the computers within their peer network.
This helps the ASs to work
together to determine
how to route traffic from
one network to the other.