Denial of service attack.
The attacker hacks the routing table and
either adds a false route or
kills a legitimate one.
Sniffing.
An attacker needs to control a device
along the communication route.
To do this, the attacker can BGP to
detour traffic through a malicious site.
Routing to endpoints
in malicious networks.
This requires that the attacker
redirect traffic away
from a legitimate host to
an attacker-controlled site.
Creating route instabilities.
This has not been
exploited by attackers yet.
These instabilities
are too unpredictable and
can cause attacker to be
affected by their own attack.
However, there is a possibility
that script kiddies
could begin to exploit them.
Revelation of network topologies.
This begins with attacker gaining
access to the routing table and
can, with patience, discover
the peer relations among the ASs.
Now let's discuss some solutions
to the BGP security issues.
One solution is around PKI,
or Public Key Infrastructure.
Here, each AS obtains
a certificate to certify each
route origination authority from
the regional Internet register, and
then attach the ROA to
path advertisement.
Essentially, each AS that advertise
a path is a route origination authority.
Another solution is to use SBGP.
The main idea here is to sign
every hop of a path advertisement.