A DNS Lookup is an iterative or
recursive process carrying
the hierarchy code database.
For example, suppose your browser
is looking up www.cc.gatech.edu.
The local DNS service is handling
this request of looking up the IP
address of this domain name.
The query will start on the root or
top level domain servers.
That is,
the local DNS server asks the root and
top level domain servers what is
the IP address of www.cc.gatech.edu.
And these servers say, I don't know, but
I know the main server of gatech.edu.
So the local DNS server then
asks gatech.edu DNS server
what is the IP address
of www.cc.gatech.edu.
And the gatech.edu DNS server says,
I don't know but
I know the name server cc.gatech.edu.
So finally,
the name server cc.gatech.edu says,
I know the IP address of
www.cc.gatech.edu and here it is.
So that's an example of looking up
a domain name in most iterative or
recursive queries to DNS servers.
There are several types of DNS
records in the response to DNS query.
One is the NS record.
This points to a name server.
That is,
this record contains the IP address
of a name server such as gatech.edu.
And then there's A record.
This contains the address of
the domain name in the original query.
For example, www.cc.gatech.edu.
And then there's MX record.
This contains the address of
the mail server for the domain.
For example, mail.gatech.edu.
And finally, there's a TXT record.
It contains all the useful
information about a domain.
For example, it can be used
to distribute public keys.