As illustrated in the previous example,
querying the IP address of a domain
name can involve a number of steps.
To save time, the records are cached
on a local server for reuse later.
For example, when the IP address of
www.cc.gatech.edu has been obtained,
the mapping of this IP address and
the domain is cached so
that the next time the browser
is looking up www.cc.gatech.edu,
the DNS server does not have
to go out to look it up again
because the mapping is
already stored in the cache.
Obviously, this saves time.
On the other hand, each record,
meaning the mapping of IP address and
domain that's being stored in the DNS
cache, has a TTL, or time-to-live.
And, when this TTL expires,
the cache entry is invalid.
Which means, if the browser
looks up www.cc.gatech.edu,
after the TTL of the cache entry
has expired, the DNS server,
then has to go out and look it up again.
TTL is useful because a server,
say www.cc.gatech.edu maybe
moved to a new IP address.
So, you want the TTL to expire, so
that the DNS servers can look up for
the new mapping.