As we have discussed,
the DNS responses and
in particular,
the mapping between the IP address and
a domain are cached so that we can
save time on repeated queries.
The NS records of
the domains are also cached.
Therefore, if the browser
looks up www.ece.gatech.edu,
the local DNS server only needs to start
with gatech.edu instead of the root.
DNS servers can also cache the negative
results such as a domain does not exist.
For example, if somebody misspelled
gatech.edu to say gatech.ed,
the DNS query response will be
this domain does not exist.
And this result is cached.
So that, next time if somebody
mistype again the same way,
gatech.ed, the DNS cache can always say,
hey this domain does not exist,
without having to query it.
And all cache data, whether it's
positive or negative response has a TTL.