Now let's discuss the main
vulnerabilities of DNS.
First of all, we must be able
to trust the domain name and
address mapping provided by DNS.
In fact,
many security policies depend on this.
For example, the same origin policy
in browsers, or URL-based filtering.
Obviously if the host address mapping
provided by DNS can be forged,
then the traffic intended for
the original legitimate host is now
destined to the wrong or malicious host.
This means that the wrong or
forged host can now intercept
the legitimate traffic.
What if the host address mapping
provided by DNS can be forged?
For example, instead of getting
the IP address of gmail.com,
the browser instead gets
the IP address of evil.com.
The result is that, traffic will
be routed to evil.com instead.
Which means evil.com can
intercept traffic to gmail.com.
There are several ways to forge
the host as just mapping.
For example, the attackers can
compromise the DNS servers,
including cache poisoning,
which we're going to discuss shortly.
Or the attackers can control
the access point or gateway and
intercept DNS queries and
forge a response.
A solution is to authenticate each
request and response using cryptography.
And DNSsec is such a solution.
Now let's discuss attacks on the inner
server, in particular cache poisoning.
The basic idea is that the attacker
would provide to the local DNA server
some false records and
get the records cached.
For example, if the local DNS server
queries the domain gmail.com and
the attacker is able to inject a
response with the IP address of evil.com
and have that IP address of evil.com
cached by the local DNS server and
then subsequent traffic to gmail.com
will be routed to evil.com.
The existing defense in DNS is
the users 16-bit request ID
to link a respond with a query.
That is,
the attackers response must have the ID
that matches the ID of
the original query and
we will discuss how an attacker
can overcome this defense.
A DNS cache can be easily poisoned
if the DNS server does not use
the IDs properly, or
the IDS are predictable