The first statement,
DNS stores IP address.
For security reasons, the domain
name is stored somewhere else.
This is false.
DNS stores both the IP address and
the domain name.
That's the whole point of providing
the mapping between domain name and
IP address.
The second statement.
All domain names and IP addresses
are stored at the Central Registry.
This is true.
When a new domain name is
registered at a local DNS,
it will also be copied
to the Central Registry.
The third statement,
it can take several days for
information to propagate
to all DNS servers.
This is true.
It takes anywhere from 12 to 36 hours to
propagate information to
all DNS servers worldwide.