Now let's take a closer look at
the internals of DNS query and response.
Let's start with the format
of a DNS packet.
There is the usual IP header.
There's a UDP header
because DNS uses UDP, and
the UDP payload is the actual DNS data.
One of the most important fields
in DNS data is the query ID,
which is a 16 bit random value.
A DNS query contains a query ID.
And a response also carries the ID.
Therefore, even though a DNS
server may send out many, many
queries at the same time, it can use
the ID to link a response to a query.
That is, the response to a query will
have the same ID of the query ID
of the original query.
Now, let's look through an example.
Suppose a local DNS
server is looking up for
the domain www.unixvis.net
on behalf of a browser.
So, this is the local DNS server.
It's going to send the query
to one of the root service.
It sent a flag to say recursion desired.
That means it's asking the destination
DNS server to perform recursive queries
on its behalf.
Here is the response
from the root server.
The root server does not know
the IP address of www.unixwiz.net.
So it provides the IP addresses
of the next NS service.
And these are called glue records.
Let's look at this in more detail.
The response comes from the root server,
back to the local DNS server.
It says that it's a response, the root
server does not know the IP address
of www.unixwiz.net, but
it knows where to ask.
It responds with a series of
NS records that should know
how to handle the original query.
Notice that both the domain names and
IP addresses of these named
servers are provided.
Because this response is not the final
answer to the original query,
it sets this flag to zero to indicate
that this is not authoritative.
And also because the root server
is busy, it's not going to perform
because of queries on behalf
of the local DNS server.
That's why it sets this flag to
indicate that it's not going to perform
because of queries.
That is, the local DNS server should
contact these named servers instead.
The final, or authoritative,
response comes from the named server,
linux.unixwiz.net.
And notice that now
the authoritative flag is set to 1.
Notice that this final response
contains the IP address of the domain
www.unixwiz.net, which is the domain
name contained in the original query.
And the TTL is one hour, which means
this record will be cached and
be valid for one hour.
And since these NS records are in the
same second level domain, unixwiz.net,
of the original queried domain,
they are also cached.