Let's take a closer look
at amplification attacks.
Typically, the attacker uses a machine,
and then these attacker machine
controls a number of bots,
or compromised computers.
And each of these bots will send
many requests to a server, and
the response from the server is
much larger than the request.
So the amplification is
accomplished by two factors.
One is the number of bots involved.
And second, the server response
is much larger than the requests.
Here's a specific example
of amplification attack.
This involves DNS,
the domain name system.
Here's the amplification factor
involving the server, the DNS server.
So here we have the machine sending
a DnS request to the server.
And of course, the address, the source
of the DnS query is spoofed and
the server thinks that
the request is from the target.
The server response is much
larger than the request.
In this case, it is 50 times.
Here, EDNS means extension mechanism for
DNS.
It allows for actual flags and
response data.
Therefore, the response is much larger.
In a DNS-based amplification attack,
each of the bots controlled by
the attacker will send many requests
to any of the DNS resolvers.
And there are many of them.
And for each request,
the response will be sent to the target
because in each request,
the source IP address is spoofed.
The attacker can choose any
subset of the DNS servers to use
because there are so
many open DNS resolvers on Internet.
This attack can generate
a huge amount of traffic
in a very short period of time.
For example,
the attacker can easily generate tens or
even hundreds of gigabits per second
traffic targeted at a victim.