Before we discuss web security,
let's remind ourselves as to
why we need web security.
In this quiz,
match the attacks to their descriptions.
So the attacks are, using components
with known vulnerabilities,
missing function level access control,
sensitive data exposure,
security misconfiguration,
insecure direct object references,
cross site scripting, broken
authentication and session, injection.
And the descriptions are, modifies
back-end statement through user input,
inserts Javaccripts into trusted sites,
program flaws allow bypass
of authentication methods,
attackers modify file names,
abuses the lack of data encryption,
exploits misconfigured servers,
privilege functionality is hidden rather
than enforced through access controls,
uses unpatched third party components.