And the answers are the first attack
using components with
known vulnerabilities.
The description is uses
unpatched third party components
because unpatched third party
components have known vulnerabilities.
Second, missing function
level access control.
For this attack, the description
is privilege functionality is
hidden rather than enforced
through access controls.
Because the attacks here says it's
missing function level access control.
The third attack
sensitive data exposure.
For that to work,
the description is this one.
Abuses the lack of data encryption.
The next attack security
misconfiguration.
The description is exploits
misconfigured servers.
The next attack insecure
direct object references.
The description is that
the attacker can modify
file names because file names
are direct object references.
The next attack, cross site scripting.
The description is,
inserts Javascript into trusted sites.
The next one,
broken authentication and session.
The description is, program flaws allow
bypass of authentication methods.
Because the attack here exploits
broken authentication and session.
The last one, injection,
the description is modifies back-end
statement through user input.
In other words the attack action
is injected through user input.