Now, let's discuss
the goals of web security.
Obviously, we need to be able
to browse the web safely.
This means that,
when browsing a website, sensitive data
on the user's computer can not be
stolen and uploaded to the web.
And that if the web browser has multiple
open sessions with multiple sites.
For example,
one session to a bank website, and
another session is to
a social network site.
The sessions don't
interfere with each other.
Intuitively, if the social
network site is compromised,
it should not affect the user
session with the bank site.
In addition, we need to ensure that
the web applications can have
the same security protection,
as applications that run on
the operating system on our computers.