Now let's discuss
the Web Security Threat Model.
We use threat model to understand what
the web attackers are likely to do.
And we're going to compare
the Web Security Threat Model and
the Network Security Threat Model.
On the web, attacker can typically setup
a malicious website and the attacker
waits for users to visit the malicious
website so that the attack can be
launched through the malicious websites
to compromise the user's computers.
A web attacker typically does
not control the network.
Now let's look at
the Network Security Threat Model.
A network attacker can
be much more active.
Typically, we would assume that
a network attacker can intercept and
control the network.
For example, the attacker can
intercept and drop the traffic.
Or he can intercept and
perform traffic analysis
to crack open the encryption key to
read the data that's being transmitted.
Or he can inject malicious
traffic into the network.