Let's go over the various types
of attackers in more details.
For the web attacker, the attacker could
typically control a suspicious site,
say, attacker.com.
He can even obtain certificate for
his website so
that the website can interact with
users' browsers through HTTPS.
And then the attacker can wait for
the user to visit attacker.com.
For example, this can be done through
phishing and other kinds of redirect.
Or, the attacker can set up some
sort of malicious, or fake,
web app and wait for the user to
download these apps and run these apps.
The point here is that, typically,
a web attacker is somewhat passive.
He sets up some attack
infrastructure and waits for
the users to actually either visit those
sites or use those malicious apps.
A network attacker is more powerful.
He can perform both passive and
active attacks.
For example, a passive attack means
that the attacker simply intercepts and
analyze traffic to learn
about the communication.
For example, the attacker can
perform wireless eavesdropping
to crack the encryption key for
you're Wi-Fi network.
Examples of active attacks
include inserting a malicious
router in the network so that traffic
can route through the router and
be subject to the attackers attack.
That includes both passive
like eavesdropping, or
active attacks such
as traffic injection.
Another example is DNS poisoning, where
the attacker changed the DNS entry so
that a legitimate site such as cnn.com,
now has an IP address of a server
that's controlled by the attacker.
That is, legitimate traffic such as
to cnn.com will not be redirected,
so that legitimate traffic such
as those to cnn.com will now
be redirected to the attacker's machine.
The most general and
powerful attack is through malware.
By injecting a piece of malware
on the user's computer,
the attacker essentially escapes,
the browser's isolation mechanism.
And now,
has a program that runs directly under
the control of the operating system.
That is, the malware runs as any
other applications on your computer.
You may ask, why is that possible?
Isn't the browser supposed to isolate
the rest of the computer from the web?
The problem is that browser is a very
complex piece of software, and
as such, browsers may
contain exploitable bugs, and
these bugs often enable remote
execution of malicious code.
For example, when a browser visits a
site that's controlled by the attacker,
the attacker can send a webpage
that contains malicious input.
And the result is that a bug
is being exploited and
a piece of malicious software, or
malware, is now installed on a computer.
Now, even if the browsers are bug free,
there are still lots of
vulnerabilities on the web,
in particular on the web-server side.
That would enable cross-site scripting,
SQL injection,
and cross-site request forgery.
For example, SQL injection
would allow the attacker to
bypass the control of the web server,
and
directly inject attackers' code into
the back end of the SQL database.
The point is that malware
attackers can actually bypass
the basic control of web,
including browser, to actually attack
the users' computers or the web service.
So we will discuss three
main types of attackers.
The malware attacker, the network
attacker, and the web attacker.
It is obvious that a web attacker
is the least lethal because
he's mostly passive.
A network attacker is more powerful
because he can perform both passive and
active attacks.
And a malware attacker
is the most lethal and
powerful because it can inject
code into a user's computer or
a server to perform any actions
desired by the attacker.