Now let's discuss,
content security policy, or CSP.
The goal of content security
policy to prevent or
at least limit the damage
of Course side scripting.
Recall that we discussed course
side scripting attacks in CS
6035: Introduction to
Information Security.
Essentially a course
side scripting attack
bypasses the same origin policy by
tricking a site into delivering
some malicious code along
with the intended content.
For example,
a website is setup to echo the user
input as a web page back to a browser.
Such as echoing the user's name.
But if the user input
contains malicious code,
then the website will be sending
malicious code to a web browser.
With CSP, the main idea is that
a browser can be instructed
to load resources only
from a white-list.
CSP prohibits inline scripts
embedded in script tags,
inline event handlers,
JavaScript, and URLs, etc, and
also disables JavaScript eval,
new function and so on.
That means all the resources
that a browser will load
can be statically checked.
And again the resources are loaded
only from a white list.
Since there are many different
types of web contents,
with CSP we can specify the white
list for each type of web contents.
The sources of web contents
can be specified and matched.
For example, they can be specified
by scheme such as HTTPS or
HTTP, host name,
then we match any origin on that host.
Or fully qualified URI such
as https://example.com:443.
You can also specify how to match
the sources listed on a white list,
such as, wildcards accepted,
none, or self, and so on.
You can even create exceptions or
allow inline JavaScripts or
allow eval functions.