Now let's discuss SubResource Integrity.
Integrity is a very
important security goal.
In the context of web browsing,
many pages load scripts and
styles from a wide variety of service
and content delivery networks.
Given that contents can be from many
different sources and content delivery
networks, how do we ensure the integrity
of the contents that we're loading?
For example,
how do we protect against loading
contents from a malicious server?
For example,
the browser gets to the malicious
server because of DNS poisoning and
how do we ensure that contents that we
load from a Content Delivery Network
has not been modified, for
example, on purpose by the CDN?
The main ideas that the author
of the content specifies and
makes available the hash
of the contents.
And so
when the browser loads the contents,
it use the hash value
to check integrity.
For example,
the author of this stylesheet will
specify the hash of the file.
Similarly, for JavaScript,
the author can also specify its hash.
So basically, to use SubResource
Integrity, our website author
who wishes to include a resource from a
third party can specify a cryptographic
hash of that resource in addition
to the location of the resource.
Then when a browser fetches
the resource, it can compare
the hash provided by the website author
with the has computed from the resource.
If the hashes don't match,
the resource is discarded.
So, what happens when
the integrity check fails?
By default,
the browser can report the violation and
simply does not render,
or execute the resource.
Or if the directive simply says,
report that means the browser will
report the violation, but can still
render or execute the resource.