We call that when a browser connects to
a site, the server sets the cookie for
the web browsing session.
There are a number of attributes
that a server can set for a cookie.
For example SameSite means that
do not send cookie on
a cross-site post request.
Strict, means that never send
cookie on cross-site request.
Therefore, they provide some sort of
cross-site request forgery defense.
With HttpOnly, it tells the browser
that this particular cookie
should only be assessed by the server.
Any attempt to assess the cookie
from script is strictly forbidden.
This can provide defense against
cross-site scripting attacks.
And the scope of the cookie
is determined by
the combination of domain and path.