Now let's discuss some security
problems with cookies.
First of all, the server is blind and
what do we do mean by that?
It does not see all
the cookie attributes.
For example, whether the cookie
attributes include secure,
which means Https only, or
has the attribute HttpOnly.
When a server receives a cookie, it does
not see which domain sent the cookie.
Actually, all the server sees is some
selected attributes sent by the browser.
This problem can be
exploited by attackers.
For example,
say Alice wants to submit her homework.
She logs in login.site.com and
login.site.com sets the session-id
cookie for site.com.
And then, Alice decides to take a break
and unknowingly visits a malicious site.
For example,
because of a phishing attack.
And evil.site.com can override
the .site.com session-id cookie
with a session-id of user Badguy.
Then Alice returns to the homework
site ready to turn in her homework.
Of course.site.com thinks that it
is talking to the badguy because
the session-id has been overwritten.
The problem is that course.site.com
expects session-id cookie
that was set by login.site.com.
It cannot tell that the session-id
cookie was overwritten.
Here's another example of
cookie security problems.
Suppose Alice logs in
https://accounts.google.com,
meaning that she logs in
into her Google account.
And accounts.google.com
will set the cookie.
In particular,
it also says that this cookie is Secure,
meaning that it should be used for
HTTPS.
Now suppose that due to some phishing
attack, Alice visits the create text
site, http://www.google.com and
because this is a clear text protocol,
a network attacker
can intercept the traffic and
override the cookie attributes.
And the result is that this overwritten
cookie can be used for a HTTPS session.
As we can see, a network attacker can
intercept and rewrite HTTPS cookies,
which means that even a HTTPS cookie,
its values cannot be trusted.
We have not talked about
the path of a cookie.
The path separation is done only for
efficiency, not for security.
For example, x.com/A would tell
that if a server only needs
to access this path,
that only this cookie's needed.
Recall that the scope of a cookie
is determined by domain and path.
Which means that x.com/A does not
see cookies of x.com/B because
they are different paths.
That is, they're in different scopes.
However, this is not
a strong security measure.
Because x.com/A still has access to the
DOM, meaning the document object model
of x.com/B, because they are the same
origin as far as DOM is concerned.
For example, x.com/A can use
the following to print out or
read the cookie of x.com/B.
Another security problem of cookies
is that cookies have no integrity.
For example, a user can change or
even delete cookie values.
For example, there are tools
that a user can use to change or
delete cookie values.
For example, a user can change
the shopping cart cookie and
change the total dollar
amount from $150 to $15.
Similarly, if the website had used
a hidden field in the webpage to record
the value, a user can still edit the
source of the page and change the value.