For example, after the user logs out,
he should be allowed to log
in with a different account.
And a website should prevent
a user from accessing content
left behind by a previous user.
So what should happen during a log out?
First, the session token on
a browser should be deleted.
Second, on a server side, the session
token should be marked as expired.
The problem is that many web sites do 1,
but
not 2, this is especially dangerous for
sites that use HTTPS for
login, but then fall back to
the clear text HTTP after login.
This is because an active network
attacker can intercept the clear
text HTTP traffic and
steal a copy of the session token.
Then even after the user logs out,
because the server does not
expire the session token, the attacker
can continue to use that session token.