In addition to stealing tokens, an
attacker can also fake session tokens.
For example,
the attacker can trick the user into
clicking a URL that sets a session
token, or it can use cross-scripting
attacks to set token values.
Here's an example of how an attacker
can use session fixation attack
to elevate his anonymous token
to a user logged-in token.
First the attacker gets anonymous
browsing session token from site.com.
He then sends a URL to the user
with the attacker's session token.
The user clicks on the URL and
logs in www.site.com.
Now the attacker can use the elevated
token to hijack user's session.
To mitigate such attacks when elevating
a user from anonymous to logged in,
a website should always
issue a new session token.
So with this, after the user logs in,
the token will change to a different
value unknown to the attacker.
That is, the anonymous token that
the attacker had originally obtained
is not elevated.