HTTPS is essentially HTTP over SSL,
the secure socket layer, which is now
called TLS, transport layer security.
With HTTPS,
all traffic between a web browser and
a web site is encrypted,
whereas HTTP is a clear text protocol,
meaning that the traffic
is not encrypted.
For example, using HTTP, a user sends
a password and a web server receives it.
Since the traffic data is in clear text,
a network attacker with access to
the link can intercept the traffic
data and learn the user's password.
Now with HTTPS,
the user still sends the password, but
the password is encrypted
in transmission.
Therefore, even when
attacker can access a link,
he cannot learn your
clear text password.
In summary, HTTPS allows for
secure communication over untrusted or
public network.
It encrypts traffic and uses public key
to authenticate the web server and.
if possible.
even the browser.
Even if only the web service
public key is known,
many in the man-in-the-middle-attack
can still be prevented.
With all these benefits,
HTTPS is not used for all web traffic.
The reason is that crypto operations
can slow down the web service,
in particular,
if it is not implemented right.
And some ad networks,
do not support HTTPS.
For example,
the ad publishers cannot learn the web
contents as being viewed by the users.
On the other hand,
Google is now trying to encourage
websites from adopting HTTPS.