An essential problem in
public key cryptography
is how Alice can obtain
the public key of Bob.
The standard is to use certificate
issued by a certificate authority,
we call it the CA.
First, every entity has
installed the public key of CA.
Then Bob can ask the CA to generate
a certificate for his public key.
The certificate authority keeps
the signing private key to itself.
And again, the corresponding public key
has been installed in all entities.
The CA signs Bob's public key
using it's signing private key and
the signature is put
into the certificate.
So Bob can now present
the certificate to Alice.
And because Alice has the certificate
authority's public key,
she can verify that the signature
was constructed properly.
Which means that Bob's public
key has been certified
by the certificate authority.
Here's an example of
public key certificate.
Let's go over some
important information.
First, there's a unique serial number.
Second, there's a valid time period.
And there's a public key and
a signature produced by the CA.
Here's an example of
certificate information
that a user sees on his computer.
It identifies that the certificate is
for the public key of mail.google.com.
A certificate is for an entity or
subject that is identified
by the common name.
So what is a common name?
A common name can be an explicit name,
for example cc.gatech.edu.
Or it can be a wildcard,
for example, *.gatech.edu.
If a wildcard is used it can
only be the leftmost component,
and it does not match dot.
For example: *.a.com matches
x.a.com but not y.x.a.com.
There are large numbers of CAs out
there, and a browser typically accepts
certificates from 60 top level CAs and
1200 intermediate CAs.