Let's briefly review SSL/TLS.
The goal of this handshake is
to authenticate the server and
optimally the browser and
more importantly, at the end,
both will have a shared secret key that
can be used to encrypt HTTP traffic.
The client sends a hello
message to a server and
the severs response includes
a proper key certificate.
The browser verifies the certificate,
meaning that now the browser knows
the server's valid public key.
And with that, the browser
can now perform key exchange.
For example, it can use Elliptic
curve Diffie-Hellman key exchange.
With a server's public key,
the browser and the server
can perform secure key exchange and
prevent man-in-the-middle attack.
And the result is that they now
establish a shared secret key and
they can use this shared secret
key to encrypt HTTP data.