HTTPS is integrated into a browser, or
it is indicated in the browser GUI.
The goal is to let the user
know where a page came from.
And it tells the users that the page
contents are protected, meaning that
they're encrypted so that a network
attacker cannot see them or modify them.
In reality,
there are several security problems.
When the lock icon is
displayed on the browser,
it means that all the elements on
the page are fetched using HTTPS.
But for the browser to even
accept this HTTPS connection,
it means that the browser has
trusted the certificate and
verified that the certificate is valid.
And also,
the domain URL matches the CommonName or
SubjectAlternativeName in
the certificate.
For example,
the certificate of google.com can simply
supply a list of alternative names.