Let's discuss several security
problems with HTTPS and the lock icon.
This include upgrade from HTTP to HTTPS.
Forged certificates.
First, let's discuss
upgrade from HTTP to HTTPS.
There's an attack method
called SSL stripped.
It prevents the browser from upgrading.
With SSL stripping, the browser won't
display any SSL certificate errors,
and the user has no clue that
such an attack is happening.
This attack is also known
as HTTP downgrading attack.
The connection established between
the victim user's browser and
the web server is downgraded
from HTTPS to HTTP.
For example, when a user wants to
transfer money to his account using
an online banking service, he enters
the following URL in the address
bar of his browser,
www.foobank.com/onlinebanking.
Of course, this URL is intended for
the web server of the bank.
In the background,
the user's computer happen to be
connected to the attacker's machine.
The attacker waits for
a response from the bank server.
The attacker forwards the request to
the bank and waits for the response.
The connection between the attacker and
the bank is secure.
That means the traffic is
transferred using an SSL tunnel.
Therefore, the login page from
the bank's web server will
be
https://www.foobank.com/onlinebanking.
The attacker has access
to the login page and
can modify the response from
the server from HTTPS to HTTP and
then forward the login page
in HTTP to the client.
The user's browser now is connected to
http://www.foobank.com/onlinebanking.
The user's browser is now connected
to the bank's website with
an insecure connection.
From this point on, all the user's
requests go out in plaintext, and
the attacker can access the data and
collect the credentials.
While the server thinks that it's
been using a secure connection, that
connection is really just between the
web server of the bank and the attacker.
On the other hand, the user's browser
is using the insecure HTTP connection,
thinking that that's what the bank's
web server wants it to use.
The solution to SSL strip
attack is to use HSTS,
which stands for
Strict Transport Security.
This policy can be set for
a maximum of one year.
It basically tells the web browser
to always use HTTPS, even for
its subdomains.
When a web browser visits a website for
the first time,
the website can tell the browser
to always use HTTPS.
That is, for any subsequent visit,
all connection must be over HTTPS,
and HTTP connections will be rejected.
A web browser can also have
a preloaded list of HSTS websites.
Even before web browser
visits a site on this list,
it knows that it must use HTTPS.
The HSTS flag set by a website can
be cleared when the user selects
clear private data.
Another serious security
problem is forged certificates.
For example, if a CA is hacked, the
attacker can issue rogue certificates.
For example, for Gmail.
And once a rogue certificate is issued,
now the attacker can set up a fake
website and calling itself Gmail.
In this website,
we have the rogue certificate for Gmail.
And several countries have been caught
issuing unauthorized certificates,
for example, for Google so the ISPs
in these countries can play man in
the middle between a user and
the real Google server.
This is further illustrated
in this example.
Suppose a user wants
to connect to a bank.
There's a bad guy in the middle, and
this attacker has a rogue certificate,
therefore it can pretend to be the bank.
The user may think that he
is connected to the bank
because the certificate says so, but
however, the certificate is rogue,
meaning that the user is actually
connected to the bad guy.
This illustrates that
with a rogue certificate,
an attacker can play man in the middle,
even in HTTPS connection.
The attacker plays the bank
server to the user and
the user to the bank server.
And both sides of
connections are in HTTPS.