One approach to deal with rogue
certificate is to use dynamic public-key
pinning.
This means that a website will declare
the CAs that sign its certificate.
When a browser first visits a website,
the website tells the browser
the list of authorized CAs.
Then on subsequent visits,
the browser will reject any
certificate issued by other CAs.
Very similarly there's a public-key
pinning extension for HTTP or HPKP.
This feature tells a web
browser the list of proper keys
to be associated with the website.
And it can prevent man-in-the-middle
attacks with forged certificates.
When the browser visits a website for
the first time, the browser sends
a list of public-key hashes.
And on subsequent visits, the browser
expects the server to use one or
more of these public
keys in its certificates.
Another problem to deal with
forged certificate is for
the CAs to be transparent.
That is,
the CAs must publish in a public log
of all the certificates
that they have issued and
a browser will only accept a certificate
if it is published on a public log.
And companies like Google can constantly
scan the public logs to look for
invalid or forged certificates.