Let's review why malware is
such a big security problem.
It is very easy for
malware to get on a user's computer.
Say a user browses the web, for example,
reading the news at USAToday.com.
And this may result in
a compromise to his computer.
The reason is that USAToday.com's
ad network can be compromised, so
when they use their
browsers usatoday.com,
his browser will be served
with malicious JavaScript.
And of course, this script is bundled
with ad and this malicious JavaScript
will automatically direct the user's
browser to a rogue AV website.
Rogue AV stands for
rogue antivirus software.
The end result is that the user's
tricked to download a rogue AV,
which is actually a malware.
Here's a case study on how many
sites may have been compromised and
serve malicious contents.
The researchers analyzed
the Alexa top ranked domains.
They allowed 252 million domains
worldwide in 2016 at this time.
A research system was created to examine
Alexa top 25,000 domains each day.
Essentially the browser within a virtual
machine is forced to visit each domain.
A research system was created to examine
Alexa's Top 25,500 domains each day.
Essentially, the browser
within the virtual machine
is forced to visit domain.
The network traffic that follows
a visit to these websites
are analyzed to determine whether
drive by download had occurred.
The result show that 39 domains
resulted in drive by download.
And among these, 87% of these sites
involved exploits of JavaScripts.
And 46% of these sites served
the exploits through ad networks.
From Alexa statistics, about 7.5
million users visited these 39 sites.
And about 1.2 million user computers
are likely compromised because
these computers don't
have adequate defenses.
For example, they have out of
date antimalware software.
Collectively the attackers
always develop new malware and
new ways to spread malware widely.
For example,
an exploit was developed on mobility
in Acrobat Reader's Flash interpreter.
As defenders we may discover
that one of our user's computers
was compromised by this exploit.
For example,
we may be able to observe the phone home
traffic from the compromised computer.
That is we may observe
the command control traffic.
From the compromised computer.
And the chances are our user is not
alone because we may soon discover that
many websites are hosting
the same kind of exploits.
This is indeed the real case.
And of course,
users remain the weakest link and
often they are subject to
social engineering attacks.
For example, a very compelling email may
make a user click on an active content.
For example a video or flash content.
That result in a compromise
such as this real case.