You may wonder, don't we already
have defenses against malware?
Yes we do, but
malware keeps evolving very fast and
some of the traditional
mechanisms are not adequate.
We should deploy defense in depth,
and for network protection we have
firewalls as the prevention mechanism
and IDS as the detection mechanism.
But for firewall,
command control traffic
can look just like normal traffic,
such as visiting a webpage.
For IDS that analyzes the payload
of traffic, the encrypted or
specially encoded malicious
contents can evade such analysis.
On the host, if you ask the user's
consent, most often since the users
often do not understand the security
implications, they will simply say yes.
In terms of antivirus software,
the traditional signature matching
approaches are not effective where
malware uses obfuscation techniques.
And so, we have to continue to develop
more complex behavior-based
analysis approaches.