Now let's take a closer look at one
of the most widely used obfuscation
techniques, packing.
Given the original malware program,
the packing tool would transform it, so
that the transformed code looks random.
Because it is encrypted,
we randomly generate a key.
And this happens each time the packing
program is run on a malware program.
That is even for
the same malware program, each
packed instance will look different.
And therefore,
a signature based approach is not
effective in detecting the malware.
Furthermore, the transformed
machine code looks like data.
Therefore, a network IDS that looks for
executables and
email attachment will miss it.
If the anti virus company
obtains the zero day malware,
even though it is obfuscated.
Eventually, the researchers can
de-obfuscate the malware and
discover its behaviors.
But such analysis takes time and
the attacker can make
such analysis fruitless.
Even anti virus company
analyzes a zero day malware
even though it is obfuscated.
Eventually, the researchers can
de-obfuscate the malware and
discover its behaviors.
But such analysis takes time.
And the attacker can make
such analysis fruitless.
In particular, the attacker's server
can continuously send an updated or
new malware.
That is obfuscated of course,
to the compromised computers.
Then in effect, the defenders or
researchers have to deal with zero
day on new malware constantly.
That is by the time they have
successfully analyzed a malware,
it has become obsolete.
A real example of this server
polymorphism is Waledac.
This particular version of
the malware postcard.exe was
released on December 30,
2008 and by February 25, 2009,
the majority of the antivirus
software can detect it.
But a new version of the malware
disc.exe was detected by only
a very small percentage of the antivirus
software on the date it was released.
Here's an example showing the challenges
the anti-virus industry is facing.
The researchers surveyed McAfee
anti-virus software using
20,000 malware samples
collected over six months.
53% of the malware samples were
detected on the day of release.
32% of the malware samples
were detected with a delay.
And the delay was on average 54 days.
And 15% of the malware samples were
not detected even six months later.