The most challenging
transparency requirement
is the identical notion of time.
In particular, if malware uses
network timing measurements
to infer the presence of analyzer.
For example,
the analyzer causes delay, or
the website that the malware
connects to is not a real one.
There are many direct or
indirect measurements that
a malware can perform and
it is impossible to identify all direct
or indirect measurement techniques.
In fact, the problem of identifying all
network-based timing measurements is
equivalent to the problem of detecting
and removing all covert channels.
This problem has been
proved to be undecidable.