Now let's discuss how to build a robust
and efficient malware analysis system.
By robust, we mean it is transparent and
is not easily detected and
evaded by malware.
By efficient,
we mean it is automated and fast.
We focus on host-based analysis.
That is, learning malware on
a machine and analyze its behaviors.
As a recap, the malware will
tried to detect the presence or
the side effect of the analyzer.
And our goal is to achieve the same
result of malware execution,
regardless of the presence
of the analyzer.
So let's analyze the transparency
requirements again and
see how they can be fulfilled.
For higher privilege, let's put analyzer
in hardware or a virtual machine.
For the requirement of no non-privileged
side-effects, we need to make sure that
no side effects can be detected
by non-privileged instructions.
That is those are the malware
can execute and get results.
Of course the analyzer will
inevitable introduce side-effects.
But if the malware has to use privileged
instructions to learn about these
side-effects, these instructions have to
be executed at a higher privilege level
than the malware, and then the answers
are provided back to the malware.
The analyzer,
since it is at a high privilege level,
can lie the answers back to the malware.
For the requirement of identical basic
instruction execution semantics,
we need to use the real hardware.
Likewise, we need to make sure
that exception handling will
be the same as if on real hardware.
For timing, we need to know
the timing of each instruction I/O,
and exception handling
on the real hardware.
And make sure that the malware can only
use privileged instructions to get
timing measurements on the host so that
the analyzer can lie the answers back.
Just to recap, in order to achieve
transparency, a malware analyzer needs
to be on a higher privilege,
has no non-privileged side effects,
has identical basic instruction
execution semantics, has the same
transparent exception handling,
and identical measurement of time.