Here's an example of a transparent
malware analyzer that they built at
Georgia Tech called Ether.
By the way, it is open source.
Let's briefly describe how Ether
fulfills the transparency requirements.
Ether is built using Intel VT for
hardware virtualization.
The Hypervisor has higher
privilege over the OS kernel.
Therefore, Ether has higher
privilege than malware.
Some of these hardware supported traps
further guarantee this higher privilege.
Ether runs outside of the virtual
machine where the malware runs.
Therefore, there's minimal side-effects
that malware can directly observe.
Ether uses hardware
based authorization and
therefore, the instruction execution
semantics are the same as on hardware.
For exception handling, again,
hardware-based virtualization allows
the same semantics as on hardware.
For on-host time measurement,
the operations comes down to the use
of read time-stamp counter instruction.
This is a privileged instruction and
therefore, the Hypervisor and
ether can control the return
results to the malware
when the malware tries to
get a measurement of time.
Here's the architecture of Ether.
Ether has a component within Xen,
the Hypervisor.
And the rest of Ether is in Dom0.
A separate, privileged virtual machine.
The malware runs on a separate user
level virtual machine called DomU.
Ether provides a fine grained insertion
by insertion examination of malware and
also a coarse grained system
call by system call examination.
We created two tools to evaluate Ether.
The fist is EtherUnpack.
It extracts hidden code
from obfuscated malware.
The second one is EtherTrace,
it records system calls
executed by obfuscated malware.
We then compare both of these
tools to the current academic and
industry approaches.
For EtherUnpack, we compared how well
current tools extract hidden code
by obfuscating a test binary and
looking for
a known string in the extracted code.
For EtherTrace, we obfuscated a test
binary which executes a set of known
operations and then observe if
they were logged by the tool.
For EtherTrace again,
the results show that Ether has much
better transparency than other tools.
Now Ether has limitations and it is only
one of the tools in the continued battle
between defenders or malware analysis
and the attackers or obfuscations.
Let's take a look at this model.
Here, for each major categories
of analysis approaches,
the attackers come up with obfuscation
techniques to defeat such analysis.
For example, for static analysis,
including scanning the binaries
looking for fixed strings,
the attacker can obfuscate the malware.
For example, as a result of packing,
the binary contents will look different
from one instance to the next.
We also use dynamic analysis,
meaning running the malware.
The corresponding obfuscation
technique is trigger-based behavior.
For example, the malware will
not run until the time is right.
Or it detects the fact that it's been
analyzed in an emulation environment
and then stopped.
And since simple dynamic
analysis now becomes inadequate,
researchers have come up with various
ways to force execution of this malware.
And of course, this battle between
analysis and obfuscation will continue.