Now let's understand how emulation
works in a bit more detail.
In fetch, decode, and execute,
the emulator fetch the next bytecode,
decode to get it's opcode.
And look up the execution routine for
this opcode and then execute it.
Notice that the execute routine
execute real x86 machine code.
The Virtual Program Counter,
VPC, is a maintained point to
the next bytecode to fetch from.
Now let's discuss briefly how we
can reverse engineer emulator-based
obfuscation.
There are quite a few challenges.
First of all, we don't even know where
the bytecode program resides in memory.
The emulator code responsible for fetch,
decode, and execute, is also not known.
The malware author can certainly
make reverse engineering more
difficult by changing
how the emulation works.
We develop a tool to automatically
reverse engineer emulator-based malware,
and here's a very high level overview.
The first step is to identify abstract
variables, in particular pointers.
And of course, one of the most important
pointers we need to identify is VPC.
A VPC points to the next bytecode
to fetch, decode, and execute.
Therefore, once we identify the VPCs,
we can identify the fetch,
decode, and
execute behavior in the emulator.
From the fetch, decode, and
execute operations in the emulator,
we can obtain the opcode and
operands, as well as the execution
routine of the malware bytecode.
We can then construct a control
flow graph of the original malware.
And this will tell us
the behaviors of the malware.
Here are some results
of our experiments.
We created a synthetic program.
We then apply two emulation-based
obfuscation techniques.
One is called VMProtect, the other
one is called Code Virtualizer.
We then applied our tool
to the obfuscated program.
We then compared a control flow
graphs of the original program and
the control flow graphs from
our reverse engineering.
Here is the control flow graph
of the original program, and
a graph from reverse engineering
Code Virtualizer, and
a graph from reverse
engineering VMProtect.
As you can see, our tool is
succesful in terms of extracting
the main properties of
the original control flow graph.
Here are the results from
the experiments on a real program,
NOTEPAD.EXE.
Again, here's a CFG of
the original program.
And here's the result
from reversing VMProtect.
Again, our tool is able to
obtain the main information and
properties of the original CFG.