There is a large increase of
the number of Android malware and
the majority is still SMS Trojans.
You can read more about current
Android malware at the link
in the instructor's notes.
We discuss a few here.
AccuTrack turns an Android
smartphone into a GPS tracker.
Ackposts steals contact information.
Acknetdoor opens a backdoor.
Steek does fraudulent advertising and
also steals private information.
Tapsnake posts the phone's current
location to a web service.
ZertSecurity steals the user's
bank account information.
Similarly, Zitmo also steals
the user's bank account information.
And there are many other more.
Again, you can read more about
the current Android malware at the link
in the instructor's notes.
This plot summarizes the major
categories of Android malware and
their trends.
There are quite a few free Android
antivirus apps, here are a few examples.
The security companies own
statements provide some insights
of the state of anti
malware on mobile phones.
First of all,
the risk is relatively low.
In general, mobile devices are still
less powerful than desktops and
laptops and there are plenty of those
that can be targeted by hackers.
Furthermore, the [INAUDIBLE] process and
the sandbox space execution model
also means that the mobile devices
are in general more secure.
Nevertheless, there is still
the need to protect mobile devices.
In particular, in addition to
protection against malware,
a bigger problem is the loss of devices
and the loss or the theft of data.
And therefore secure companies also
try to protect and manage mobile data.
Mobile malware are becoming
more sophisticated and
are showing the same advanced features
of malware and laptops and desktops.
Here's an example of Android malware
that uses social engineering to spread.
It targets a group of activists.
On March 24, 2013,
the email account of a high-profile
Tibetan activist was hacked and
it was used to send spear phishing
emails to people on his contact lists.
This is what the spear
phishing email looked like.
The recipient of this email is tricked
that he should install this APK file
on his Android device
which is the malware.
After installation, an application named
Conference appears on the desktop.
After the installation, if the user
launches this Conference app,
he will be seeing the information
about the upcoming event.
While the victim reads
this fake message,
the malware secretly reports the
infection to a command control server.
After that, it begins to harvest
information stored on a device.
The stolen data includes contacts, call
logs, SMS messages, your location and
phone data, which includes phone number,
OS version, phone model, etc.
Know that the stolen data won't be
uploaded to the command control
center automatically.
The malware waits for
incoming SMS messages from
the command control center.
And based on the message,
the malware knows what data to upload.