The goal of network monitoring is to
detect and prevent attack traffic.
Attack traffic used to be obvious.
For example, the payload of a packet may
contain exploit to a known vulnerability
and therefore a signature can
be used to detect such attack.
Or a network monitor can detect,
deny a service attack or
spam activity by analyzing the volume
and rate of network traffic.
The typical network monitoring
systems are the firewalls and
the network intrusion detection systems.
Increasingly, the traditional
firewalls and
network IDS are becoming less effective.
First of all,
mobile devices are now widely used.
A mobile device can be compromised
when an employee is on travel.
And then when the employee
brings the mobile device into
the company's network, it effectively
has bypassed the perimeter defense.
In addition,
attack traffic now is very subtle and
they often look like normal traffic.
For example,
botnet HTTP-based command and
control traffic would look like
normal legitimate web traffic.
Therefore, we need more advanced
network monitoring systems to detect
this new generation of attacks.
In this lesson, we're going to
discuss botnet detection systems.