What are the challenges
in botnet detection?
First of all bots try
to hide themselves.
Second of all,
bots are also involved in multiple
activities over a period of time.
Bot malware can also
get updates frequently.
Botnets can have many different
command control methods.
In fact, a bot malware can be
programmed to select one of several C&amp;C
methods at run time.
So how do we go about detecting botnets?
We need to first focus on
the characteristics that botnets
are different from normal traffic.
First of all, a bot is not a human.
That is, the activities by bots may look
different from the activities by human.
Second of all, the fact that
botnet is a network means that
the bots are connected, and their
activities are somehow coordinated.
We can also distinguish botnets
from other traditional attacks.
Botnets are for profits, and
they most likely are going to use
the compromised computers as resources.
Botnets are for long-term use.
And therefore there will be frequent
updates to the bot malware.
And again there must be coordination
among the bots to form a botnet.
Let's first discuss how do we detect
botnets in the enterprise network.
We can deploy a botnet detection
system at a gateway or router.
This is how we deploy firewall in IDS.
There are several detection approaches
in a so called vertical correlation.
We are looking for
correlated events across a time horizon,
even if a bot has multiple
activities in its life cycle.
In horizontal correlation
we are looking for
similar or coordinated
behaviors across multiple bots.
In cause and effect correlation,
we inject traffic to pay with the bot
to conform that the traffic is
generated by bot versus human.
In this lesson, we going to discuss
two systems, one is BotHunter,
the other one is BotMiner.