BotHunter is a system that
performs vertical correlation.
We also call it dialog correlation.
That is,
BotHunter correlates multiple events
that belong to the life cycle of a bot.
Let's use an example to
illustrate the multiple steps or
types of activities in
a bot's life cycle.
First, the attacker scan the network and
identify vulnerable host.
It then sends the exploit to compromise
the victim host and opens a back door.
The compromised computer then
downloads the real bot malware,
it then connects to
a command control server.
And from there,
it can perform a number of activities.
For example image scan,
for other number of hosts.
From the phatbot example, we can
extract the life cycle of a botnet.
You can include inbound scan and
inbound infection, and
then outbound traffic
to download the egg or
the bot malware and command control
traffic, as well as other activities.
Such as outbound scan.
So the main idea behind BotHunter is
to analyze network traffic to detect
patterns that suggest any of
these activities belonging to
the BotNet lifecycle.
These observations don't have
to follow this strict order,
but they do have to appear
within the same period of time.
BotHunter uses a table to keep track
of the evidence that it collects for
each host.
And here's an example for each internal
host, BotHunter keeps track of
the specific activities that belong to
each steps of the botnet life cycle.
There are timers associated
with these observations.
That is they are valid as long
as a timer has not expired.
The integration is that within
a period of time that is
before the timer expired, if you
see multiple evidence belonging to
the botnet life cycle then we can
determine that this host is a bot.
And we give more weight to
evidence that suggests that
an internal machine has been compromised
and it is participating in botnet
activities such as egg downloading,
outbound scanning and outbound spamming.