Here's the architecture of BotHunter.
He has a number of detection engines.
Each of these engines are disposable for
detecting certain activities
of the botnet lifecycle.
And the correlator correlates
evidence of these activities and
makes detection that an internal
machine has been compromised and
has become a bot and
produces a bot infection profile.
Let's discuss the BotHunter
detection engines.
The first is SCADE.
SCADE is for scan detection,
recur in the bounded lifecycle
inbound scan is a first event.
SCADE used different ways for different
inbound scan connections, in particular,
it gives us higher weight
to vulnerable ports.
SCADE also detects outbound scan.
It looks at the rate of
outbound connections,
how likely such connection fails and
the distribution of the destination
of these outbound connections.
Collectively this can
suggest outbound scan.
Another BotHunter
detection engine is SLADE.
SLADE can detect anomalies
in network payloads.
The main idea is that we can
establish the normal profile
of a network service by looking
at the n-gram byte distribution
of the traffic payload
of this network service.
That is, an attack such as an exploit or
egg download will cause deviation
from this normal profile because
the n-gram byte distribution
of the attack traffic will be
different from the normal traffic.
SLADE has a very
efficient implementation
of payload anomaly detection.
BotHunter also includes
a signature engine.
This signature engine can
detect known exploits and
know patterns of command control.
The signature rules come
form multiple open sources.
Here's an example of infection
profile produced by BotHunter.
It list the initial host that
infects the internal machine,
the internal machine that has become a
bot and the command and control server.
It also lists evidence
of the lifecycle steps.