Many botnets use DNS for
command control.
A key advantage is that DNS
is used whenever a machine
on the internet needs
to talk to another,
because DNS stores the mapping
between domain name and IP address.
That is DNS is always allowed
in a network and using DNS for
command control won't standout easily.
Suppose a malware infects many machines,
that is many machines
now have become bots.
The question is how can this
bot organize into a botnet?
The bot malware has instructions to
connect to this command control server.
But in order to connect to
the command control server,
it will perform a DNS lookup first.
And with the IP address, the bot can
connect to the command control server
and that's how the bot
becomes part of a botnet.
The DNS service providers preferred
by botnets are Dynamic DNS providers,
because they allow the frequent changes
of the mapping between DNS domain name
and IP address.
That is the botmaster can change to use
another machine on the internet for
command control and
all he needs to do is log into his
Dynamic DNS provider, and make changes.
If we can detect that, a domain is used
for botnet command control, then we can
detect which machine connects to this
domain and this machine is a bot, but
how do we know this domain is used for
botnet command control?
It terms out that way the bots look
at the domain is different from how
machines look at instrument
domain such as a news website,
because of normal use activities.
For example, a botnet CNC is looked
up by hundreds of thousands of
machines across the internet.
And yet, it is so-called unknown
according to Google search and
that's an anomaly.
We can use anomaly detection at the
Dynamic DNS service provider by examine
queries in DNS domains to
identify botnet CNC domains.
And once we identify a domain
is used for botnet CNC,
then a number of
responses are available.
One is for the service provider
to disable a domain, but
it's one thing to occur when
none such domain reply.
Another option is for
the provider to set a mapping
of a domain to a single address.
So that instead of connecting to
the botnet command control server,
the bots are now
connected to a sinkhole.
The sinkhole in addition
to disabling the botnet
security researchers can also learn
where the bots are by looking at
the origins of the connections
to the sinkhole.