Now let's discuss another
source identification technique
called Traceback.
The goal is that given a set of attack
packets, we want to determine the paths
of these packets and use a path to
determine the source of these packets.
And the way to do this is to change
the Internet routers to record
some path information into the packet.
There are a few assumptions here.
First, most the routers
remain uncompromised,
meaning that these routers can
record information faithfully.
Second, the attackers send many packets,
and
the route from the attackers source to
the victim remains relatively stable.
Here's a naive strawman method.
We can have each router at its
own IP address in the packet.
So, at the end, the victim can
read a path from the packet
because each router has
written its own IP address.
The problem with this is that
it requires space in packet and
this can be a problem
when a path is long.
There's no extra fields in the current
IP format to record this whole
path information.
If we expect the packet format
to be changed to include this
path information it would take years,
if ever, to get this implemented.
So here's a better idea.
We observe that the non-service
attack involve many,
many packets on a same path, so we can
have each router to take a probability
to store its own address in a packet.
This required only a fixed amount of
space regardless of the path length.