Now let's discuss some novel idea
to defend against denial of service
attacks.
There are a number of examples for
capability-based defenses.
You're welcome to study these papers.
Here's a brief overview
of these defenses.
The basic idea is that the receivers,
such as a server,
can specify what packets they want,
and this is called the capability.
When the sender sends a request to
the receiver, he must include capability
in his SYN packet, meaning that
he needs to tell the server that,
hey, I am the packet that you want.
When a client wants to
connect to a server,
it needs to first request capability.
And such a request
should be very limited.
And the server can respond with
a capability that the sender can later
include in his packets.
Furthermore, all the routers will only
forward packets with valid capability.
If a source is attacking,
then its capability can be revoked, and
as a result, the routers will drop or
block such packets.
And this can take place as close
to the source as possible.