Now let's talk about
underground economy.
To understand the underground
economy of server crimes
we have to first understand who
are the actors in the underground.
The first are the ones
who write exploits.
They discover bugs that can be exploited
to cause security to be compromised and
they sell them for a profit.
Then there are the botnet masters,
or bad guys that create and
operate a malicious network
composed of compromised computers.
Essentially, they buy exploits and
turn them into malware and
they put in the botnet command and
control components.
So when they release the malware,
they have a botnet under their control.
Then they rent out the botnet
to other bad actors for
malicious and fraudulent activities.
One of the utilities of
a botnet is to send spam.
And so the bot master of a botnet can
simply rent out his botnet to a spammer,
and the spammer in turn sends out a spam
contents on behalf of other bad actors.
One type of bad actors that can use
to help of spammers are the phishers.
They set up scam sites
to steal information and
they ask the spammers to send the URL's
to victim users to the scam sites.
Similarly, counterfeiters use spams
to sell their counterfeit goods and
obviously, they need to be able to
collect money from the victim users.
For example, from their credit cards.
A bad actor in a cyberspace needs
to consider the possibility that
his operation, in particular his
websites, may be detected and
shut down by the law enforcement.
And so he needs to find a so-called
bulletproof hosting providers.
These providers typically operate in
lawless places and they are expensive.
A majority of the bad actors
are in it for the money.
And on the Internet, what they can steal
are the bank accounts and credit cards.
And so they need to turn them into cash.
They allow carders, cashiers,
and mules to do just that.
The crowdturfers leverage human powered
crowd sourcing platforms to create and
manage fake accounts that
are not tired to real users.
And they can use crowd
sourcing to solve captures.