There are three cloud service models.
The first one is Software as a Service.
It enables a customer to use
a provider's applications
running on a cloud infrastructure.
This applications on a cloud
can be accessful from various
kind devices through a thin client
interface such as the web browser.
The second model is
Platform as a Service.
It enables a consumer to deploy
on to the cloud infrastructure
consumer created applications
using programming languages and
tools supported by the cloud provider.
The third model is
Infrastructure as a Service.
It enables a consumer to provision
processing storage networks and
other fundamental computing resources on
the cloud where the consumer is able to
deploy and run arbitrary software,
which can include operating systems and
applications.