There are several cloud
deployment models.
The first one is private cloud.
Here, the cloud infrastructure is
operated solely for an organization.
It may be managed by the organization or
a third party and
may exist on-premise or off-premise.
Here, the cloud infrastructure is
shared by several organizations and
supports a specific community
that has shared concerns.
It may be managed by the organizations
or a third party, and
may exist on-premise or off-premise.
The third model is public cloud.
Here, the cloud infrastructure is made
available to the general public or
a large industry group, and
is owned by an organization
selling the cloud services.
The fourth one is hybrid,
is a composition of two or
more of these models.