To summarize what we
have discussed thus far.
Let's go over the NIST cloud
definition framework, there are several
deployment models and each can
use one of these service models.
Again, the deployment models include
Hybrid, Private, Community and
Public and the service models
include software as a service,
platform as a service and
infrastructure as a service.
All Cloud environments share
some essential characteristics.
These include On Demand Self-Service,
Broad Network Access, Resource Pooling,
Rapid Elasticity, Measured Service.
And they also share some
common characteristics.
This includes Massive Scale,
Homogeneity,
Virtualization, Low Cost Software,
Resilient Computing,
Geographic Distribution, Service
Orientation, and Advanced Security.