There are several key security issues.
For example,
how do we trust the cloud computing
environment because we don't manage it.
Furthermore, multiple different
organizations may be using the same
cloud computing environment.
And in terms of data protection,
obviously,
we should use encryption
to protect confidentiality.
But we also need to consider
various compliance issues.
These security issues become very
challenging because the clouds
are massively complex systems.
Although the primitives and
common functions are simple,
the complexity comes from the fact
that these primitives and
function units are replicated
thousands of times.
On the other hand,
as we will discuss shortly,
cloud security is a tractable problem
because there are both advantages and
challenges associated
with cloud computing.
Let's first discuss the advantages.
First, you can put public data away
from the internal network to the cloud.
And it is easy to manage testing and
security patches when most systems
in a cloud computing environment
use the same software.
And recovery is easy and fast because
it is easy to set up the same system.
But there are also challenges.
First, you have to trust
the cloud providers.
And you cannot respond to all
the findings, or investigate directly,
because you have to rely on the cloud
providers who are the direct admins, and
some software running in
the cloud is proprietary.
And finally,
there is no physical control of
the computing resources that you use.