All the core components of
a cloud computing environment
are relevant to security.
This include cloud provisioning
services, cloud data storage services,
cloud processing infrastructure, cloud
support services, cloud network and
perimeter security and
elastic elements: Storage,
processing and virtual networks.
Now, let's discuss
the security advantages and
challenges for
each of these core components.
The first is provisioning services.
There are several security advantages.
This include,
rapid reconstitution of services.
Greater data availability because we
can provision multiple data centers and
advanced honeynet capabilities.
The main security challenge is that, if
the provisioning service is compromised,
the impact is disruptive.
For data storage services,
there are several security advantages.
This include data can be fragmented and
dispersed, therefore,
data can be more resilient to attacks.
In addition, data can be
encrypted at rest and in transit.
There's also automatic backup and
replication of data.
But, there are also several
security challenges.
For example,
data from multiple organizations may
be put in the same storage server.
And, the storage server may
be in a different country.
For the cloud processing infrastructure,
the main security advantage is that
we can secure the master
copy of a program and
then, replicate that copy throughout
the cloud computing environment.
But then, there's also several
security challenges, for
example, multiple applications can be
running on the same physical machine.
And therefore,
achieving a real isolation is not easy.
For example, cash and memory access are
side channels that can leak information.
And of course,
we'd assume that the hypervisors or
the by virtual monitors are secure.
Cloud Support Services can provide
on demand security controls for
customer applications.
But now, the cloud providers need to
make sure that customer applications
will not cause security problems
in the cloud environment.
In terms of networks security, since the
computing systems are now distributed,
denial of service attacks
are now harder to succeed.
Furthermore, standard perimeter
security measures such as IDS and
firewalls are deployed by default.
But since different applications
share the same cloud,
it is challenging to create
security zones where the resources
share a common security exposure or
security risk.