Let's summarize the security advantages
a cloud computing environment
can provide.
These include Data Fragmentation and
Dispersal, Dedicated Security Team,
Greater Investment in Security
Infrastructure, Fault Tolerance and
Reliability, Greater Resiliency,
Hypervisor Protection
Against Network Attacks and
the Possible Reduction
of C&amp;A Activities.
Furthermore, the compliance
analysis is simplified and
data can be held by unbiased party.
There is Low-Cost associated with
Disaster Recovery and Data Storage.
There are on demand
security controls and
real time detection of system tampering.
Reconstitution of services is easy and
vast.
And an advanced Honeynet
can be deployed.