A deep web is one that's not indexed
by the standard search
engines such as Google.
A dark web refers to also invisible
web or hidden web where the web
content typically only exists
on so-called darknets.
And so what is a darknet?
It is an overlayed network that can
only be assessed with specific software,
configurations or
authorization, often using non-standard
communication protocols and ports.
Two example darknet are the friend
to friend peer to peer networks and
the privacy network such as tor,
T-O-R, tor.
And a surface web is one that we
are probably most familiar with.
It contains web contents that
are public, searchable and
indexed by standard search engines.
When we think of the Internet we're
usually referring to the surface web.
As you can see in this visual,
the surface web is actually a very
small part of the Internet.