Let's also summarize
the security challenges.
First, we have to consider various
international privacy laws.
For example, the Eu Data
Protection Directive and the U.S.
Safe harbor program.
And data can be subject to
subpoenas from government,
including a foreign government.
And since multiple organizations may
be using the same cloud computing
environment, we need very
strong isolation protection.
And since computation and data can be
distributed log in becomes a challenge.
Similarly, since the cloud is
a distributed computing environment
it is challenging to provide
consistent quality of service.
And finally, since the customer does
not own the computing environment
there could be potential
data ownership issues.
For example, who owns the one time data
produced by a customer application?
There are additional challenges.
These include, now we have to
depend on a secure hypervisor.
And, the cloud is an attractive
target to attackers.
And, we sill need the security
of the operating systems
running in the virtual machines.
And, the potential impact of
a successful attack on the cloud
can be massive.
And since some organizations
now start to use public cloud,
it is challenging to reconcile
the security policies
of the internal network
versus the public cloud.
And for public cloud that uses
software as a service model,
a customer cannot control what
software or what version to use.
It is obvious that we should protect
data security using encryption.
In particular, we need to encrypt
not only the data at rest, but
also access to resources
because otherwise
every service can learn about
the computing tasks being performed.