There are some additional issues
associated with cloud security.
In particular,
we need to consider the privacy impact
when PII data is moved to the cloud.
PII stands for
personal identifiable information, and
it is any data that could potentially
identify a specific individual.
Customers should be aware that they need
to negotiate with the cloud providers to
obtain a security
service level agreement.
But then we need to make sure that
we have proof that the service level
agreements have been satisfied.
Obviously, a cloud provider needs
to plan for disaster recovery.
In addition, a cloud provider needs to
consider a number of compliance issues.
For example, HIPAA for healthcare
data and PCI for payment data.