Let's discuss memory monitoring and
analysis in a virtualization
environment.
The security in a controlled
virtual machine are smaller,
because they can run a stripped down OS.
The security machine
gets a raw memory view,
meaning that it has seized the physical
memory from the other virtual machines.
If you want anything useful,
you need to rebuild the obstruction
levels on your own.
And this is challenging, and
we will discuss this shortly.
There are several types of monitoring.
The first is passive monitoring.
This means that the security virtual
machine takes a snapshot of view,
of the raw memory of a virtual machine.
The second type is active monitoring.
This means that the security virtual
machine takes a view of the memory of
another virtual machine,
when there's an event being
triggered at that virtual machine.
An important goal of memory
monitoring is to locate
the important data structures in
memory for security analysis, for
example, examining the process list.