Here's an example of passive monitoring.
Again, this means that the security
virtual machine monitors that
application periodically by getting the
view of the memory from another virtual
machine.
This is known as performing
virtual machine introspection.
And here are the main steps
in passive monitoring.
In the security virtual machine,
the security tool performs an API
call to access a kernel symbol.
The address of the kernel
symbol has been looked up and
then page tables for
the memory of the user virtual machines
are being traversed to
locate the kernel data.
And then, the pointer to the memory
is returned to the security monitor.
We use a virtual machine introspection
library called libVMI to convert
the raw memory view into something
meaningful, such as, virtual addresses,
kernel symbols, etc, and
we will discuss libVMI shortly.