Now we need to address one
very important detail.
When you read memory,
all you see are 1s and 0s.
But how do you know what the 1s and 0s
mean, unless you know the memory layout,
according to data structure definitions?
For example, this blob may represent a
data structure that you're looking for.
Therefore, as we have discussed
in passive monitoring,
we need to convert the raw memory
view into something meaningful
such as virtual addresses
kernel symbols, etc.
We use libVMI, or previously called
XenAccess, to analyze memory contents.
This is an example of
the code that used libVMI
APIs to obtain the list
of learning processes.
And this is the output.
The pull here is that with libVMI or
XenAccess,
you don't even write a whole
lot of code in order to obtain
such useful runtime information
of the other virtual machine.
libVMI is open source,
it provides access and
analysis of virtual addresses,
kernel symbols.
It was first released as Zeb
acess in Spring 2006, and
here's the GitHub repository.
Here's a quick summary of the libVMI
features, you can perform virtual memory
translation, for example so that you
can know which are the kernel symbols.
You can also place monitoring hooks
into a guest virtual machine, for
example, to trap exceptions and
page faults.
For example,
hooks can be placed in a virtual machine
to trap the following events.
For example,
memory read-write-execute events,
register read-write events, interrupts
and single stepping of instructions.
This is useful to trace
a log of program execution.