Now, let's discuss active monitoring.
Active monitoring is event driven which
allows for enforcing security policy and
stopping attacks before they happen.
Here's an example of active monitoring.
The security application receives event
notification from the guest virtual
machine when the code execution,
which is one of the hooks,
hooks invoke trampoline which transfer
the control to the security application.
The hooks in the associated code in
the guest virtual machine are protected
using the memory protection
provided by the hyperviser.
Of course, when a security application
receives an event notification,
it's going to perform virtual
machine inspection, for
example, using the lip VMI.