The question is can we have
both the security benefit
provided by virtual machine monitoring
which means out of VM monitoring and
the efficiency of traditional monitoring
which means In-VM monitoring.
We have developed a secure
In-VM monitoring approach.
We call this approach SIM for
secure In-VM monitoring.
It provides the same security
as the out of VM approach.
And its performance is similar to
the traditional In-VM approach,
the main idea is to use hardware
which virtualization features
to minimize the need to
switch to hypervisor.
In other words we can read or
write the memory of an untrusted
virtual machine at native speed.