Now let's discuss how SIM can
satisfy both the performance and
security requirements.
Recall that in operating systems,
paging-based virtual memory is generated
by creating page tables that map virtual
addresses to physical addresses.
An operating system creates a separate
page table for each process so
that it can have its own
virtual memory address space.
And the necessary
isolation can be achieved.
The SIM address space here
contains all kernel code data and
also the SIM data in
its own address space.
Therefore, the instruction as part
of the security monitor can access
in native speed.
Notice that the guest operating system
has it's own virtual address space.
That is, although we put SIM into
the same virtual machine as the guest
operating system,
they have their own separate and
different module address space.
In order to perform security monitoring,
SIM needs to look at the address
space of the guest operating system.
And this can only be done
through the Entry Gate and
the Exit Gate since this requires
the switching of address spaces.
We need to modify the CR3
register contents directly.
Intel VT, contains a feature that
doesn't check out a VM exit to
the hypervisor, if the CR3 is switched
to an address space that's predefined
and maintained by hypervisor.
Therefore, by predefining
the SIM address space and
system address space we can achieve fast
switching without exiting to hypervisor.
We also use the Hypervisor memory
protection to protect the security of
the SIM address space and
protect the entry and exit gates.
The entry gates and exit gates are the
only ways to switch between the SIM
address space and
the system address space.
We use inter-hardware feature called the
last branch recording in the invocation
checker.
We last branch recording.
We know the last few basic blocks
leading to the entry gate.
The SIM security tool is self contained,
meaning that it does not caught any
quote or using any data from
the kernel of the untrusted region.
The SIM security tool can read
my memory in native speeds.