Property Preserving Encryption
is one way to protect data
while allowing application
to continue to work.
And this approach is widely deployed
in various environments including
the Cloud.
For example, Microsoft advertises
that data is always encrypted.
On the other hand,
the applications continue to work.
Property Preserving Encryption
has several advantages.
There's no need to change
application and database servers,
it supports common data retrieval
methods, including SQL queries.
It is reasonably efficient,
but what about security?
Although it widely believed that it is
secure, we should take a closer look.