So we have just discussed how
malware can be distributed and
installed on victim's computers.
These infected computers
are valuable resources.
For example, they have a unique
IP addresses and bandwidth, and
they're typically distributed
across the internet.
And they have spare CPU cycles that can
perform a wide range of activities.
From attackers point of view
he wants to control and
utilize these infected machines and
the way to do this is to turn
the compromised computers into a Botnet.
The bad guy or the botmonster will
need a command control infrastructure
to control the bots.
For example he can then ask the bot to
update its malware or can send commands
to the bots to launch synchronised
activities and the botnet can rent it
out to other bad guys to launch their
activities, such as sending spams.
Once in place,
the botnet now becomes a platform
to launch any number of malicious and
fraudulent activities.