Here are some results
of applying this attack
on the electronic Medical records.
The x axis is the cumulative
fraction of records recovered, and
the y axis is the fraction of hospitals.
That is, in all of this parts,
our point xy shows that
at least x fraction of records was
recovered for y fraction of hospitals.
For example, for disease severity
at least 40% of the records
were recovered for 50% of the hospitals.
The best result we can obtain
is that all records, for
all hospitals, were recovered.
Here are the highlights of the results.
For example, for
sex, 100% of the patients For
95% of the hospitals recovered.
And for major diagnostic category,
40% of the patients for
28% of the hospitals were recovered.
And we show more results
here the highlights are, for
age 10% of the patients for
85% of the hospitals were recovered.
For length of stay, 83% of the patients
for 50% of the hospitals were recovered