A promising approach to eliminate this
kind of leakage is to use oblivious RAM,
or ORAM.
ORAM can hide access patterns.
The main idea is that using ORAM, while
the cloud provider can still observe
data access, the access patterns are
independent of the actual data requests.
Some of the main techniques
include O data access
operating on fixed size data blocks.
The data is encrypted, not using
property preserving encryption.
In addition, ORAM also use dummy
accesses, or re-encrypt data and
shuffle data around.
Here's a high level pictorial
example of ORAM at work.
The application needs to
access confidential data
such as getting an encryption key,
encrypt and store data, and
getting another encryption key.
For each of these access requests,
there are multiple requests
to the cloud server.
These requests all fixed
sized data objects, and
they are both read and writes.
That is, regardless whether
the original request is for read or
write, the actual dummy accesses
include both read and writes.
And the data objects
are all of fixed size and
not distinguishable from each other.
And this is how you hide the access
pattern from the cloud provider.
ORAM is an active research area, and
if you are interested,
here are some papers.