Now let's study an example of scam.
First, the Botnet sends scam
messages to the victim users.
The user clicks on the link and
the link will eventually lead him
to website to purchase fake drugs.
And payment will then be withdrawn
from his bank account and
he will receive shipment
of the fake drug.
Using data collected from spam feeds,
Botnet infiltration and
various types of honeypot data.
The researchers were able to find
some interesting data regarding
this Pharmacy Express scam.
In particular,
they find that these two accounts for
around 35% of all affiliate scams.
And we will look more into these
scammers in more details shortly.