In 2012,
some of these scammers got breached and
their data were dumped and
made publicly available.
The data contained complete
logs of sales, customers, and
affiliate relationships.
So researchers study this data and
publish their findings in this paper.
Here's a look at the transaction
volumes per week for these scammers.
We can see that these scammers
were around for a long time.
We can see here that
the repeat customers or
the repeat orders are an important
part of the business.
This data presents a counter-point
to the conventional wisdom
that online pharmacies are pure scams.
They don't simply take credit card and
either never providing goods, or
providing goods of no quality.
Because if that is true,
then we would not see repeat customers.
Here's a breakdown of
the different types of drugs
being purchased by customers.
Here we see that pharma scams
bring in a lot of revenue,
but there are also a lot of costs.
The actual net revenue,
or profit is not huge.
These costs include
payment to the affiliates.
Cost of the network infrastructure,
and payment to spammers and
botnet operators.