Now let's discuss the methodology
of penetration testing.
Penetration testing
includes several steps.
The first step is footprinting.
This is about finding the general
information of your network.
Next step is scanning.
This is about finding more detailed
information about your network,
such as the services
available on your network.
The third step is enumeration.
It finds more target information
such as user account.
The fourth step is gaining access.
It finds vulnerabilities associated
with the network services, and
then exploit these vulnerabilities
to gain access to the network.
The fifth step is escalating privilege.
The goal here is to gain
route of super user access.
The sixth step is pilfering.
The goal here is to try to steal
information from the network.
This is one of the standard activities
that an attacker would do to a network.
The seventh step is covering the tracks.
The goal here is to hide
an evidence of a break in so
that security amends cannot easily find
out that the network has been breached.
The last step here is
creating back doors.
The goal is to create easy access for
future malicious
activities on the network.
The last few steps can be iterated for
example to move from one part
of the network to another part.