Once you have the general information
such as the IP ranges of a network,
now you gain more detailed information
of the network using scanning.
You can find out which machine is up,
and which ports are open.
Similarly on the servers
what services are running.
You can even find out the versions and
configurations of these services.
Then you can look up the corresponding
vulnerability information on the web.
For example for a particular
version of the Apache web server,
you can look it up on the web to see
one of the known vulnerabilities,
such as what input can
cause a buffer overflow.
Most promising avenues
are typically associated with
services that are always up,
such as the web services, so
you want to focus on
analyzing these services.
On the other hand,
you want to avoid detection so
you want to reduce the frequency and
volume of your scanning and analysis.
Here are the different techniques and
tools for scanning.
As you can see, Nmap is one of the most
popular tools It can find out which
IP's up, which port is open and
even perform OS finger prints.