Once you have obtained the relevant
information of network services and
user accounts, now you can exploit and
gain access to the network.
Typically, there are all
the existing tools and
scripts associated with
known vulnerabilities.
But of course, you can customize
them to suit your needs.
On the other hand, if the vulnerability
is new or there does not exist a tool or
script, then you have to
develop the exploit yourself.
In general, this is a manual process and
can be quite difficult.
Here are some examples of techniques and
tools for gaining access.
For example, you can use tools
to capture and crack password.
And there are tools that will exploit
vulnerabilities in widely used services.