Let's discuss the impersonation
techniques first.
For example, an attacker can
pretend to be an employee and
call the help desk, and claim that
he has forgotten his password.
A common weakness is that,
the help desk does not require
adequate authentication.
For example, the help desk may just
ask for the mother's maiden name.
And the attacker may only know this,
because he has read the Facebook
information of the employee.
Another impersonation technique is
to fake a third party authorization.
For example, the attacker
can claim that a third party
has authorized him to
access the network.
And if the attacker can provide
the fishing information
to convince people that he
really knows the third party.
Then, he will have easy time gaining
the trust and the access to the network.
In particular,
if the third party is not present.
Another very effective
impersonation technique is to
pretend to be a tech support person.
For example, the attacker can claim that
the company needs to reconfigure its
systems, and ask for user credentials.
If the users have not been properly
trained to guard their credentials,
then this attack can easily succeed.
Another old fashioned way of
impersonation is to just walk around and
see what information is valuable.
For example, passwords or sticky notes,
or other kind of important documents,
or even overhearing
important conversations.
An attacker can dress
up like a repairman,
because a repairman is typically
allowed access to the facility.
The attacker can then plant listening
devices to capture useful information.
This exploit works
because users typically
do not question people in uniform.
Similarly, an attacker can
pretend to be someone in charge
of a department or company.
For example, the attacker can pretend to
be a medial personnel, a home inspector,
or school superintendent.
In each of these examples,
the attacker can actually gain
useful information from a user.
The attacker can gain information such
as address, mother's maiden name, and so
on of an employee.
And this information can then
be used to impersonate employee
through the call to a help desk.
Again, this exploit works because
users tend to trust authority.
Impersonation can also
take place in snail mail.
For example, an attacker can send mail
to a user pretending to be an authority
and ask for personal information.
This exploit works because users
tend to trust the printed materials
more than webpages and emails.
These are examples that I'm
sure you're familiar with.