Now let's take a look at
TCP IP network stack.
The Link Layer is a group of protocols
that only operate on the length
the host is physically connected to.
The network or internet layer is a group
of protocols that are used to transport
packets from one host to another and may
cross network boundaries if necessary.
The Transport layer protocols provide,
host to host communication services for
applications.
They provide services such as connection
oriented data stream support,
reliability, flow control and
multi tasking.
The Application layer protocols
depend upon the underlying
Transport layer protocol to establish
host to host data transfer channels.
And manage the data exchange
in a client-server or
peer-to-peer networking model.
When host A sends
traffic data to host B,
the data usually starts
as Application message.
The Transport layer segments the data
and puts TCP header onto the segments.
The IP layer then puts the IP
header on these segments, and
they become the IP packet.
The Link Layer puts a link header onto
the IP packets, and this becomes frames.
And this Link Layer frame can
then be sent to the link,
connected to the host,
such as the ethernet cable.