The first statement, application layer
controls can protect application data,
and IP addresses,
this statement is false.
IP addresses exist in a lower layer,
and so
application layer controls
cannot protect IP addresses.
The second statement,
IP information cannot be protect by
transport layer controls, this is true.
The third statement, network layer
controls can protect the data within
the packets as well as the IP
information for each packet.
This statement's true,
because that is what network layer
controls are supposed to do.
The fourth statement,
data link layer controls can protect
connections comprised of multiple links.
This is false, they cannot protect
connections with multiple links.