Now, let's discuss a few examples of classification models.
The first one is decision tree,
here the training data is repeatedly petitioned until
all examples in each petition belong to one class.
The decision tree can also be thought of as
a set of rules that describe the decision logic.
Let's go over a simple example,
the application here is to learn
the decision tree to decide whether we should play tennis or not.
So the class label here is yes to no to play tennis,
and the features or attributes include the weather conditions,
and here is the decision tree produced by a machine learning algorithm.
Again, a decision tree can be represented as a set of rules.
For example, if you see outlook equal to sunny and humidity equal to normal,
then yes we play tennis.
If the outlook is overcast then also yes to play tennis,
or if the outlook is rain and wind is weak,
then we also say yes to play tennis.
Here's a high level overview of the process of building a decision tree.
We first find the best attributes that can serve as the root.
Then we break-up the training dataset into
subsets based on the values of this root attribute,
that is, we grow from the root into branches.
Therefore each subset we test the remaining attributes to
see which is best at petitioning this subset,
that is, for each branch,
we test attributes to determine how to best grow into branches.
We continue this process until all examples in a subset belong to one class,
or there's no more attributes left to further permission to subset.
In this case, the default cast label is the majority.
Now the question is, how do we determine which
attribute is best at partitioning a set into subsets?
We use entropy and information gain to determine this.
The entropy of a set is the minimal number of bits needed to
represent examples in this set according to their class labels.
Therefore, roughly speaking, the entropy of a set
represents how pure the examples are in this set.
That is, if the examples of this set are evenly distributed into different classes,
then the entropy is the maximum and if the examples are all in a single class,
then the entropy is the minimum.
In order to determine which attribute is best at partitioning a set,
we compute its information gain.
As you can see from this formula,
a high information gain value for attribute A,
means that A is better as separating
samples in a set S according to their classification,
that is, using A S a petition into purer subsets.
Therefore, we should select the attribute that has
the highest information gain and use it to partition a set.