Clustering can also be used for classification.
In clustering, we assigned training examples
into different clusters based on some distance measure.
That is examples in the same cluster are more
similar to each other than examples from different clusters.
Typically, we defined some distance function to measure similarity.
Here's an overview of the clustering process.
Typically, we predetermine the number of clusters.
We also start with seed clusters,
each with one element.
That is, each seed is a representative example of a cluster.
They may assign a samples to these C clusters based on distance measures,
then we adjust or find a new centroids.
A centroid is the center of the cluster according to distance measure.
Then based on the new centroids,
we are just cluster membership,
so the examples are assigned to the best fit clusters.
The example here belong to this cluster because
it is closer to the centroid than to the centroid and that centroid.
In other words, cluster membership is based on distance to the centroid of the cluster.
We continue this process of finding new centroids and adjusting cluster membership,
until the customers converge.
That is, there's no more changes in the cluster membership.
Once the clusters are finalized,
then each cluster can be represented by its centroid.
Given a test data, it is assigned to a cluster
if its distance to the centroid is the shortest.