As a way to summarize,
classifiers are very useful to many applications,
including security applications, such as intrusion detection.
However, we should be reminded that,
machine learning algorithms are just tools.
Therefore, we need to use them carefully.
We should always try simple classifiers first.
Most specifically, it is more important to have
small features than complicated or smart classifiers.
The reason is that, smart features,
capture the domain knowledge.
This is the key to producing effective classifiers.
On the other hand, if we have a lot of data or wide variety of data,
we can use more powerful classifiers.
The problem of intrusion detection,
can be considered as, a classification problem.
Suppose, we are monitoring network traffic.
The traffic can contain normal traffic and various types of attack traffic.
The process of intrusion detection, is to determine,
among this set of all traffic,
which ones are normal,
which ones belong to different types of attacks.
In other words, intrusion detection,
is about classifying each number flow into normal or different attack types.
Therefore, it is natural to think that,
we can apply machine learning algorithm,
to learn a classifier, to detect intrusions.
That is, given a traffic data which has higher entropy,
because it is mixed with intrusions and normal traffic.
Our goal is to partition the data into subsets that each has a pure class.
Either normal or one of the attack types.
As we have discussed in decision tree,
we need to use features that has high information gain,
in this process of partitioning the original data set into subsets of pure classes.
So, that's the high level intuition,
of applying machine learning,
to the problem of intrusion detection.
Now let's discuss some details.