We start with raw data captured from the network tab,
for example, your pickup data.
From the pickup data,
we can summarize the data into connection records.
Each record has a set of attributes,
for example, time stamp, duration,
source IP, destination IP,
number of bytes, the service,
and the flag, and so on.
For example, SF means the connection has gone through both SYN and FIN,
and REJ means that the connection request has been rejected.
As we have discussed earlier,
having small features is the key to building effective classification models.
This is known as the feature construction problem.
In the context of intrusion detection,
the attributes or features of the connection records are not very useful.
For example, if you look at SYN flag,
that means, we only see the initial SYN packet.
Of course, with SYN flag,
we'll see a lot of connection attempts with SYN flag.
Of course, normal data can also have this S0 flag,
for example, because the connection request or response is lost.
That is, by looking at the feature flag,
it is not sufficient to detect intrusion.
On the other hand, if you look at the percentage of
S0 flag connections to particular host,
then we can see that this feature can distinguish intrusion from normal.
In other words, this feature has high information gain.
The problem is that this feature is not in the original feature set,
which means we need to construct features that have high information gains.
So, the question is how do we construct features that have high information gains?
That is, features that are useful to distinguish normal versus intrusions.
Our approach is to use temporal and statistical patterns associated with intrusions,
for example, a lot of S0 connections to the same service and host,
within a short period of time.
This pattern is associated with SYN flag.
Once we have these patterns,
we can then construct features accordingly that can be used to detect these intrusions.