The basic algorithms are the association rules and frequent episodes.
These algorithms can produce many useless patterns.
For example, these algorithms can produce associations
and frequent sequences involving source bytes and destination bytes.
These patterns are not useful for intrusion detection.
The reason is that, these patterns don't even involve
more important attributes such as a service and the flag.
Therefore, we modify the basic algorithms,
so that they only produce relevant or useful patterns.
The intuition is that,
development patterns must describe these essential features.
More specifically, we use some of
these essential features as a so-called axis attributes,
or reference attributes, to constrain how the patterns can be computed.