An axis attribute is typically the most important attribute,
for example, the service.
An association must contain an axis attribute.
Therefore, we can eliminate patterns that
describe associations among non-essential attributes.
Once we compute associations involving axis attributes,
then we can compute sequential patterns involving these associations,
and that's how we compute sequential patterns.
Here's an example. We use service as the axis attribute,
then we can compute a number of associations.
For example, there's frequent association of S zero and http.
We then use reference attribute to compute a sequence of related associations.
These associations in a sequence all refer to the same reference
subject because they are essentially a sequence of related actions.
For example, in this sequential pattern,
all associations are referring to the same destination host.
Again, the reference attribute can be used as a constraint to filter out patterns,
that are not useful for intrusion detection.