After we compute the frequent patterns from the normal data and from the intrusion data,
we can then compare and identify the unique patterns that are from the intrusion data.
We can then use these patterns to construct futures to build classifiers.
We call the axis and reference attributes the anatomy of an attack and
the emergence attributes are those that are
independent of the axis and reference attributes.
Since our patterns are frequent and sequential in nature,
we apply these operators to add the corresponding,
temporal and statistical features.
To summarize, we mind patterns from
both the intrusion and a normal datasets and compare the patterns.
We identify the patterns associated with only the intrusion dataset.
We construct futures according to
these patterns and add these features into the training dataset.
We can then apply a machine
learning algorithm to learn a classifier that can detect intrusions.