Now, let's discuss an evaluation of our approach.
We use the darpa evolution dataset.
There are 38 attack types in the data and these attack types are in four categories,
denial service, probing, remote to local,
and user to root.
In particular, remote to local means that gaining
local axis and user to root means that gaining superuser privilege.
In this evaluation, training dataset is provided
but 40 percent of the attack types are only in test data.
That is these attack types are new to the intrusion detection systems.
Here are the features that we defined and constructed for each connection record.
The intrinsic features such as protocol,
duration and flag, these are the ones that are inherent to any connection.
In other words, they can be used for many applications not just intrusion detection.
We construct a feature for the purpose of intrusion detection.
The content features are based on analysis of the payload.
For example, we can tell how many failed login attempts.
Whether the login was successful or not,
number of root shells,
whether a su root has been attempted,
number of access to security control files and so on.
We compute a frequent patterns from the connection record and
then we construct temporal and statistical features accordingly.
These include number of connections to the same destination host
as the current connection in the past two seconds and among these connections,
number of rejected connections,
number of connections with syn errors,
number of different services,
percentage of connections they have the same service,
percentage of different or unique services,
and number of connections they have
the same service as the current connection and among these connections,
number of rejected conditions,
number of connections with syn errors,
number of different destination hosts,
percentage of connections they have the same destination host,
percentage of different or unique designation hosts.
Here we showed examples of the values of content features interconnection record.
We also label each connection as normal or one of the attacks.
Here is some example rules produced by machine learning.
For example, a buffer overflow attack can be detected
because there are a number of indicators of compromise.
A root shell has to be attained and su root has not be attempted.
Here we show examples of the values of traffic features.
Again, each connection record is labeled as normal or one of the attacks,
and here are some example rules produced by machine learning.
For example, in a smurf attack
ICMP echo request has been sent to the same service on the same host.
Satan is a probing attack and therefore there are
many different ports or services being probed and since many of them are closed,
many connection attempts are rejected.