Let's have a quick overview of machine learning.
The task of machine learning is that,
given training examples, we would learn a function that can predict the output.
Then, once we learn this function,
we can apply it to testing examples and this function can then produce the output.
For example, the input can be fruits and the output can be the names of the fruits.
For example, is it an apple or orange?
A partition function will be able to analyze the features of
these fruits and determine whether it is apple versus orange.
The first step in machine learning is training.
Here, the Xs are the examples and the Ys are the labels of these examples.
Then, the machine learning algorithm is going to produce
the best possible function by minimizing the prediction error on this training data set.
We're going to discuss a few example machine learning algorithms.
In a testing phase, we apply the learned function to a set
of test data which was not used in training,
and the function should be able to produce predicted value of Y given X.
Ideally, data used in machine learning should reflect the real world.
Therefore, we use a process to draw data from the real-world application.
Then, that data is randomly split into a training data set and test data set.
We can then apply a machine learning algorithm to
a training data to learn the particular function that can be applied to test dataset.