Here is an example of machine learning.
Suppose you want to learn the name or predict the name of an object,
for machine learning purpose,
these objects are represented as feature vectors of their images.
For example, apple, tomato, and cow,
they're all represented as feature vectors,
and then our function based on these feature vectors can predict the type of the object.
So, let's go over the steps in this machine learning example.
We start with the images of these objects,
we then make exact features from these images so that
each of these objects now is represented as a feature vector.
Of course, we put the correct label to each object.
For example, all these are apples,
all these are pears, and so on.
Then, once we have the objects represented as feature vectors with their labels,
then we can apply machine learning algorithm to chain a predictive function.
This predictive function is the learned model.
In testing, again, we start with the image of an object,
we extract the same set of image features as in chaining.
That is, now the object is represented as a feature vector.
We then apply the learned model into this feature vector.
The learned model which is a predictive function is
going to tell us the prediction or the type of this object.