Now, let's discuss
browser security model.
Let's take a step back and compare
operating system with web browser.
An operating system supports multiple
applications to run on a computer at
the same time and allows them to
share the resources on a computer.
Similarly, a web browser can render
multiple webpages to different sites.
And each page can contain data and
code from multiple sources.
So it is instructive to compare
the operating system and
web browser security models.
For Operating System,
the primitives are system calls,
processes, and disk storage.
For Web Browser, the primitives
are Document Object Model or
DOM, frames, cookies and local storage.
The principles on the operating
system are users, and
associated with users is
the discretionary access control policy.
For web browser,
the principles are origins and
mandatory access control is used.
Vulnerabilities in operating system
can lead to buffer overflow,
root exploit and so on.
Whereas on web browser,
such vulnerabilities can
lead to cross-scripting,
cross-site request forgery,
cache history attacks, and so on.
Now let's take a look at
the execution model of web browsers.
Given a webpage,
the browser goes through these steps.
First, load the contents.
Second, renders the contents.
That is,
the browser processes the HTML pages and
runs each JavaScripts to display
the contents of the page.
The page may include images and
frames and so on.
And then the browser response to events.
What are the events
handled by a web browser?
The main events are user actions,
such as clicking, moving the mouse.
Rendering, like loading a page.
Timing such as Timeout.
The contents being rendered
can be from many sources.
For example, you could have scripts,
frames loading HTML pages,
Flash objects, etc.
By specifying allowscriptaccess,
the Flash object
can communicate with external data,
such as external scripts and
navigate external frames and
opening windows, etc.
The point is that there are many
contents from many sources, and
they can interact with each other.
Obviously, this makes it challenging for
enforcing security policies.
The basic idea of browser security
is to Sandbox web contents.
More specifically, we want to
safely execute JavaScript code.
Because it can be from a remote website,
this means that a JavaScript code
cannot access the file system directly.
It can only have limited access to
the operating system, the network and
browser data,
as well as content from other websites.
The main policy is the so-called
Same Origin Policy.
That means active code,
such as JavaScript, can only
read properties of documents and
windows from the same origin defined
as the same protocol, domain and port.
Now exceptions to this
policy can be allowed.
That means scripts that are assigned
by legitimate developers that a user
can trust, such as scripts signed
by Microsoft, Google, Apple, etc.
For example, the user can
grant these privileges such as
UniversalBrowserRead/Write,
UniversalFileRead, and so on.