First, anything changed or created is
not visible beyond its boundaries.
This can apply to both sandboxes and
virtual machines.
Sandboxes will isolate applications so
that other applications cannot see it.
To see changes in virtual machines
you must be in the virtual machine.
Second, if data is not saved,
it is lost when the application closes.
This is an advantage of sandbox.
And you can call it a security
strength of the sandbox
because any malware
downloaded will not be saved.
Third, virtual machines have their own
copies of complete operating systems.
There can be multiple operating
systems on a single hardware platform.
Four, sandbox is lightweight and
easy to set up.
Fifth, for virtual machines, disc space
must be allocated to the application.