Frame and
iFrame are like many browser windows.
A frame is typically rigid or fixed on
a page, whereas iFrame can be floating.
Here's an example of iFrame.
It essentially says that here is the
width and height of the frame window and
it will display this page.
So why do we discuss frames
in a context of web security?
Or in more general,
why do we even use frames?
As the previous simple example shows,
we can display a webpage within a frame,
or a minute browser window.
So, from this example,
it is obvious that frames provide
a natural isolation of separation
of different web contents.
For example, we can delegate screen
area to content from another source.
And a browser provides
isolation based on frames.
And, even if a frame is broken,
the parent window can still work.
Again, to display web contents from two
different sides, A and B, we can have
two different browser windows,
such as what we see here, A and B.
On the other hand,
we can achieve the same result
by having just one browser window,
let's say B here on the right-hand side.
And within it, we have a frame
that display contents from A.
The point is that we should be able
to achieve the same kind of isolation
whether we use two different browser
windows or use a frame within a window.
Again, we apply the same origin
policy to achieve frame security.
Specifically, each frame
of a page has an origin,
that's defined as protocol,
host, and port.
A frame can access only
the data from its own origin.
That is, a frame cannot access data
associated with a different origin.
Therefore, for example, even though we
have a frame within a browser window and
they display contents from different
sites, for example, A and B.
The same-origin policy guarantees that
these two sessions, the frame and
the browser window,
they don't interfere with each other.
So there was the default
same origin policy.
In addition, frame-to-frame access
control policy can also be specified.
For example, we can say canScript(A,B).
That means Frame A can execute
a script that manipulates
DOM elements of Frame B.
We can use canNavigate to specify that
Frame A can change the origin
of content for Frame B.
Likewise, we can specify policy for
frame to access principle.
For example, we can use readCookie,
writeCookie,
to specify that can Frame A read/write
cookies from a site.
You can read more about the web
browser security mottos
by following these links.