So far we have described the classic
web browser security models.
To understand the more
modern mechanisms,
let's define browsing context.
A browsing context may
be a frame with its DOM,
that is a frame with web contents.
Or web worker,
which does not have a DOM.
A web worker as defined by
the World Wide Web Consortium or W3C and
the Web Hypertext Application Technology
Working Group is a Javascript executed
from HTML page that runs in the
background independently of other user
interface scripts that may also have
been executed from the same HTML page.
In short, a web worker is a Javascript
that runs in the background and
it is independent of
the user interface elements.
Now, every browsing
context has an origin.
Again, an origin is determined
by protocol, host, and port.
And as such, our browsing context
is isolated from another context
by the same-origin policy.
Different browsing contexts may
communicate using postMessage.
And they can make network
requests through XHR or tags.
XHR stands for XML HTTP Request.
It is an API available to Javascript.
Typically, XHR is used to send HTTP or
HTTPS requests to a web server.
And lo, the server responds
data back into the script.
That is, a Javascript use XHR to
request contents from a web server.
There are similarities between
browsing context and process context.
An opening system uses separation and
isolation to allow multiple
execution context and provide local
storage and communication services.
Similarly while a web browser provides
common local storage it uses isolation
and separation to provide security
protection to the browsing contexts.
The modern browser mechanisms
that can be used for
security protection include
HTML5 iframe Sandbox.
Content security policy.
Cross Origin resource sharing.
And HTML Web Workers.
Sub Resource Integrity.
And we're going to discuss
these mechanisms now.
As in operating systems, sandbox is
very useful for browser security.
The idea is to restrict frame actions.
When we used a directive Sandbox for
frame essentially
we are insuring that the iframe has
unique origin, cannot submit forms, and
APIs are disabled, and
it can prevent contents from plugins.
On the other hand when we create
iframe if we use Sandbox allow-scripts
directive, then we only ensure
that iframe has unique origin.
But we can allow
the rest of the actions.
For example,
here's a Twitter button in iframe.
In this example,
there's no Sandbox related directive.
So this you can call
it the classic iframe.
Now we can use a Sandbox directive here.
We specified the Sandbox directive.
But then we also specified that
we will allow Javascripts and
allow form submissions and so on.
This simple example shows that we can
use the Sandbox directive associated
with the iframe in order to specify
the security policy that's appropriate.
Here are the list of Sandbox permissions
that you can specify for iframe.