Now, let's discuss cross
origin resource sharing.
We've been discussing
the same origin policy,
which means that cross origin reading
and writing is typically not allowed.
Now, what happens when
a website has multiple domains?
For example, Amazon, the company has
both the amazon.com and aws.co websites.
These two domains belong
to the same company, so
we expect that they should be
able to share some resources.
Now of course,
we want the same origin policy, so
that another analytic website cannot
easily access resource from Amazon.
Cross Origin Resource Sharing is
a technique that we can use to relax
the same-origin policy, so
that JavaScript on a web page such as on
amazon.com now can consume
content from different origin.
Let say, aws.com.
It basically uses wireless.
For example, amazon.com can list
the domains that it allowed.
Here's how
Cross Origin Resource Sharing works.
The browser sends the options
request to the origin HTTP header.
The value of this header is the domain
that served the parent page.
For example, when a page from amazon.com
attempts to access a users data
in aws.com, the following request
header will be sent to aws.com.
That is it specifies
origin https://amazon.com.
The server can inspect
the Origin header and
respond whether the access is allowed or
not.
For example,
the server can send back an error page,
if the server does not allowed
the cross origin request or
it can specify which origin
is allowed to access.
For example, in this case, the origin
https://amazon.com is allowed or
it can use a roll call to say
that all domains are allowed.