In a domain is any domain-suffix
of a URL-hostname,
except the top level domain.
For example,
the web server login.site.com can
set cookies for all of site.com.
Because site.com is a suffix, but not
another site or the TLD, which is .com.
Using this rule the cookies
is set by login.site.com have
these allowed domains,
login.site.com and site.com.
And these domains are not allowed
because they are other domains or
the TLD, .com.
And path can be set to
anything within that domain.
How are domains identified?
They are identified by name,
domain, and path.
Here we have two cookies.
Both cookies store in
browser's cookie jar.
And both are in scope of login.site.com,
but they're distinct.
What are the policies for
a server to read cookies?
In other words,
the reading same origin policy.
The browser sends all
cookies in URL scope,
which is determined by domain and path.
And the goal is that server should
only see cookies in its own scope.
Here's an example.
We have two cookies,
both set by login.site.com.
The different servers see different
cookies depending on their scopes.
For example the server
http://checkout.site.com
only sees Cookie2 because it's
within the scope of site.com.
Another example, http://login.site.com,
again, only sees Cookie2.
And the reason is Cookie1
requires secure which
means that the connection
has to be HTTPS.
The third example here,
https://login.site.com,
it can use both Cookie1 and Cookie2.
What are the rules for
client-side read/write of cookies?
A JavaScript can set cookie values.
It can also read out
the attributes of a cookie.
It can even delete a cookie.
The exception is that if
the cookie is set as HTTP only,
that means it cannot be accessed
by client-side scripts.
Which means client-side scripts cannot
read or write this HttpOnly cookie.