Obviously, we can use cryptography to
provide data integrity protection.
The main idea is that when
a server sets a cookie attribute,
it will attach a integrity check
value for the attribute, and
it can later on check whether
that attribute has been modified.
So to do this, the server uses a secret
key that is unknown to the browser,
and for each attribute value that is
set, it computes a integrity check.
The courier tag T, that essentially
is a message authentication code,
using the secret key k, and
compute over the session ID the name and
value of the attribute.
And when it sets the cookie,
we attach the message authentication
code to each attribute value.
When a browser, later on,
presents the cookie to a server,
the server can then check the integrity
of that cookie attribute value.
The server essentially
uses the secret key and
compute over the session ID, name and
value of the cookie attribute,
and then verify that
the result is the same as T.
Again, because T is computed
using the secret key,
the browser cannot compute it.
So that is, only the server can
compute T, and the server can use T
to verify that the attribute value
of the cookie is not changed.
Here's a example of how this
can be done in the real world.
So a server key can be generated and
the integrity of a cookie can
be protected using this key.
Similarly, integrity can be tracked.
Here, are the example
APIs that you can use
to provide cookie integrity protection.