Before we go into
the details of web security,
let's understand how
the modern web works.
For typical website, it contains
both static and active contents.
The active contents, or the code,
can be from many sources and
they can be combined in many ways.
Then the security challenges are we
have many different types of data and
codes for many different sources.
And they run and
interact with each other.
For example,
on a typical web page we have code or
data related to the page itself,
the third-party API's, for
example to tutor, third-party
libraries to how you navigate and
scripts that run advertising contents.
And the data and codes on a website
can be from many different sources,
by many different developers.
For example,
a website can have many parties
contributing to its data and code.
These include page developers,
library developers,
service providers, data providers,
ad providers, and other users,
and extension developers,
such as the web app developers and
the CDN's,
the content distribution networks.
Obviously these parties can be from
different vendors and companies.
So the basic security questions are with
data and codes from so many different
sources, how do we ensure data And
integrity when we browse the web?
For example, we need to figure out
how to protect page from ads and
services because they
are from different sources.
On the other hand, maybe there's
a legitimate reason to share data
when they are from different sources.
That is, how do we share data
with cross-origin page and
how do we protect one user
from another user's content?
How do we protect the page
from a third-party library?
How do we protect a page from
the content distribution network?
And how do we protect
browser extensions from page?