Now let's discuss another
Botnet Detection System, Botminer.
The first question is, why do we need
another Botnet detection system.
Notice that Bot hunter is based on some
specific Botnet infection life cycles.
But Botnet can have different
infection life cycles and
they can change the protocols and
structures of the command control.
For example, Botnet can use
a centralized command-control system or
fully distributed
peer-to-peer control system.
Our goal is to have a Botnet
detection system that is independent
of the command-control protocol and
structure.
In order to achieve this goal,
we need to focus on the intrinsic
properties of Botnet.
In particular, Bots are for long-term
use, and bot with the Botnet have
similar or coordinated communication and
activities.
Therefore, we need to
perform both vertical and
horizontal correlation,
here's the architecture of BotMiner.
We arrive at this architecture based
on the definition of a Botnet.
We coded a botnet is a coordinated
group of malware instances,
they're controlled via
Command Controlled Channels.
The C-Plane monitor here, is for
monitoring Command Controlled Traffic
and A-Plane here, is for
monitoring malicious activities
because these are malware instances.
On both planes, we perform clustering to
detect groups they are in correlated or
similar ways.
Then we use cross-plane correlation to
detect a group of machines that perform
similarly in both command control
activities and malicious activities.
And these are parts of the same Botnet,
here's a workflow of C-plane clustering.
First of all, a flow record for
connection between a local host and
a remote service is defined
by the protocol, source and
destination IP Destination port,
time, and number of bytes.
All flow records go through a number
of steps that include filtering,
aggregation, feature extraction,
and clustering.
Here are some example of our features,
look at bytes per second,
flows per hour, bytes per packet, and
packets per flow and
we perform clustering in two steps.
In step one, we group C-flow records
into course-grained clusters.
In step two, within each of
these course-grained clusters,
we further position them
into finer grain groups.
The main idea here is that we
can use a small set of features
to perform course-grain clustering.
Because the number of features
that we use is small,
this step is very efficient.
There within each course-grained
cluster, you can afford to use the full
feature space to perform
fine-grained clustering.
In A-plane clustering, we first
cluster based on activity type, for
example, this is scan, spam,
binary downloading or exploit.
Within each activity,refer
to use the features
that tend traffic to perform clustering.
For example for scan, we can use the
destination sump nets and the ports and
for spam we can use a spam template.
Again the main idea
of A-plane clustering
is to capture similar activity
patterns among the hosts.
In cross-plane correlation
we are looking for
the intersection between a-plane and
c-plane clusters.
Intuitively, hosts,
there in the sections,
have similar malicious activities and
similar C&C patterns.
In particular, if two machines appear
in the same activity clusters and
in at least in one common C-cluster.
That means they should be
clustered together because
they're in the same Botnet.