So far, we have discussed botnet
detection in the Enterprise network.
Now, let's discuss how we
detect botnets on the internet.
We observed that a botnet must
use internet protocols and
services in order to maintain
a network infrastructure.
For example,
in order to maintain its network
structure must use some sort of look-up
services to find command-and-control
servers or the peers.
And you know that to support is
various kinds of malicious activities,
a botnet must use hosting services,
for example to store and
distribute attack data and
for malware download.
A botnet can also use transport services
to route or hide its attack traffic.
Therefore by identifying the abnormal
use of internet services,
we can detect botnet
activities on the internet.
In this lesson, let's focus on DNS.
And the reason is that most bots use
DNS to locate command control and
hosting service.