Now let's focus on how do we detect
that a domain is used for upon as C&C.
There are a number of heuristics
based on observations.
First, member masses purchase a domain,
they must use credit card, and
that leaves traceable
financial information.
And the other limit such traceable
information as little as possible.
Therefore, they may do the so-called
package deal, where for
one second level domain,
they're going to use it for
multiple three level domains for
botnets, for example here for
the same package deal for
the second level domain evilhacker.org,
there are multiple botnets using
different three level domains,
the point is that with a single
financial transaction,
they can support multiple botnets,
therefore
we can cluster the three level domains
under the same second level domain
that's looks similar in their names or
they resolved to similar subnets of IPs.
Because they're likely to
be botnets they're related.
And we sum up the look-ups to all
of these domains within a cluster.
By doing so we will compare the look-up
patterns of legitimate domains.
which is the Botnet domains
they look different.
That is the Botnet domains tend
to have larger lookup volumes.
And remember these domains
are in dynamic DNS providers and
the domains tend to be small and
medium sized businesses,
therefore legitimate domains will not
have a very large lookup volumes.
Another observation is that bots tend
to look up their their Command and
Control service as soon as their host
machines are connected to the internet.
The intrusion is that bots must
maintain communication with
the command control server and since
they have no control over when the host
machines connect to the internet,
they must take their first opportunity.
The result is that there
is an exponential arrival
of DNS request from the bots,
whereas legitimate DNS lookups by normal
user activities is a lot smoother.
For example, Human uses don't all
immediately check the same side.
Therefore, if you sought the lookout
volume per hour by 24 hour windows,
we can see the exponential arrival
rate of the bot's queries,
whereas human queries
are a lot smoother.
There are other detection heuristics.
For example, the look up's
are from all over the internet.
And a C&C server is resolved to many
different IP's across the internet.
And the resolved IP address
change frequently and so on.
Any of these observations alone
cannot effectively detect
a Botnet command control domain.
And therefore,
we combine them in a detection system.