Now let's discuss how we detect
botnets in large networks such an ISP.
Here, we can focus on the DNS queries
that can be observed by the recursive
DNS server and the ISP.
That is, we can analyze the Internet
traffic from the internal host to
the DNS server.
In particular,
we can detect any abnormal growth
of the popularity of a domain name.
It can suggest that this domain name
is used for botnet command-control.
Intuitively, the reason
that a botnet will grow
is that more machines become infected,
and become bots.
Therefore, the growth pattern of
a botnet corresponds to the propagation
pattern of an infection.
According to studies, exploit-based
infection grows exponentially.
Email-based infection grows
exponentially or linearly.
And dry-by downloads
growth likely sublinear.
In a large ISP, there are many domain
names being looked up every day.
But we don't have to
analyze all domain names.
In fact, we can focus on
a few anomalous domain names.
These are domain names
that look suspicious.
In particular, many regularly spelled,
easily sounding domain names
have been taken up by businesses and
individuals already.
Therefore botnets are forced to use
very random looking domain names.
In other words, these random looking
domain names are suspicious.
And then we need to
analyze the growth pattern
of these suspicious domain names.
In particular, we look for
the exponential or
linear growth of their popularities.
Here's a sketch of our ideas.
We assume a baseline of N days,
and we assume that,
within this N days,
all domains are legitimate.
Therefore, we record these
domains In a Bloom filter.
A Bloom filter is a very
efficient representation of set.
That is, we use the Bloom filter
to record a set of domains
observed within these N days.
We also use a Markov model to model
how these domain names are spelled.
After this baseline, whenever we
observe a new domain, that is,
a domain that is not in our Bloom
filter on a set of recorded domains.
And if this domain does
not fit our Markov model,
that means it is spelled in
a different way and looks suspicious.
Then we know that we have a new and
suspicious domain.
Then we analyze the lookup sequence
to this new and suspicious domain.
And if the growth is linear or
exponential, then we know that
this domain is used for botnets.
So far we have discussed
botnet detection.
The latest threats are more targeted and
more advanced.
For example, the use custom built
malware on zero-day exploits,
their activities are low-and-slow and
they move within network and
covering their tracks.
Even the existing botnet detection
systems are not effective
against these targeted advanced threats.
In order to counteract
these targeted and
advanced threats, we need
multifaceted monitoring and analysis.
That is we need malware analysis,
host-based monitoring, forensics, and
recovery, network monitoring,
Internet monitoring, threat analysis,
and attribution.