Let's analyze why the traditional
security measures cannot detect Botnets
effectively.
First of all,
traditional signature-based
anti-virus systems are not effective,
because bot codes are typically packed
and they can use rootkit to hide.
And they also use frequent updates
to defeat anti-virus tools.
The traditional IDS/IPS are not
effective, because they typically look
at the specific aspect of an attack For
example, let's be specific exploit.
Whereas Botnet typically perform
multiple kinds of activities,
because they are for long-term use.
That is, although we can detect that a
host has been compromised by an exploit,
we do not know that
it belongs to Botnet.
Because we need to analyze its
command control traffic and
daily malicious activities.
Honeypots and
Honeynets are also not effective.
First of all,
since they only passively waiting for
incoming connections they are to be
lucky to capture botnet activities.
In addition, sophisticated bot malware
can detect a honeypot because the lack
of realistic user activities.
And since a Honeypot is a single host
it cannot detect a network of bots.