Now let's discuss DNC cache
poisoning attacks in more detail.
Let's start with traditional
poisoning attack.
Suppose the attacker wants to poison the
cache of the DNS server at gartech.edu.
In particular, the attacker wants to
forge the IP address of www.google.com.
The attacker first sends a query
to the local DNS server.
This can be done, for example, through a
compromised machine within gartech,edu.
The local DNS server is
now going to perform
a recursive query with
the query ID 12345.
And at some point the main server,
ns1.google.com,
is going to provide
an authoritative answer
given the IP address of www.google.com
with a matching query ID.
Now the attacker knows that this
recursive query is taking place.
Because he has an inside hub that
initiated the original lookup.
So the attacker is going to forge
a response claiming it is from
ns1.google.com.
And in that response it's
going to use the IP address
of evil.com instead of the real
IP address of www.google.com.
But the attacker does not
know the real query ID, so
all he can do is send a flood of
responses, each with a guest query ID.
So this is a matter of the attacker
being able to guess the correct query ID
and reach the local
DNS server faster than
the legitimate response from
the real DNS server of Google.
If the attack succeeds,
then the incorrect answer will be
cached resulting in cache poisoning.
But if the attacker's attempt fails,
the legitimate IP will be cached and
the attacker has to wait for
TTL to expire before launching
the whole attack again.
As you can see,
the traditional poisoning attack
is hard to successfully implement.
But then Kaminsky found
an approach that's drastically
more effective than
the traditional attack.
The general approach is the same
as the traditional attack.
But the key difference is
the nature of the forged payload.
The intention of cache poisoning
is to poison the final answer
that is the A record
with the IP address.
But what then Kaminsky discovered
is that we can go up one level and
hijack the authority records instead.
As in the previous example, let's assume
that the attacker wants to poison
the cache of the DNS server caltech.edu.
And he wants to forge the IP
address of www.google.com.
But this time the inside help
is going to send a query
of a random domain
within www.google.com.
For example, 12345678.www.google.com.
And as before the DNS Server is
going to perform a recursive query.
Now the legitimate response, you say
that this random domain does not exist.
But you will provide the IP
address of www.google.com.
The attacker is attempting
to do the same thing.
The goal is to have the DNS
server cache this raw IP address.
And you may ask, what's new here?
Isn't the attacker facing the same
challenge of guessing correctly
the query ID before the response from
Google In the traditional attack.
When the first attempt fails, the
attacker has a way for TTL to expire.
What's new here in
the Kaminsky's Poisoning Attack is that
when a first attempt fails, the attacker
can start immediately again.
That is, it doesn't have two wait for
TTL to expire and the reason is he can
simply use a different random domain and
that will immediately
result in another query.
So that he can flood
the DNS server again.
That is, the attacker can repeatedly and
continuously force the local DNS
server to query a random domain.
And keep flooding the local DNS server
until the poisoning attack succeeds.
Yet when you put it that,
such Kaminsky's Poisoning Attack
can succeed in mere ten seconds.