Even DNS-SEC cannot
prevent all DNS attacks.
The DNS Rebinding Attack
is one such example.
To among a DNS rebinding attack,
the attacker needs only register
a domain name, such as evil.com.
And attract web traffic, for example,
by running an advertisement in a frame.
In this attack, when evil.com is
looked up, the attacker answers with
the IP address of his own server and
use a very short TTL value.
The attacker's server, evil.com,
also serves the browser
a malicious JavaScript.
To circumvent the firewall,
when the malicious JavaScript issues a
query to evil.com, the TTL has expired.
The attacker then rebinds the host name,
evil.com,
to an IP address of an internal server.
That is, now the firewall thinks
that evil.com is internal.
The browser now believes that these
two servers belong to the same origin,
because they share the same host name,
www.evil.com.
So it will allows script
to read back the response.
Therefore, the malicious script
can easily extra trade information
from the server to evil.com.
That is now the attacker is able
to read arbitrary documents
from the internal server.
To mitigate such attack,
the browser should use DNS Pinning.
Meaning that, you should refuse the
switching to new IP address for domain.
On the other hand,
this means that it may break proxies,
VPNs, dynamic DNS and so on.
Therefore, it is not consistently
implemented in all browsers.
For the internal servers,
they should check Host headers for
unrecognized domains such as evil.com.
It should also provide stronger
authentication of users.
For the firewall is
to implement a policy
such that external domain names cannot
resolve to internal IP address.
It should provide stronger protection
of browsers within the network.