We have discussed how we can scan [inaudible] state information,
but how do we validate the responses?
The idea here is that we can encode secrets into the fields of the probe packets.
This is similar to the SYN cookies.
Here are the formats of the Ethernet,
IP and TCP packets,
and some of the fields here can be used to encode the secrets.
In order to validate packets, we receive.
We encode a scan invocation and host-specific secret into
mutable fields that will have a recognizable effect on the probe responses.
Specifically, for each scan host ZMap computes
a hash of the destination address keyed by the scan's specific secret.
This MAC value or Message Authentication Code
is then spread across any appropriate and available fields.
In the case of using a TCP SYN packet for scanning,
we encode the secret into the source port and sequence number.
We know that the destination host will have to
include the port and sequence number to send a response.
For example, a sequence number will be encoded into the acknowledgement number field.
More precisely, in response packet the receiver port was the sender port in
the scanning packet and
the acknowledgement number is the sequence number of the scanning packet.