Here are the high level workflows of ZMap.
To send scanning packets,
ZMap will be configured,
for example, of a random permutation of the address space.
And then the probing packets will be sent to
these addresses according to the random permutation.
Since the majority of fields in a probe packet never change,
ZMap performs all network operations at
the ethernet layer using a raw socket in order to cache values.
This eliminates time lost to kernel operations such as route lookups.
This allows ZMap to send probing packets at a very high speed and validate the responses.
For example, checking the MAC value and the probing results can then be analyzed.
This configuration allows ZMap to send probes at approximately
1.4 million packets per second on a gigabit network.
ZMap is an extensible framework to allow any type of
single packet scan such as a TCP sync scan,
ICMP echo requests or application-specific UDP scan.
The ZMap framework abstracts out details such as configuration,
timing, addressing and validation.