The first major question is whether ZMap
or our network can handle scanning at gigabit speed.
In order to answer this question researchers at
the University of Michigan perform 10 trials scanning one percent of the IPB for address
space at different rates ranging from 1,000 packets per
second to the maximum 1.4 million packets per second.
This maximum is determined by the NIC configuration.
NIC stands for network interface card.
As we can see there is no correlation
between a scanning rate and the number of hosts that respond.
One way to interpret this result is that
even slower scanning rates does not produce additional response.