Another interesting question is,
"Is one probe packet sufficient or is sending multiple packets beneficial?"
This is difficult to answer directly because there is
no ground truth for the number of live hosts on the Internet.
In order to estimate ZMap coverage,
multiples in packets were sent to one percent samples of the IPv4 address space.
If you look at the number of responses we clearly see a plateau after a SYN packets.
In fact, we should expect to see an eventual plateau in a number
of responsive hosts regardless of additional SYN packets sent.
Analyzing these results we can estimate that with a single packet the coverage is about
97.9 percent and with three packets the coverage is 99.4 percent.