Many previous projects have used the popular Nmap network scanner to perform scans.
Therefore, we should compare ZMap with Nmap.
The researchers performed several experiments focusing
on the total time spent for scanned and scan coverage.
In these experiments, one million addresses were scanned.
In these experiments, Nmap used the most aggressive scan template called
insane and with a minimal scan rate of 10,000 packets per second.
As we can see from these results,
ZMap is capable of scanning the IPv4 address
space more than 1,300 times faster than Nmap.
ZMap also has higher coverage than Nmap even when Nmap sends multiple probes.
To be fair, Nmap is
an excellent multi-purpose network scanner and it is
optimized for completely different use cases than ZMap.
So why does ZMap have higher coverage than Nmap?
We analyzed the response time of the scan responses.
ZMap does not timeout hosts, but Nmap does.
In fact, if Nmap sent one packet,
it times out after 250 milliseconds.
If it uses two packets,
it times out after 500 milliseconds.
As you can see, some responses arrive after Nmap has timed out.
Ultimately, since ZMap uses stateless scanning and does not keep state,
it has both increased performance and increased coverage.
Ultimately, since ZMap uses stateless scanning,