Now, let's discuss a few interesting internet-wide security studies using ZMap.
In one study, the researchers scanned the HTTPS servers
and the SSH servers and collected their public keys.
As you can see, a large number of machines share their public keys.
Although there are lot legitimate reasons why machines would share their keys,
we need to understand whether the keys happen to be the
same without the intention of sharing because that is bad for security.
In particular, researchers find that some of
these machines share their key in a vulnerable manner.
For example, they simply use the default keys without creating
their own keys and there's
a apparent entropy problem that caused them to have the same keys.
Let's look at the effect of not having sufficient entropy.
As a quick review, in RSA,
the public key n is the product of p and q,
where p and q are large random prime numbers.
The security of RSA is based on the fact that
factoring n back to p and q is very, very inefficient.
That is, it's very hard for the attacker.
On the other hand, if two private keys N_1 and N_2 share the same prime number, say p,
then it's trivial to compute p because p is
the greatest common denominator of N_1 and N_2.
The reason that two different public keys may have
the same prime number can be that there's not sufficient entropy and therefore
two machines may happen to generate the same large prime number
p. There is also a very efficient algorithm due to D.J.
Bernstein to compute the GCD of every pair of N_1 and N_2.
With this efficient approach,
the researchers were able to crack many keys on TLS and SSH machines.
The majority of these machines are network devices.