Now, let's look at why these embedded systems or network devices generate broken keys.
These embedded systems all run Linux and they
all use urandom to generate cryptographic keys.
Linux maintains several entropy pools.
As entropy is gathered,
it is stored in the input pool and is eventually mixed
into the non-blocking pool which feeds urandom.
However, many of these sources are not present on an embedded system.
For example, the system may not have
keyboard and many of them don't have spindle-based disks.
In fact, most of these embedded systems don't even support real-time clocks.
Therefore, with all of these random sources removed,
we end up with a deterministic source of randomness.
Furthermore, entropy is a mix from
the input pool to the non-blocking pool until there are more than,
192 bits of entropy have been collected.
Therefore, even if a small amount of entropy has been collected on a device,
none of it is available until the pool reaches this threshold.
This graph shows the build-up of entropy on
the first boot of a typical Ubuntu desktop server.
No randomness is added from the input pool to
urandom until 192 bits of entropy is available.
From the graph, we can tell that this did not
happen until fairly late in the boot process.
This is the so-called Boot-Time Entropy Hole problem,
which means that urandom may be predictable for a period after boot.
Unfortunately, cryptographic keys may be based on this predictable urandom.