Let's have a quick review of how certificates is used in Web browsing.
Browsers such as Firefox decide who they trust.
These certificates are stored as part of the browser or the operating system.
Browsers typically support a couple of hundred root certificates, such as this.
These root certificate authorities then agree to sign other certificates for example,
Equifax is a root certificate authority and agrees to sign Google with authority.
And this can go on in moving
multiple intermediates and we end up having a certificate chains.
That is, if you look at Google.com,
it's signed by a chain of certificates and a top
certificate is just a self-signed certificate.
This entire chain is presented by
Web browser to the client and the client can verify the signatures
by traversing the certificate chain
up to the browser trusted certificate, which is self-signed.
The researchers at the University of Michigan perform
regular scans to try the use of certificates.
They observe 3,700 browser trusted certificates in one year.
They also discovered two cases of misused certificates.
In one case, a signing certificate was accidentally issued to a Turkish transit provider.
In another case, 1,300 certificates were issued by the Korean government.