At a high level, there are several worrisome observations.
First, the certificate authorities are ignoring defense in depth, a least privilege.
They are offering services that put the whole ecosystem at risk and they're
using some weak keys and deploying HTTPS remains difficult.
Let's go on with these observations next.
For defense in depth, there are several technical practices already in
place for limiting the scope of a signing certificate including setting,
name or path length constrains and distributing
leave certificates among a large number of intermediate certificates.
There are clear cases for using these restrictions but the vast majority of the time,
the CA's do not utilize these options.
As another example, local domain names are not
fully qualified and intended resource is ambiguous and there is no identifiable owner.
As such, these local domain names frequently appear on more than one certificate.
In one example, there are about 1,218 browser trusted certificates for a domain male,
owned by organizations ranging from the U.S. Department of Defense to small companies.
In terms of the keys used,
the researchers also find that 90 percent of the certificates
use a 2048 bit or 4096 bit RSA keys.
But 50 percent of the certificates are rooted in the 1024 bit key.
More importantly, more than 70 percent of these will expire
after 2016 and many still use signs using MD5.