There are a lot of benefits from Internet Wide Security Scanning.
For example, we can discover new vulnerabilities,
we can understand how a defensive mechanism has been adopted.
On the other hand, Internet Wide Security Scanning means that
we have to probe the entire address space and with existing tools,
this is very difficult and slow task.
On the other hand, some of the Security Studies
does require the scanning of the entire address space.
For example, if we can obtain the cryptographic keys in the entire address space,
then we can understand the ecosystem of
public key infrastructure and its vulnerabilities.