In fact there have been quite a few inferential Internet-Wide Network Studies.
For example, in 2012 researchers at
the University of Michigan released a paper
describing the weak keys used in network devices.
In particular, they found vulnerabilities in more than five percent of HTTPS hosts and
10 percent of SSH hosts but a study required a lot of computing powers and time.
Similarly there's a study from
the Electronic Frontier Foundation on public key certificates.
Again the study requires a lot of effort and
a comprehensive scan of the whole internet also requires months of efforts.
All these projects require heroic effort just to perform initial data collection.
As you can see these scans require
massive polarization and typically they also require an extended period of time.
Given the benefits of Internet-Wide Network Security Studies
we want to see just a few more of them.