But in order to do that,
Internet surveys should not require heroic efforts.
For example, it would be nice if we can scan the whole HTTPS ecosystem every day.
Given that existing tools are so slow,
researchers at the University of Michigan wrote ZMap,
a new Internet scanner, from scratch.
ZMap is a fully-functional open-source network scanner that can
scan a single port on the IPv4 address space.
On a gigabit network,
it can cover 98 percent of
the IPv4 address space from a single machine in under 45 minutes.
With ZMap, performing a scan on the Internet no longer
requires hundreds of hours of coding or months to execute.
Now, performing an Internet scan is
a single command which could be finished within an hour.