While there are many excellent multi-purpose network scanners,
these scanners were never intended or optimized for scanning the entire Internet.
ZMap, on the other hand,
was designed from the ground up for
the specific purpose of completely scanning the whole Internet.
Let's compare existing network scanners with ZMap.
Existing network scanners need quite immense amount of
resources to keep track of state of the entire Internet.
ZMap, on the other hand,
eliminate local per-connection state.
Existing scanners also spend a lot of resources keeping
track of which host is being scanned and which host have responded.
On the other hand, ZMap uses
Shotgun Scanning Approach and keeps minimum state information.
Previous scanners have been attempting to be more polite by slowing the scans.
ZMap, on the other hand,
distributes the scan across the Internet.
This allow ZMap to scan at
more aggressive rate without impacting the destination networks.
Finally, ZMap also bypasses
the inefficient network stack in
the operating system and generate outgoing packets directly.