If we simply poll network actresses in numerical order,
we will risk overloading the destination networks.
However, we also don't want to have to track what host we have scanned or need to scan.
In order to scan according to a random permutation,
we select addresses according to a cyclic group.
Specifically, we iterate over a multiplicative group of
integers modulo a prime number slightly larger than 2^32.
Here's an example of how do we randomly iterate through all the numbers in a group.
Here, the generator is 5,
and we start with number 2.
The process is we multiply the current number by 5 mod 7,
and the result is the next number,
and all numbers will be enumerated or iterated.
For example, we start with 2.
2 multiply by 5 mod 7 is 3.
So we move 3.
3 times 5 mod 7 is 1, and so on.
As you can see we can iterate through all the numbers in a group.
Following that simple example,
here's how we can iterate through the addresses in address space.
Each scan is essentially a random permutation of the address space.
Again, we treat the address space as a multiplicative group.
So we first decide on the generator and then we choose a random starting address.
With this approach, we can guarantee that
all addresses in the address space can be iterated.
More importantly, there's very little state information we need to keep track of.
Essentially, for each scan,
we need to keep track of the primitive root or the generator and the current address
because when the first address is visited
again we know that we have iterated all the addresses in the address space.
As you can see, this is very little information to keep track of for each scan.