Now let's discuss a threshold secret sharing scheme by Shamir.
Shamir is the S in RSA and in 1979,
he invented a (k,n) threshold scheme.
Here's how Shamir's secret sharing scheme works.
We choose a random k-1 coefficients;
a1, a2, a3 through a_k1.
We let the secret S be a0.
In other words, we pick a random k-1 degree polynomial and we represent it as this.
Again, a0 is a secret S,
and a1, a2 through a_k-1 are randomly chosen.
Then we construct n points on this polynomial.
That is, for i=1,
2 all the way through n,
we compute q of i.
Then we construct n points of the polynomial q(x).
That is, for i=1, 2,
all the way through n, we compute Si equal to q of i.
For example, if i=1,
we set x=1 for q(x).
This Si's are essentially the shares of S.
All arithmetic operations are done modulo a prime number p,
and p is greater than S and n. Again,
the coefficients a1, a2,
through a_k-1 are randomly chosen from a uniform distribution over the integers in
the range of 0 and p. Given any subset of k of these pairs or points,
we can find the coefficients of the polynomial q(x) by interpolation.
Of course, once we find the coefficients,
we have determined the polynomial q(x).
This is guaranteed by the mathematical property that any k points
can uniquely determine a polynomial of degree k-1.
Once q(x) is determined,
then we set x equal to 0 and compute q(0),
that will give us a0,
which is the original secret S. In other words,
with this scheme given any K shares,
we can reconstruct the secret.