Here's an example. Suppose k equal to two.
That is, the polynomial is a linear function, a line.
Suppose all you know is one point, say S1.
You cannot determine the polynomial because there are
infinite number of lines that go through S1.
It is clear that you need two points to determine a line.
For example, if you know both S1 and S2,
then you can reconstruct the line and then you can compute S,
which is the original secret.
Notice that, this example also shows that obviously,
any two points on a line can determine the same line,
which means any two of the entries can help you
reconstruct the original secret S. In general,
when we need to determine q(X),
we should use the Lagrange interpolation algorithm.