Let's use an example to illustrate.
Suppose k is three and n is five.
Further, the ultra secret is seven and a0 is seven,
a1 is three and a2 is five and the modular prime number p is 11.
That is; qx is 5x squared plus 3x plus seven modular 11.
Since n is five,
we compute five shares of five points by setting x to be one,
two, three, four, and five,
and these are the shares.
Since k is three with three shares,
we should be able to reconstruct the secret.
Say we have three shares S1, S2, and S5.
Then we can use this formula due to Lagrange to compute qx.
So, we can plug in these points to the formula that is setting the x,
i or j's to be one,
two and five and setting the y,
i's to be four, zero, and four.
Then we have qx represented as this formula.
With simple arithmetic, you can verify that qx is five x squared plus 3x plus seven.
Then we set x to zero and q of zero is seven
which is the original secret and this is how we use Shamir's Secret Sharing Scheme.