In practice, if we set n equal to 2k minus one,
that will require an attacker to compromise
more than half of the shares in order to reconstruct the original secret.
In general, we typically assume that
an attacker cannot compromise the majority of our systems.
Let's summarize the security properties of Shamir's secret sharing scheme.
First of all, shares can be dynamically
added or deleted without affecting the other shares.
Second, security can be easily enhanced without changing a secret.
For example, we can change the polynomial,
recompute the shares, and then,
give the new shares to the participants.
Third, in organizations where hierarchy is important,
we can supply each participant different number of shares according to their importance.
For example, the CEO can have all the shares so that he alone can reconstruct the secret,
whereas three VPs are required together to reconstruct the secret.
Fourth, this scheme cannot be broken
even when the adversary has unlimited computing power.
That is, the attacker has to have k shares.
Otherwise, no matter how much power he has,
he can only be a random guest.