Now let's discuss how do we make system services tolerate attacks.
First, we will discuss a related area called fault tolerance.
A fault in the system is the cost of an error that leads to a system failure.
Again, a system error is because of a fault,
and error leads to a failure.
Fault tolerance can be achieved through a failure masking.
And failure masking can be achieved through redundancy.
For example, let's look at a example system.
Here, a single fault in any of these three components can lead to a failure.
An example of redundancy is triple modular redundancy.
We can put motors at each stage of the system.
And each voter accepts the majority as the correct output from the components.
This scheme can mask any single failure of the components.