Getting a set of non-faulty services to reach consensus is actually quite challenging.
Let's use an example to illustrate.
The Byzantine Generals Problem refers to
a hypothetical situation in which a group of generals,
each commanding a portion of an army plan to attack a city.
The generals must decide to attack or wait.
Every General must agree on a common decision,
anything less will result in a defeat.
The problem is compounded by the fact that there may be
traitorous generals that do not vote for the best strategy.
Of course, there can be disagreement among the generals.
For example, some would vote for attack,
while others will go for wait.
As you can see, it's not easy to reach consensus.