When we say an asynchronous system achieve fault-tolerance,
we typically mean that,
it has both safety and liveness.
Safety means that, even if the system fails, nothing series happens.
Liveliness means that, the kinds of
the system can eventually receive replies to their requests.
In order for an asynchronous system to provide safety and liveness,
it needs to have a minimum 3f plus one replicas.
Here, f is the maximum number of faulty replicas.
We need 3f plus one replicas,
it must be possible to proceed after communicating with n minus one replicas,
since f replicas might be faulty and not responding.
However, it is possible that the f replicas that did not respond are not faulty,
and therefore f of those that respond, might be faulty.
Even so, there must be enough responses,
that those from non-faulty replicas out number those from faulty ones,
that is, n minus two f is greater than f. Therefore,
n has to be greater than 3f.