So far we have discussed fault tolerance for system services,
but what about attack tolerance for system services?
Can we apply fault tolerance techniques to achieve attack tolerance? The answer is no.
Because in fault tolerance,
we use redundancy which means we use
replicas of a system and all replicas runs the same program.
That means the same attack can compromise all replicas.
Therefore, redundancy is not a solution for attack tolerance.
To achieve attack tolerance,
we need to use diversification.
That is each instance to use
a different implementation and this applies to all layers of the stack.
Which can include network and application protocols,
programming languages, operating systems and so on.
Each instance can use a different security protection mechanism
or apply a security mechanism to different part of the program.
This can achieve efficiency for example
because not all operations are checked all the time.
It can also help us identify the attacks based
on which protection mechanism works and which fails.
Of course, it is very costly to implement and very complex to manage diversification.
We can take the idea of diversification one step further to
use what we call moving target techniques to achieve attack tolerance.
That is, we can dynamically change our network and system configurations.
For example, we can have many instances of the system and network services.
Each instance can have a different implementation,
and these instances can be composed on-the-fly.