We all know the principle of defense in depth.
That is, the first layer of defense is prevention.
The second layer is detection,
and the third layer is about surviving the attack.
The best way to survive an attack is to able to tolerate the attack.
That is, an attack will not be able to render our network or system ineffective.
When we say our network and systems should tolerate an attack,
we mean that our data and our services should tolerate the attacks.
For our data, we want the confidentiality,
integrity, and availability to remain intact.
For our system services,
we want the availability and integrity to remain intact.
Let's first look at how to make our data tolerate an attack.
Typically, data is stored in one place,
for example, a dedicated server.
So, all the attacker needs to do is to compromise that data storage server.
That is, if the attacker can compromise the data storage server,
then the confidentiality, integrity,
and availability of data are all compromised.
Now, what if we replicate the data and store the copies in multiple,
say n different servers,
would this scheme improve security?
That is, would this scheme make our data more tolerant towards attacks?
For confidentiality protection, this is actually a weaker scheme
because the attacker can get data from any of these n servers.
That is, the attacker now has more opportunities.
Whereas, if we use a majority voting scheme,
then integrity and availability are better protected because
now the attacker needs to compromise the majority of these n servers.
So, now the question is, for our data,
can we have a better confidentiality protection?