One approach is by secret sharing.
Cryptographic secret sharing involves,
giving each party a share of a secret,
the secret can only be reconstructed if all parties participate and share their portion.
For example, if the secret is a password.
That is P-A-S-S-W-O-R-D!
we can break the secret into shares,
and give the shares to three different parties.
That is, now each of these three parties has a share of the secret.
Now, I'm going to ask you what's wrong with this scheme, I'll give you a hint.
If the attacker knows the password has nine characters,
how many possible combinations will have to be checked?
What if the attacker doing the guessing,
knew one share of the secret.