Again, in cryptography, a secret sharing scheme
distributes the secret among a group of participants,
so that each of the participant has a share of the secret.
The share can only be reconstructed when the shares are combined together.
Most importantly, individual shares are of no use on their own.
We secure sharing.
We can give a tighter control and remove
any single point of vulnerability with regard to confidentiality.
This is because even if an attacker has compromised an individual
key shareholder he still cannot change or access to data.
And of course we can also improve integrity and
availability by replicating each share among the group.