Now, let's discuss session
management on the web.
What is a session?
A session is a sequence of requests and
responses from a browser to a server.
A server can be long.
Without session management,
a user can be asked to reauthenticate
himself again and again.
So, the goal of session management
is to authenticate user only once.
So that all subsequent requests
are tied to the authenticated user.
So, the general idea behind session
management is to use session tokens.
So, for example, there's the initial
handshake that's in the browser and
the web server.
And then, as the user wants to
access some more secure content,
he may be asked to authenticate himself.
And once the user has been
authenticated, the server can elevate
the token from anonymous browsing
token to a authenticated token.
And when the user logs out or
checks out, this login session
token should be cleared.
There are many ways to
restore the session tokens.
Obviously, we can use browser cookie.
For example, we can create a session
token cookie or session cookie.
The problem with browser
cookie is that a browser
can send a cookie with every request,
even when it's not, and
this gives rise to the cross-site
request forgery attack.
A session token can
be embedded in a URL,
which means that every request
will have the session token.
This means that if the application is
not returned securely, there can be
token leaks via http referer header, or
if the user posts URL in a public forum.
Another option is to store that session
token in a hidden field in a forum.
The downside to this method
is that every user action
must result in a submission of a form,
or you lose the session token.
So, none of these methods are perfect.
The best solution is,
depending on the application,
is you choose a combination
of these three options.
Now, let's discuss
the HTTP referer header.
When a browser sends a URL
request to a server,
if the request contains
a HTTP referer header,
it tells the server the page that you
are coming from, meaning your referer.
Here's an example.
It shows that the user were here.
Again, by checking the referer,
the web server can see where
the request originated.
In the most common situation, this means
that when the user clicks a hyperlink
in the web browser, the browser
sends the request to the server.
The request includes the referer field,
which indicates the last page
the user was on that is.
The one where they click the link.
The problem with referer is that
it can leak the session token
to the previous server.
The solution is that he
can suppress the referer,
means that don't send referer
when you refer to a site.