A major threat in web session
management, is session hijacking.
Here, the attacker waits for
user to log in, and
then the attacker can steal the user
session token and hijacks the session.
And session hijacking is not limited to
active network attacker that intercept
traffic.
For example,
if counter is used a session token,
then when a user logs in a website it
can get a counter value, then he can
view sessions of other users because
he would know other counter values.
Similarly, even if the token is
protected using cryptography,
if the cryptographic algorithm or the
key is weak then a user can still break
the protection, get the counter value,
and then view sessions of other users.
So the point here is that we should use
tokens that are not predictable, and
there are APIs that allow us to
generate random session IDs.
Again, to make session tokens
unpredictable to attacker,
we can use the underlying framework.
For example, rails.
For example, by combining the current
time stamp and random nouns and compute
this values over MD5, that should
give you a very unpredictable token.
Even when a session token is random,
there's still a security
threat of session token theft.
For example, if a web site uses HTTPS
for log in, but subsequently use
HTTP for the rest of the session, then
an active network attacker, for example,
can sit at a wireless cafe and
use a tool, for example, Firesheep
to intercept the clear text HTTP
traffic and steal the session token.
Another way for
the attacker to steal the session token
is to play man in the middle at
the beginning of the SSL connection.
Another approach to steel session token
is to use Cross Site Scripting attacks,
and if the server does not
invalidate a session token
after the user has logged out,
then the stolen token
can still be used by the attacker
even after the user has logged out.
One idea to mitigate session
hijacking is to bind a session token
to the user's computer.
For example, we can embed some machine
specific data in the session ID.
So what machine specific
data of a user can be used?
We begin by binding the session
token to the user's computer.
Now we must decide specifically
what information we should use
as the session token.
We want it to be unguessable and
unique to the machine, but
still quick to generate.
So is using the IP address a good idea?
Probably not and the reason is that the
user's computer changes its IP address.
For example, due to DHCP, then the user
will be locked out of his own session.
What if we used the browser
user information
instead of the IP address
as a session token?
The problem with this approach is that
such information is easily stolen or
guessable by the attacker.
So the conclusion is that,
while it is appealing to use kind
site information a session token,
there's not a good solution when we
consider both security and convenience.
Therefore, the best approach is still
an unpredictable session
token generated by the sever.