A recent trend is that malware authors
are starting to use emulation-based
obfuscation techniques.
And this is an insertion level approach.
And there are several commercial tools
out there and they can be used for
instrument purposes such as
digital rights management.
So how does emulator-based
obfuscation work?
Suppose we have the original malware and
it is for
x86 instruction set architecture.
For example, your Intel based machines.
The malware is then transformed
into Bytecode Program
of an arbitrary language L.
And then, this emulator, based on L,
will emulate this microprogram on x86.
That is the obfuscated malware
Include both the Bytecode Program and
its emulator.
And when the obfuscated
malware runs on x86,
the emulator will emulate this Bytecode
Program and execute the malware logic.
So what are the impact of emulation
based obfuscation on malware analysis?
First of all,
the malware program now is a Bytecode of
arbitrary language L which is not known.
In fact, the language L can
be randomly generated and
since we don't know the language
L we can not perform
pure static analysis on malware
Bytecode program written in L.
We can perform analysis on the Emulator.
The Emulator actually is not specific
to the malware Bytecode program.
It is only specific to the language L.
In face, the malware Bytecode program
is only one of the possible inputs
to the Emulator.
We can perform dynamic analysis
including some of the low code analysis.
We call this greybox methods.
But such analysis is actually
performed on the Emulator,
not the malware code directly.
The reason is that
the executable is the Emulator.
The malware Bytecode is the input.
Therefore, the analysis results
that we get are from the Emulator,
not directly from the malware Bytecode.
Manual reverse-engineering cannot scale,
because
each instance can have a different
language L, and a different Emulator.
Since the process of creating such
confiscated malware is automated.
We also needed an automated approach
to reverse engineer these Emulators.
By this, we mean that we should not
require knowledge of the language L.
And our approach should be
general enough that will work
on a large class of Emulators.
But is an automated approach possible?
In theory, it is not.
On the other hand, most of the Emulators
have a fetch-decode-execute behavior
that can be identified at runtime and
then can be the starting point
of our reverse engineering.