Since the malware contents
are encrypted, and
look random, a signature-based
approach would not work.
Therefore, the first statement is true.
And, since the malware contents
are encrypted, and look different,
there's no single signature
that matches all the instances.
So, the second statement is false.
Of course, we need to include code that
decrypts the malware in runtime so
that the malware can execute.
Therefore, the first statement is true.
Know that we can simply use
the code that the compressed or
the encrypted malware as a signature
because legitimate programs
can contain such instructions, for
example for digital rights management.