Now let's discuss malware analysis.
What are the benefits
of malware analysis?
If we understand malware's
network behaviors,
we can create rules to detect and
block malware traffic.
If we understand malware's
on-host behaviors,
we can repair the compromised hosts.
If we have knowledge of the malware's
support infrastructure on the internet
and it's evolution history, we can also
analyze it's trend and threat scope.
Such as, how widespread the malware
is and the likely next target, etc.
Of course, the attackers try to
defeat malware analysis, and
are using the most sophisticated
techniques available.
Another challenge in malware analysis is
the volume of malware is really huge.
Available and
automated tools made a job of creating
malware obfuscated of course very easy.
And in fact there are hundreds of
thousands of new samples every day.
Since the malware creation process is
already automated it is imperative that
malware analysis has to be automated
as well In addition to automation,
malware analysis also
needs to be transparent so
that the malware does not
know it is being analyzed.
Otherwise the malware may refuse to run,
or
purposely alter to its
behaviors to fool the analysis.
This is the so-called malware
uncertainty principle, but
this is very challenging.
In physics, the Heisenberg
principle says that an observer
will inevitably affect
the observed environment.
In malware analysis, our tools may be so
invasive that the malware can
detect them if we're not careful.
In malware analysis, our tools and
techniques are often invasive.
And if we are not careful,
the malware can detect a presence
of the analyzer and refuse to run.
In fact, malware authors already
tried to actively detect
malware analysis tools.
In the malware creation tool kits,
there are standard point and
click options to add logics to detect
various malware analysis methods,
such as these examples.
So we need malware analysis
to be transparent to malware.
That is, malware should not be able
to detect that it is being analyzed.
But how do we fulfill such
transparency requirements?
A malware analyzer should be at a higher
privilege level than a malware, so
that the malware can not directly
access, or know about, the analyzer.
In addition,
the malware may use operations to try
to find the presence of the analyzer.
For example, it may try to find
a side effect of analysis.
These operations should be privileged,
so
that the malware cannot
directly get the answers back.
And, since the analyzer is
at a higher privilege level,
it can actually lie the answers
back to the malware.
That is,
the malware gets the wrong answer and
doesn't know about the side effects.
And obviously, the malware should
get the same correct result
of instruction execution as if
the analyzer is not present.
Likewise, the malware should
see identical signals and
instruction handlings,
as well as time durations.
In terms of fulfilling
the transparency requirements
most interesting tools fall short.
For example, even analyzer
is in guest this means that
the analyzer runs on a same machine and
has the same privilege as the malware
then the analyzer does
not have high privilege.
Some of the analysis study
facts can be discovered but
a malware without privilege operations.
And the exceptions trapped by
the analyzer may be discovered
by the malware.
If the analyzer runs
in a virtual machine
that's based on software
virtualization such as VMWare
then there could be side
effects that can be discovered.
But a malware without
privileged operations.
If the analyzer runs in emulation
environment such as QEMU
the execution semantics of instructions
maybe different from real hardware.
Emulation based malware analysis
tools are the most widely used.
But they have major shortcomings.
The main issue here is that
this emulation emirames
do not fully emulate the hardware.
There is that a corner cases
where a set of instructions
give different results on emulation
emirames versus hardware.
And there have been attacks
based on these corner cases
to detect emulation emirames.
But the bigger problem is that
there is no way to eliminate
all these corner cases.
In fact, in theory there's no way to
guarantee the absence of such attacks.
And the reason is the so-called
EQTM is not decidable.
Which means that when
you view an emulator,
you cannot determine that it behaves
exactly the same as the real machine.
In other words,
you cannot rule out the possibility that
there are situations that your emulator
and the real machine behave differently.
Here's a simple example of
the discrepancies between emulator and
real hardware.
That is, the real hardware will give
an illegal instruction exception, but
an emulator will happily
execute the instruction.