Toolchain attack is one
approach to produce malware.
Here's a real example,
an official distribution of Xcode
was compromised with malware.
If a developer used this infected
Xcode library to develop an app,
the app will be infected.
The infected app will then collect
information on devices and
upload the data to a C&C server.
This attack is very potent,
because any app
that is compiled using this Xcode
library now becomes a malicious app.
This XcodeGhost was able
to infect many apps,
including 39 apps published in
the official iOS App Store.
Attacking the App Store review process
is one approach to distribute malware.
Here's an example.
We created the Jekyll app in 2013,
we planted vulnerability in this app,
this vulnerabilities can be exploited
at run time with a particular input.
Once the vulnerabilities is exploited
the Jekyll app can activate new
addition execution path through
Return-Oriented Programming.
And then the app can send SMS,
email, tweet, and so on.
On the other hand the App Store review
process cannot find these malicious
paths, because they cannot review
without a correct input and runtime.
To illustrate, the App Store review
process finds that the control flow of
the app to be safe, that is all
the exclusion paths are acceptable.
On the other hand a run time
minimal ability planted
in the code is exploited,
because of the specific input
that a new control flows that were not
observable in the app view process.
These new control flows allow the Jekyll
app to do evil and make profit.
For example,
it can do a number of activities.
These can be achieved by calling private
APIs that are not directly accessible to
legitimate apps.
But a Jekyll app knows
the memory layout and
hence the addresses of these APIs and
can directly jump to them.