Let's discuss a few approaches
to mobile malware detection.
Please check the instructors notes for
links to these papers.
Kirin is a very simple
system that looks for
suspicious combination of permissions.
RiskRanker use heuristics such as
cryptos that relates to unpacking code.
Similarly, DroidRanger
use heuristics such as
loading native code from
suspicious websites.
DREBEN uses a machine learning algorithm
called SVM, or Support Vector Machine.
And the data attributes used for
modeling include permissions,
API calls, and so on.
Many malicious apps are actually
repackaged version of legitimate apps.
This is actually the most effective
way to distribute malware,
because a popular or cool app
already has a large number of users.
There are research systems
on clone detection.
Here are a few examples.
For example, DroidMOSS use fuzzy
hashing of Java methods to match and
detect clone code.
DNADroid performs similarity
analysis on PDGs.
PDGs are program dependency
graphs between methods.
There are a few sandboxes for
mobile malware analysis.
And these sandboxes
enable dynamic analysis.
Here are a few example sandboxes.
Many dynamic analysis and detection
tools use system call information.
Here are a few examples.
For example, PREC stands for
particle root explore containment.
It can dynamically identify system calls
from high risk components, for example,
third party native libraries.
And execute those system calls
within isolated threads.
Therefore, PREC can detect and
stop root exploits with high accuracy,
while imposing very low interference
to benign applications.