Information leakage is a big concern,
and
apps that leak sensitive information can
often be considered malware even though
many think that they are in a gray area.
There are several approaches to
detect leakage, for example,
PiOS performs static analysis
to detect information leakage.
TaintDroid uses taint tracking to
perform information flow analysis.
That is,
it analyzes how data from a source,
such as address book, flows to the sync,
such as the internet.
Another approach is to check if an app
does what it promises to do, for
example, WhyPer compares the app's
permissions against its description.
And the analysis is based on natural
language processing techniques.