One of the most important
analysis is data flow analysis.
Here's an example of data flow,
the source is location data and
the sink is SMS or
website on the internet.
Data flow analysis can
be useful malware or
greyware analysis to find out
what information is being stolen.
And based on the discoveries, we can
improve enterprise specific policies.
Data flow analysis can be used
to check the external app
to make sure that there's
no API abuse or data theft.
Data flows gathered from an app
can be used to inform users
about potential privacy implications.
Data flow analysis can also be used to
discover abilities in applications.
For example,
accepting data from untrusted sources.
However, analyzing data flows
is a very challenging task.
For example, Android has more than three
million lines of very complex code.
Performing data analysis on whole
system would take a long time, and
it's not practical.
And of course to be useful,
data flow analysis has to be accurate.
As we have just discussed,
analyzing a app in a context
of full Android is very expensive
because there is too much code involved.
The STAMP approach is to abstract
the Android stack into models.
And these models include
the following information.
We are going to focus on data flows.