There are more than 30 types of sources.
Here are some examples.
There are more than ten types of sinks,
and here are some examples.
Each pair of source and
sink is a flow type,
and there are close to 400 flow types.
Here's an example of data flow
analysis on the Facebook app.
The description of the app says that it
allows the user to synchronize contacts.
And it says that Facebook does not allow
the export of phone numbers or emails.
And the users can plug one or
all apps but there's no privacy policy.
Here are the possible flows.
On the left, we have the sources.
On the right, we have the sinks.
That is potentially all resources
can go to all the sinks.
>From the Facebook description,
we expect to see the state of flow for
sinking contacts.
However, the data flows
observed from the Facebook app
include additional flows
that lead to leakage.