Some apps may appear to be
providing useful functions but
they secretly still uses
confidential information.
These apps are considered malware.
Here's an example of such malicious
apps and it was taken off the app store.
But malicious apps may still
get on victims devices
even after it is taken
off the app store.
One technique is to exploit the design
floor in Apple's DRM scheme.
Apple allows users to purchase and
download iOS apps from their app store
through the iTunes client
running on their computers.
They can then use their computers to
install the apps onto their iOS devices.
The iOS devices will request
an authorization code for
each app installed to prove
the app was actually purchased.
In a FairPlay man in the middle attack,
attackers purchase an app
from the app store, then intercept and
save the authorization code.
They then develop a program that
simulates the iTunes software, and
installs the software
on a victim's computer.
And this fake iTunes software
can check the victim's
iOS devices to believe the app
was purchased by the victim.
Therefor the user can install apps
they never actually paid for, and
the attacker can install malicious
apps without the user's knowledge.
This attack continues to work even
after the malicious app is removed
from the app store.