Now let's take a look at the network
protocols to understand why the internet
is vulnerable to DoS service attacks.
So the internet protocol or
IP is connectionless.
This means that it is not reliable,
meaning that each packet will find it's
way to destination and there is no
mechanism to ensure that all packets
will arrive properly and in sequence
at least not at IP layer essentially
it is the best effort delivery.
So here is the format of the IP header
for the purpose of our discussion
let's focus on a source IP address and
a destination IP address.
>From the security point of
view the main weakness of IP
is that there is no authentication
of the source IP address.
Which means that the attacker
can spoof an IP source address.
Now let's take a look at TCP.
TCP is session based which
means the destination is going
to make sure that all packets belonging
to a same connection will arrive and
properly sequence.
And in order to achieve this
there's congestion control and
in order delivery mechanisms.
These mechanisms ensure
that the data loss or
packet loss is minimized and the need to
retransmit packets is also minimized.
And here's the format of the TCP header.
Notice that we use a sequence number for
each packet.
Acknowledgement number to
acknowledge a packet as received.
And number flags to actually
keep the state of the session.
Now let's take a look
at TCP handshake or
the steps to establish a TCP connection.
Suppose our client wants
to connect to a server.
It first sends a SYN packet,
this packet has a SYN flag set and
also a sequence number.
The acknowledgement number is 0
because this is the first packet.
The server responds
with a SYN/ACK packet,
which means that both the SYN flap and
the ACK flags are set.
The sequence number is
a server sequence number and
acknowledgment number is
the sequence number plus one.
This means that this SYN/ACK
packet is an acknowledgement
of the initial SYN
packet from the client.
And then the client sends a final
ACK packet to the server.
In this ACK packet, it incremented
its Its own sequence number and
acknowledge the sequence
number from the server.
This tells the server that the client
has received this SYN/ACK packet.
At this point,
the TCP connection is established.