With that background,
let's discuss how TCP SYN flood or
denial of service attack can work.
Notice that, in TCP handshake,
after the server receives a SYN packet
from the client, it sends a SYN/ACK
packet back to the client, and
then waits for
the ACK packet from the client.
When it received the ACK packet,
it knows that the connection
is established.
Therefore, the server needs to keep in
memory the state of the connection,
meaning that it's waiting for the ACK
packet that matched the SYN/ACK packet,
which matched the initial
SYN packet from client.
So SYN flood exploits the fact that
server needs to keep in memory such
state information.
In particular, the attacker can send
a lot of SYN packets to the server,
and the source IP address is spoofed to
some random target source IP address.
The result is that the SYN/ACK packet
will be sent to the spoofed or
the target address.
Since the source IP address of these
SYN packets are randomly generated and
spoofed, the SYN/ACK
packets may get lost,
meaning that the ACK packet
may never arrive at a server.
The result is that the server's
memory gets filled up,
because the server needs to keep track
of the SYN/ACK packets and wait for
the ACK packet from the clients.
And since many of these
ACK packets do not arrive,
the server is holding in
memory this state information.
And as a result,
its buffer gets filled up.
And when that happens,
no further connections can be serviced.
In other words,
the denial of service is accomplished.
Here's a real example of SYN flood.
The Blaster worm in 2003
infected many machines.
And these infected machines were
insructed to launch a denial of service
attack at noon on August 16th.
That is, these machines were instructed
to launch SYN flood on port 80
on the target server windowsupdate.com.
In particular,
50 SYN requests were sent every second.
And each packet is 40 bytes.
And the source IP address of these
request packets were randomly generated.
As a result,
the server windowsupdate.com
was rendered unavailable.
As a response, Microsoft moved the
Windows update service to a new domain,
windowsupdate.microsoft.com.
So how do we defend
against SYN flood attacks?
How about increase the memory size or
decrease the timeout value so that
when a server does not receive an ACK
packet, it just clears out the memory.
These are not good solutions, because an
attacker can just send more packets or
at a faster pace.
A better solution is to remove
the need for a server to keep state.
And this, of course, comes with a cost.