SYN flood attacks can be
launched at a massive scale.
Typically, for
distributed denial of service attack,
a large botnet can be used to
generate a huge amount of traffic.
And the result is that the website, or
even its uplink network routers,
can be saturated.
It is very hard to filter
these SYN packets,
because they all look legitimate.
So how do we defend against
such massive flooding attack?
One idea is to use
a very powerful server,
or a group of servers,
to protect a website.
The idea is that these
intermediate servers
will only forward established TCP
connections to the real website.
Suppose many machines or bots send
a lot of requests to the website, but
they're intercepted by the proxy.
The proxy is very powerful
because it can use many servers.
And they can be distributed
across the Internet.
The proxy sends the SYN/ACK packets in
response to the initial SYN packets.
When a proxy receives the ACK
packets from the client,
it will then forward
to the real website.
The idea here is that
the attacking machine or
the bot will not send actual
ACK packets to the proxy.
Only the legitimate clients will send
the ACK packets to the proxy, and
only those will be forwarded
to the website to be serviced.
In other words, the proxy here
stops the flooding attack.
However, the idea of using a proxy to
protect a website is not bulletproof.
Here's an example of a stronger attack.
An attacker can use an army of bots
to actually completely
finish the TCP handshake.
In other words,
use complete TCP connections to website.
Then it can send requests
to the website and
keep repeating all these
requests to the server.
That is, all of these requests
are legitimate from a protocol
point of view, but they were designed to
overload the server with a lot of work.
And the result is that if the attacker
can command a huge army of bots,
the attacker can still
bring down a website.
This is similar to the situation
when there are huge number of
legitimate users visiting
a website at the same time.
Of course, such attack can actually
render the proxy protection useless, but
on the other hand, because the TCP
connection is fully established,
that means the attacker cannot
use any random source IP address.
The attacker must use the real
IP address of the bots,
which means that the bots' IP
addresses are now revealed.
And then a proxy can actually block or
rate limit traffic from these bots.
In other words, after the initial
attack, there's a chance that the proxy
can actually use the information
to rate-limit and
then reduce the effect
of the flooding attack.
Here's a real-world example of such
an attack, it's fairly recent.
So here, a honest end user
visits a popular website, but
this website is compromised and
the response will include a miniature
JavaScript injected into the response.
And the user has no idea
that this JavaScript
is embedded into the response HTML page.
For example, this JavaScript can be
embedded in an invisible iframe.
Once the response HTML page
runs on the user's browser,
the malicious JavaScript will run, and
it will do a denial of service
attack on a server, say, Github.com.
Here's how the JavaScript can
launch an attack on Github.com.
It basically asks the victim website,
say, GitHub.com,
to fetch a random resource on a server.
And it sends such a request
every ten milliseconds.
Therefore, with many users unknowingly
running this malicious JavaScript,
the victim website, say Github.com,
can be rendered unavailable.