The Internet routing protocol
can also be exploited to
launch in our service attacks.
In particular,
there have been several incidents of
route hijacking that resulted
in denial of service.
Here's one example involving
Pakistan and YouTube.
The Internet is divided into a large
number of so-called autonomous systems.
Each autonomous system or
AS is responsible for
logging packets in and out a subset of
the Internet defined by the prefix.
For example, the YouTube service
address is within this prefix.
It is actually 208.65.103.238.
In February 2008, Pakistan Telecom
advertise that, is actually
responsible for subset of Internet
defined by this particular prefix.
And this prefix is more specific
than a segment that includes
the YouTube server.
And since the routing positions for
a specific IP address,
such as the YouTube server
use the more specific prefix.
Then the whole Internet thought that
Pakistan Telecom is responsible for
routing traffic to YouTube.
The result of this
route hijacking is that
all traffic to YouTube was
instantly routed to Pakistan.
As you can see,
the traffic volume at the YouTube server
jumped to zero until the route
hijacking mistake was corrected.
In a more recent example,
China Telecom published
BGP routes that caused .mail and
.gov to route through China Telecom.