So far, we have discussed denial
service attacks that exploit
weaknesses in network protocols.
Denial service attack can also
happen at a higher level.
For example, let's look at
a typical handshake protocol.
Here's a protocol that use
publicly based authentication.
So the client sends a hello
message to the server, and
a server sends its public
key to the client.
And then, the client will use that
public key to perform key exchange.
For example, the client can generate
a secret share key between a client and
a server, and encrypt that
using the server's public key.
And when a server receives
this encrypted key,
it will use its private key to decrypt,
to extract this secret share key.
The point is the client encrypts
the secret share key using the server's
public key, and then the server
decrypts that using its private key.
It's all good from
a crypto point of view.
However, RSA Decrypt is ten times
more costly than RSA Encrypt,
since the server has to do so
much more work.
The attacker can send many such
handshake requests to the server
to bring it down.
Similarly, at the application
level a client
can send a simple HTTP request to your
server asking for a very large PDF file.
And obviously, the server needs to spend
far more resources than the client.
Therefore, an attacker can send many
such HTTP requests to your server,
causing the server to fetch a large
number of very large PDF files, and
this will actually bring
down the web server.