So how do we mitigate such
denial of service attacks.
One solution is to use client puzzles.
The main idea is to
slow down the attacker.
For example, we can ask
the client to solve a problem.
For example, the server can
challenge C to the client and
ask the client to find or
compute X such that the n needs
significant bits of
the SHA-1 hash are all 0s.
The assumption here is that it would
take the client 2 to the n time to solve
this challenge.
For n=16, it would take 0.3
seconds on a 1 gigahertz machine.
And of course, the client needs to
present X back to the servers, and
it is very easy for server to check
that the solution is correct.
This is because the server
needs to only compute hash
1 whereas the client is to
compute to the n times.
During a denial of
service attack everyone,
that is including legitimate clients or
possible attackers,
everyone must submit puzzle
solution to the server.
And of course, when there's no attack,
no one needs to solve the puzzle.
Here are some examples of how
client puzzles can be deployed.
For TCP connection flooding,
the challenge C can be the TCP's
server sequence number, and
the first data packet from the client
must contain the puzzle solution.
Otherwise the server will
terminate the TCP connection.
For SSL handshake denial
of service attack,
the challenge C can be
based on a TLS session ID.
And the server will check the puzzle
solution before even attempting to do
RSA decrypt,
because RSA decrypt is very expensive.
And similar ideas can be
applied to application layer
denial of service attacks.
One advantage of the client puzzle is
that the hardness of the challenge, or
in particular, n, can be decided
based on the DoS attack volume.
For example, if the volume is high,
you can set n to be higher so
that it takes more time for
the client to find a solution.
In other words, this will reduce
the volume of traffic to the server.
The limitation is that this requires
changes to both the client code and
the server code.
It also hurts legitimate clients,
in particular,
clients that use low power computing
devices such as cellphones.
Another variant of client puzzle
is to use memory-bound functions.
This is because CPU-bound functions such
as the one we just discussed, cannot
be scaled to very hard puzzles for
low end machines such as cell phones.
Whereas memory-bound functions
can be easily scaled, even for
low-end machines.
There are several proposals to use
memory-bound functions as puzzles.
You are encouraged to
study these papers.