Let's discuss another
mitigation technique.
You may be already familiar with this.
It is called CAPTCHA, which stands for
Completely Automated Public Turing test
to tell Computers and Humans Apart.
The idea is that the server should
verify that the connection is from
a human instead of, for example,
from a bot or a malware.
So I'm sure many of you
are familiar with this.
The idea is that only human
can interpret this figure and
then type in the actual words.
During a denial of service attack,
the server can generate CAPTCHAs and
process request only if the client
presents the actual valid solution
to the CAPTCHA challenge.
Because that will prove that there's
actual human behind the request.