Another important mitigation
is source identification.
The goal is to identify
the source of attack packets so
that ultimately we can block
the attack at each source.
You may think that this problem
should be easy because, for example,
we discussed that many of the packets
involved a denial of service attacks,
they have spoof or
random source IP addresses.
So the question is, why don't we
just ask the ISPs to filter out
source IP addresses that are not
legitimate or valid for the ISP?
For example,
if the router expects that all traffic
is from this particular prefix, then
it can drop all packets with a source
IP address other than from this prefix.
That way smooth packets can be dropped.
The biggest problem for this proposal is
that it requires all ISPs to do this.
Because, as we will show, if only 10%
of ISPs do not implement, then there's
actually no defense against denial
of service for the whole Internet.
Then the problem becomes that
every ISP is waiting for
everyone else to implement this first.
As we have shown in
the previous example,
if only 3 ISPs do not
implement ingress filtering,
the attackers can already launch
a big denial of service attack.
As of 2014,
a quarter of the autonomous systems
are mostly ISPs or big enterprises.
They do not implement ingress filtering.
In total, that means 13% of
the IP addresses can be spoofed.