So now, let's go into the detail
of the traceback mechanism.
The main component is
the edge sampling algorithm.
An edge includes the start and
end IP addresses.
It also includes distance,
which is the number of hops
since the last edge stored.
Here's the procedure for
a router to decide how to
record the edge information.
When a packet arrives, it throws a coin.
If it's heads, then it will write its
address into the start address and
then write 0 into the distance field.
If it's tail, then if distance is 0,
then it writes its IP address
into the end address field.
And regardless,
it will increment the distance field.
So here's an example.
Again, a packet would
include edge information,
which includes the start address,
end address, and distance.
Suppose the packet travels through
three routers, R1, R2, and R3.
R1 tosses a coin and it's head.
So R1 writes its address to
the start field and 0 in distance.
Now R2, it tosses a coin and it's tail.
The distance was 0.
So according to the process,
it should write itself to the end and
then increment distance to 1.
Now for R3, it tosses the coin and
it's tail again.
But the distance was not 0.
So it does not write itself to the end.
It simply increment the distance.
Now it's 2.
Now, for R3, it tosses a coin,
it's tail again,
and the distance is greater than 0, so
it does not write itself to the end.
It simply increment
the distance from 1 to 2.
Now, as you can see, the edge
information includes the starting of
the edge, which is R1, the end,
which is R2, the distance is 2.
That means from R3's perspective,
the distance is 2 since
the beginning of the edge.
With the edge information,
now we can talk about how
do we reconstruct the path.
The package arrive at the victim
contains edge information.
And this information can be extracted
to reconstruct the path that started
from the victim all the way to
the source of the attack packets.
Again, the edge information
contains the starting router and
the end router of the edge and
the distance from the starting router.
And the number of packets needed to
reconstruct the path is given by this
formula.
This is the expected number of packets.
And p is the probability of head versus
tail, and d is the length of the path.