Let's discuss a more recent type
of denial-of-service attack called
reflector attack.
So here, the attacker spoofed
the victim's source IP address and
sends DNS query to many DNS servers.
And all DNS servers will
respond to this query and
send their response to
the victim machine.
And, of course, the result is
that the victim is flooded.
In addition to DNS example,
there are other examples that use
web servers and Gnutella servers.
A reflector attack is typically
launched by a bot master.
Commanding many bots, each of them
will send a lot of requests to many
reflectors, such as DNS servers,
web servers and the Gnutella servers.
And these requests will spoof
the victim IP address and
as a result, the reflectors will
send the response to the victim.
Since the actual flooding traffic is
from the reflectors to the victim,
a traceback scheme will trace the attack
packets back to the reflectors.
And the reflectors may not do any
marking or keep any state, so
there's no traceback from the reflector
back to the bots or bot master.