Now let's discuss network denial of
service attack in some more details.
The goal of network denial of service
attack is to take out a large site
such as a web server with as little
computing power as possible.
So how is network denial
of service accomplished?
One of the main approaches
is amplification.
This means that the attacker only needs
to send a small number of packets and
can achieve a big effect such as
rendering the targeted site unavailable.
There are two types of
amplification attacks.
The first type is to exploit a bug or
vulnerability on the server.
For example, if there's a design flaw or
implementation error on the server code,
then the attacker machine
can send a few packets that
contain input that would trigger
the bug and then crash the server.
And of course,
when the server program is crashed,
then the server become unavailable.
Another type of denial of service
attack is to send a flood of packets.
For example,
an attacker can use a large botnet to
send a lot of requests to the server.
Network denial of service attack
can happen at any network layer.
As a quick review, there are multiple
layers in a network stack.
For example, denial of service
attack can happen at the link layer.
This means that the attacker
simply sends a lot of traffic
to saturate the link.
Denial of service attack can happen at
a TCP/UDP layer or the transport layer.
For example,
the server needs to use memory to
hold the state of TCP connections, so
the attacker can send a lot of TCP
packets to exhaust the server's memory.
Denial of service attack can also
happen at the application layer.
For example, the attacker can
request the server application
to fetch a large amount of data.
And if there are many such requests, the
server's resources will be exhausted.
The sad truth is that
the current Internet design
cannot handle distributed
denial of service attacks.