Now let's go over an application
example and then do a quiz.
One example of attacks is to use
the NTP, Network Time Protocol.
This protocol is used to
synchronize machines to the clocks.
For example on a Mac, the day and time
are set by an NTP server run by Apple.
When a computer request
the time from the NTP server,
the server responds with
the correct time and date.
In NTP, the data volume of
the request from a machine
is much smaller than
the response from the server.
Now you can imagine how NTP can be
used for the now service attack.
So with that background,
let's do a quiz.
Which of these are reasons why
the UDP-based NTP protocol
is particularly vulnerable
to amplification attacks?