Now let's start with very simple cryptocurrencies.
GoofyCoin is about the simplest cryptocurrency we can imagine.
There are just two rules of GoofyCoin.
The first rule is that Goofy can create new coins anytime he
wants and the second rule is that the newly created coins belong to Goofy.
To create a coin, Goofy generates a uniqueCoinID,
that is, ID that he's never used before.
Then he construct a string, CreateCoin[uniqueCoinID].
He then computes the digital signature of the string using his private signing key.
He then computes the signature on this string using his private signing key.
The string, together with his signature is a coin.
Anyone can verify that the coin contains
Goofy's valid signature of a CreateCoin statement and is therefore a valid coin.
Another rule of GoofyCoin is that whoever
owns a coin can transfer the coin to someone else.
Transferring a coin is not simply a matter
of sending a coin data structure to the recipient,
it is done using cryptographic operations.
Let's say Goofy wants to transfer a coin that he equated to Alice.
To do this, he creates a new statement that says "Pay this to Alice" where this
is a hash pointer that references the coin that
he created and that he wants to transfer to Alice.
As we discussed earlier,
identities are just public keys and therefore
Alice here is really the public key of Alice.
Goofy also signs the statement because he owns the coin and
therefore he has to sign any transaction that spends the coin.
Let's say Goofy wants to transfer a coin that he created to Alice.
To do this, he creates a new statement that says,
"Pay this to Alice" where this is hash a pointer that
references the coin that he created and then he wants to transfer to Alice.
As we have discussed earlier,
identities are just public keys and therefore
Alice here is represented by the public key of Alice.
Goofy also signs the string that represents this transfer statement.
That is, since Goofy is the original owner of the coin,
he has a sign any transaction that spends the coin.
Once this data structure in particular with Goofy signature is created,
Alice now owns the coin.
She can prove to anyone that she owns the coin because
she can present the data structure with Goofy's valid signature.
In particular, this data structure contains not only the statement signed by Goofy,
it also points to a very coin that was owned by Goofy.
Therefore, anyone can verify that this transfer is
valid and that Alice is now the new owner of the coin.
Once Alice owns the coin,
she can spend it in turn.
To do this, she creates a statement that says,
"Pay this to Bob's public key" where this is
a hash pointer to the coin that was owned by her and of course,
she signs the statement.
Now Bob owns the coin and anyone can verify that Bob is really the new owner.
That is, anyone can follow the chain of hash pointers
to the coin's creation and verify that at each step,
the rightful owner signed a statement that says,
"Pay this coin to a new owner".