Let's say Alice pass a coin to Bob by sending her a sign statement to Bob,
but didn't tell anyone else.
She could create another sign statement that pays the very same coin to Chuck.
To Chuck, this would appear to be a perfectly valid transaction,
and now he thinks he's the owner of the coin.
Bob and Chuck would both have valid-looking claims to be the owner of this coin.
This is called a double spending attack.
That is, Alice is spending the same coin twice.
Intuitively, we know coins are not supposed to work this way.
In fact, double spending attacks are one of
the key problems to any cryptocurrency has to solve.
GoofyCoin does not solve the double spending attack,
and therefore, it is not secure.
GoofyCoin is simple, and its mechanism for transferring coins is very similar to Bitcoin.
But because it is insecure,
it is not a cryptocurrency.