To solve the double spending problem,
we will design another cryptocurrency,
which we will call Scrooge Coin.
Scrooge Coin is build of Goofy Coin,
but it is more complicated in terms of data structures.
The first key idea is that a designated entity called Scrooge,
publishes an append-only ledger that contains,
the history of all the transactions that have happened.
The append-only property ensures that
any data written to this ledger will remain forever.
If the ledger is truly append-only,
we can use it to defend against double-spending by requiring
that all transactions to be written to the larger before they accepted.
That way, it will be visible to anyone
if coins were previously sent to a different owner.
To implement this append-only feature,
Scrooge can be a blockchain that he will sign.
This blockchain is a series of data blocks.
Each with one transaction or multiple transactions,
each block contains the IDs of the transactions,
the contents of the transactions,
and a hash pointer to the previous block.
Scrooge signs a final hash pointer,
which binds all the data in
the entire blockchain and then publishes the signature along with the blockchain.
In Scrooge Coin, a transaction is only
valid if it is in the blockchain signed by Scrooge.
Anybody can verify that a transaction was endorsed by Scrooge,
by checking Scrooge's signature on the block that it appears in.
Scrooge makes sure that it doesn't endorse
a transaction that harm suitable span on already spent coin.
Why do we need a blockchain with
hash pointers in addition to having Scrooge sign each block?
This ensure the append-only property.
If Scrooge tries to add or remove
a transaction to the history or change an existing transaction,
it will affect all of the following blocks because of the hash pointers.
That is, as soon as someone is monitoring the latest hash pointer published by Scrooge,
the change will be obvious and easy to catch.
In a system where Scrooge sign blocks individually,
you will have to keep track of every single signature Scrooge ever issued.
A broad chain makes it easy for any two individuals to verify that they
have observed the exactly same history of transactions signed by Scrooge.