In Scrooge coin, there are two kinds of transactions: the first kind is CreateCoins.
In this example, a CreateCoins transaction creates multiple coins.
Each coin has a serial number within a transaction number.
Each transaction has an ID,
and each coin has a serial number within a transaction.
Each coin has a value,
meaning it's worth a certain number of Scrooge coins and also recipient,
which is the recipient's public key.
In this example, a CreateCoins transaction creates multiple coins.
A transaction has a transaction ID.
Each coin has a serial number within a transaction.
Each coin has a value, that is,
it's worth a certain number of Scrooge coins,
and each coin has a recipient,
which is the public key of the recipient.
A Scrooge coin transaction is always valid by definition if it is signed by Scrooge.
The second kind of transaction is called PayCoins.
It consumes some coins, that is,
destroy them and creates new coins of the same total value.
The new coins might belong to different people,
that is, different public keys.
This transaction has to be signed by everyone who's paying in a coin,
that is, if you're the owner of one of the coins,
there's going to be consumed in this transaction,
then you have to sign this transaction to say that
you're really okay with spending this coin.
The rules of Scrooge coin say that
a PayCoins transaction is valid if four things are true.
First, the consumed coins are valid.
They really were created in previous transactions.
Second, the consumed coins were not already consumed in some previous transaction,
that is, this is not a double-spending.
Third, the total value of the coins that come out of
this transaction is equal to the total value of the coins that went in,
that is, only Scrooge can create new value.
Forth, the transaction is correctly signed by owners of all the consumed coins.
If all of these conditions are met,
then this PayCoins transaction is valid and Scrooge will accept it.
He'll write it into the history by appending it to the blockchain,
after which everyone can see that this transaction has happened.
It is only at this point that the participants can
accept that this transaction has actually occurred.