Now we come to the core problem with ScroogeCoin.
ScroogeCoin will work in a sense that people can see which coins are valid.
It prevents double spending because everyone can look into the blockchain and see
that all the transactions are valid and that every coin is consumed only once.
But the problem is that Scrooge has too much influence.
He cannot create fake transactions because he cannot afford other people's signatures.
But Scrooge could stop endorsing transactions for
some users denying their service and making their coins unspendable,
or Scrooge can be greedy and he could
refuse to publish transactions unless he gets a fee.
Scrooge can of course create as many new coins for himself as he wants.
The problem here is centralization.
Although Scrooge is happy with the system,
the users might not be.
Cryptocurrencies with a central authority have largely failed to take off and
the main reason is that it is difficult for people to
accept a cryptocurrency with a centralized authority.
Therefore, a key technical challenge is that can we
create a cryptocurrency without a central authority.
To do this, we must figure out how we can agree upon
a single published blockchain with history of all the transactions.
The users must all agree which transactions are
valid and which transactions have actually occurred.
They also need to be able to assign IDs to things in a decentralized way.
Finally, the mining of new coins needs to be controlled in a decentralized way.
If we can solve all of these problems,
then we can build a currency that will be like
ScroogeCoin but without a centralized authority.
In fact, this will be a system very much like Bitcoin.