First, provide a globally accessible blockchain through the use of nanosatellites.
This is Spacebit.
Second, a social networking platform that uses
cryptocurrency to members that view ads in the app.
Popular in Uzbekistan.
This is GetGems.
Third, a decentralized peer-to-peer digital currency.
The community is friendly and vibrant,
and known for charitable acts such as sending
the 2014 Jamaican bobsled team to the Olympics.
This is Dogecoin.
Fourth, according to a published white paper,
it used new variations on the blockchain that would
result in new breed of cryptocurrency. That's Paycoin.
Fifth, the largest crowdfund in history.
An attacker exploited a vulnerability in its smart contract
with losses totaling $50 million. This is DAO.
This quiz highlights some important points about cryptocurrency.
There is a strong market for it,
but it is also a volatile field,
and it is not an easy problem to solve.
To further muddy the water,
at the end of 2016,
there was talk of cryptocurrencies disappearing altogether.