Since there's no centralized authority in Bitcoin,
it is very important for us to understand how we can achieve distributed consensus.
In Bitcoin, there's no centralized authority and therefore
we need to understand how we can achieve distributed consensus.
There are two basic requirements for distributed consensus.
First, the consensus protocol terminates when all correct nodes decide on a same value,
and the value must have been proposed by some correct node.
There has been a lot of research on distributed consensus.
Now let's look at a unique setting of Bitcoin.
First, Bitcoin is a peer-to-peer system.
When Alice wants to pay Bob,
she simply broadcasts a transaction to all Bitcoin nodes.
In fact, Alice doesn't know where Bob's computer
really is and the computer may not be online.
Achieving consensus in a peer-to-peer system is very hard because some nodes may crash,
some nodes may be malicious,
the network is not perfect because not all pairs of
nodes are connected and there are network faults and latency.
Now let's discuss how we can achieve consensus in Bitcoin.
The trick is to use incentive and this is
possible only because Bitcoin is a currency and we embrace
randomness or the imperfect nature of the peer to peer network by
doing away with the exact termination point of the consensus protocol.
The protocol is that achieves consensus over a long timescale,
for example, in about an hour.
The key idea here is implicit consensus.
At each round a random node is picked,
this node then proposes the next block in the block chain.
Other nodes implicitly accept or reject this block.
If they accept they will extend the block chain from this block.
If they reject they will ignore this block and
instead extend the block chain from an earlier block.
Every block here contains not only the transactions,
but also a hash pointer to the block that it extends.
Here is a high level discussion of the consensus algorithm.
First, new transactions are broadcast to all nodes,
each node collects new transactions into a block,
at each round a random node gets a chance to broadcast its block.
Other nodes would accept this block if all of the transactions in it are valid,
that is the signatures are valid and it is not double spend.
If the nodes accept this block,
they will include a hash pointer to this block in the next block that they create.