Now let's discuss the security of bitcoins.
First, can Alice steal bitcoins that belonged to another user?
This is not possible because there's no way
Alice can create a valid signature that spends that coin.
That is, as long as the underlying cryptography is solid,
Alice cannot steal bitcoins.
But can Alice launch a double spending attack?
Suppose Alice creates two transactions.
Here we use C subscript A to represent a coin owned by Alice.
Suppose in the first transaction she sends Bob a bitcoin.
In the second transaction,
Alice double spends by sending the same bitcoin to another node that she controls.
Of course, only one of these transactions can be included in the blockchain.
If the blockchain get extended from the second transaction,
then Bob will be denied this bitcoin.
Suppose Bob is the merchant.
In order to protect himself from this attack,
Bob should wait until the transaction has multiple confirmations.
That is, there are multiple blogs extended from this block in the blockchain.
The most common heuristics is to wait until you hear six confirmations.
Let's summarize the safeguards in bitcoin.
The protection against invalid transactions is done through cryptography,
but also enforced by consensus.
Protection against double-spending is purely by consensus.
There's no 100% guarantee that a transaction is in the consensus branch.
That is, the guarantee is probabilistic.
Again, the more confirmation you see,
the higher probability that a transaction is valid.