Because the target hash value is very small,
it is very hard to find a correct nonce.
In fact, only the nodes with a lot of
computing power these are kind of miners would do this proof of work.
Another nice property is that we can adjust the cost of proof of work.
For example, if the goal is to be able to create one block every 10 minutes,
then the nodes can automatically recalculate the target hash value every two weeks.
It is obvious that probability that Alice will win the next block
depends on the fraction of global computing hash power she can choose.
Therefore, the key security assumption is that attacks are
infeasible if the majority of the miners weighted by hash power follow the protocol.
In other words, the majority of the miners weighted by hash power are honest.
It is obvious that proof of work is very easy to verify.
In particular, the nonce value has to be published as part of the bulk.
Therefore, other miners can simply verify
that the hash value is smaller than target hash value.
Obviously, proof of work can be used as incentive
when the mining reward is greater than the mining cost.