To summarize this lesson,
let's think about what a 51 percent attacker can do,
that is, an attacker that controls 51 percent of the computing power.
Can the attacker steal Bitcoins?
No, because digital signatures can prevent this.
Can the attacker suppress some transactions from the blockchain?
Yes, because this attacker can refuse to extend from that block.
Can the attacker suppress transactions from Peer-2-Peer network?
No, because the transitions are broadcasted to Peer-2- Peer network.
Can they change the block reward?
No. That is determined by the whole system.
Can the attacker destroy confidence in Bitcoin?
Yes. For example, by refusing to extend from the valid block,
then Bitcoin may become useless for valid transactions.