Now, let's have a quick review of hash functions.
There are several important properties of cryptographic hash functions.
First, it is easy to compute.
You can compute the hash of a message of any size.
For a given hash function,
it produces fixed length output.
Hash function is a one-way function, that is,
given the hash of the message,
it is not easy to find the original message.
Hash functions are also designed to be collision resistant.
That is, given a particular message, m_1,
it is computationally infeasible to find a different message, m_2,
such that m_2 and m_1 have
the same hash value and that is the weak collision-resistant property.
A strong collision
resistant property states that,
computationally, it is infeasible to find
two different messages such that they've the same hash value.