Now, let's introduce a new data structure called hash pointer.
We know that a typical data pointer is the address to where the data is stored.
A hash pointer contains a pointer to where
the data is stored but also the hash of that data.
That is, we expand the data pointer to include the hash of the data.
We're going to use this notation to represent hash pointers.
If we have a hash pointer, obviously,
we can use the data pointer to get the data back.
But since we have the hash,
we can also verify that the data has not been changed.
We can use hash pointers to build very useful data structures.
In particular, we can build blockchain,
which is a linked list of hash pointers.
Suppose we have a hash pointer pointing to a block.
This block contains not only data value but also the hash pointer of the previous block,
and likewise, the previous block contains
not only the data values but also a hash pointer to the previous block.
And this is called a blockchain.
To construct a blockchain,
we append a block at the end,
include a hash pointer in a block,
and then compute a hash and store the hash pointer.
This hash pointer is a root of this blockchain.
A use case for blockchain is a tamper-evident log.
That is, we want to be a log data structure that stores a bunch of
data and allows us to append data onto the end of the log.
But if somebody changes the data in the log,
it is easy for us to detect that.
We can see that if an attacker changes data in this block,
the hash will not match the hash pointer store in the next data block.
Of course, the attacker can then change the hash value stored in this hash pointer.
But the result is that the hash value of this block will not
match the hash value stored in the hash pointer of the next block.
The attacker can again change this hash value.
But then, it will not match the hash value stored in the root.
Therefore, tampering a data item will cause the difference of the computed hash of
the whole chain to be different than the hash value
stored in the hash pointer to the whole chain.
That is, by just remembering this single hash pointer,
we can easily detect data tampering.