Now, let's have a quick review of digital signatures.
What we want from signatures is that only the owner of the private key can sign,
but anyone can modify because they can retrieve the owners public key.
Further, a signature is tied to a particular document.
Let's review how digital signatures are created and verified.
We have a private signing key and a public verification key.
The key pair can be created by specifying the key size.
Then, for particular message,
we can create a signature by essentially encrypting
the message using the private signing key.
Given the message and the signature,
any person who has obtained the public key can verify the signature.
The verification is performed by using
the public key to decrypt the signature and matching the result with the message.
What are the requirements for signatures?
Obviously, a valid signatures can be verified,
and no one can forge a signature.
Public key cryptography guarantees that although anyone can know the public key,
but without the private key,
which is only known to the owner,
no one can forge a signature.