Public key can be used as an identity.
For example, if you can verify a signature using a person's public key,
you can think of it as a person who owns the public key has stated the message.
Of course, you can create a valid signature only because you have the private key.
Therefore, by creating a valid signature or speak of a message,
it means that you can prove to anybody that you're already the owner of the public key.
Here's how we can use public key to create a new identity.
First, we'll create a new random pair of public key and private key.
The public key or the hash of the public key becomes your name or your ID.
But the private key is really what you can use to prove your identity.
The advantage of this approach is that since only you who have the private key,
nobody can forge your identity;
and if the public key looks very random,
nobody really knows who you are.
Another advantage is the decentralized identity management.
That is, anybody can create a new identity at anytime.
In fact, you can make as many identities as you want.
There's no central point of control or coordination.
These public key-based identities are called addresses in Bitcoin