Now let's look at the transport
layer protocols, in particular,
the transmission control protocol or
TCP.
TCP is connection-oriented and
it preserves the order of packets,
we can use an analogy to explain TCP.
Suppose we want to mail a book, and
the way we send the book is to
mail each page in envelope.
And that's analogous to breaking
application data into TCP packets.
And of course, for each page,
there's a page number, so
that we know the sequence of
these pages in the original book.
Likewise, TCP packets
have sequence numbers.
Now, when the pages arrive,
they arrive in separate envelopes and
may be out of order.
At the destination, we make sure
that we receive all the pages,
put them back in order and
reassemble the book.
Similarly, at the definition host,
each packet upon it's receipt,
will be acknowledged.
And any lost packet will be notified so
that the source can resend the packet
and then the packet will be
reassembled in the original order.
Now let's take a look at TCP Header,
it includes the port numbers,
the sequence number of the packet and
acknowledgement number.
That is for acknowledging
a previously received packet.
It also has a number of flux, these
are used to control the TCP connection.