Let's review how TCP Handshake works.
The client sends a SYN packet to server.
We randomly generated
initial sequence number.
The server sends a SYN/ACK
packet to the client.
It also has a randomly generated
initial sequence number.
And also acknowledged the sequence
number of the SYN packet
from the client.
And then the client sends the ACK
packet back to the server.
It also acknowledges the sequence number
of the SYN/ACK packet from the server.
At this point the connection
is established.
Once a connection is established both
sides can expect that their next packet
will have the sequence number that is
increment from the previous packets.
Now of course packets
can arrive out of order.
But one can expect that the sequence
number should not be too far
out of the current window.
Therefore, if packets arrives
with a sequence number
that's too far out of the current
window it would be dropped.