We call that in TCP handshake,
the first packet from the client and
the first packet from the server have
the sequence numbers randomly generated.
This is very important.
Suppose, these initial sequence
numbers are predictable.
Then the attacker can forge
a source ID address and
still be able to finish the TCP
handshake and establish a TCP session.
And this will break IP-based
authentication such as SPF,
which is Sender Policy Framework
that is used to authenticate email.
We can use an example to illustrate
the importance of having random
initial sequence numbers.
Suppose there's an attacker and
he wants to forge the source IP address
of the victim to create a TCP session.
So the attacker sends the initial
SYN packet to the server and
forge the source IP address
to be from the victim.
Now the server is going to send
a SYN/ACK packet to the victim
with its own sequence number.
Of course, the attacker did
not receive the SYN/ACK packet
because the SYN/ACK packet
is sent to the victim.
Now if this sequence
number is predictable,
then the attacker can still send ACK
packet to ACK this SYN packet as if
that the attacker had
received the SYN/ACK packet.
And when a server receives this
ACK packet on its SYN/ACK packet,
then the server knows that
the connection should be established.
>From this point on, the attacker can
send command through the server and
the server will think that
the command is from its victim.
Because the victim and the server
hasn't established TCP connection.
Here's an example of attacks on
predictable sequence numbers,
suppose the attacker can correctly
guess the sequence number.
He can then send a reset packet.
This will terminate a connection and
result in the null service attack.