Again, from the perspective of routing,
the Internet is a collection of
domains or autonomous systems.
An autonomous system is a connected
group of computers where their
IP addresses share some common prefixes,
and they're using a single or
common routing policy.
The routing between these
domains is determined by BGP.
And the routing within each domain is
determined by protocols such as OSPF.
Now let's discuss the security
of routing protocols.
Recall that the ARP protocol
maps IP address to MAC address.
Now, suppose there's an ARP request
asking for the MAC address for
node B's IP address.
This ARP request is broadcasted
to the whole network.
Now if node A is malicious,
it can send ARP reply to the gateway
with its own Mac address.
If this reply arrives at the gateway
before the reply of node B does,
then the gateway will think
that node A is node B.
Which means that node A now is right
in the middle, and you can read or
inject packets into node B sessions.
The Border Gateway Protocol, or BGP,
decides the routing policy
between autonomous systems.
However, in BGP routing information,
and in particular route updates,
are not authenticated.
Therefore, through a false
advertisement, an attacker can cause
traffic to a victim host to instead
route to the attacker's own address.
There are plenty of examples
illustrating the danger of
false route advertisement.
Essentially, anyone can
hijack route to victim