Let's illustrate how BGP works.
Here, the nodes
are the autonomous systems.
And the edges represent
peering relations.
Here, nod 2 provides transit to node 7,
and this information is propagated,
so all autonomous systems
know how to reach node 7.
The main security issues of BGP
are due to the fact that BGP path
information is not authenticated which
means that anyone can inject false
advertisements and such advertisements
will be propagated everywhere.
As a result, attackers can shape and
route traffic to launch
denial of service attacks,
send spams and perform eavesdroppings.
Here's an example of BGP path hijacking.
Here's a normal or legitimate path.
And then, there was path
hijacking event in February 2013.
In this attack, only the path
of this direction is changed.
The other direction is not changed.
Therefore, if you are in DC,
because this direction is not changed,
you cannot tell by doing traceroute.