You can think of the Internet as
a collection of large networks.
These large networks
are typically managed
by the Internet Service Providers,
or the ISPs.
The ISPs work together to allow traffic
to flow from one network to another.
So to the users, the Internet is
just one big connected network.
Because a user can reach from his
computer on one end of the Internet
to another computer on
the other end of the Internet.
The computers within a local
area network use the local and
inter-domain routing protocol
to communicate with each other.
Computers from different networks,
for example,
from two different ISP networks,
use TCP/IP protocol to communicate.
But in order to decide how to send
traffic from host A to host B which may
be in two separate ISP networks,
there needs to be routing information
which is decided by BGP which stands for
border gateway protocol.
The domain name system is a distributed,
hierarchical database system
that provides the mapping between an IP
address and a symbol domain name,
such as www.cc.gatech.edu.