Let's discuss S-BGP in more detail.
The users IPsec to protect
the point-to-point router communication.
It also assumes PKI.
The reason is that it uses public key
cotography to provide attestations.
In particular address attestation
proves the authorization to
advertise certain address blocks.
And route attestations
proves the validation
of the route update information.
And of course S-BGP
requires repositories and
tools to manage certificates.
The certificate's revocation lists and
the address attestations.
Here's an example of address blocks
advertised by autonomous system
nodes seven.
That is as the routing
information is being publicated.
all the nodes need to know that
nodes seven is responsible for
these addresses.
Now let's discuss
attestation in more detail.
In address attestation, the issuer is
the organization that owns the address
prefixes contained in the attestation
and the subject is one or
more ASS that are authorized
to advertise these prefixes.
For example,
this ASS are the organization's
internet service providers.
In other words, an AS such as an ASP
has to be authorized by the owner
of the address blocks to advertise
the route to these address blocks.
An address at the station includes
the following information.
Essentially it certifies that
the owner owns the address blocks and
the owner authorizes the AS to
advertise for this address blocks.
The owner uses his private key
to sign the address blocks.
Address attestation is used to
protect BGP from incorrect updates.
The second type of attestation
is route attestation.
Here the issuer or
the speaker is an AS and the subject or
the listener is a transit AS.
Basically, route attestation allows
BGP speaker that receives a route
advertisement to verify that each AS
along the route has been authorized
by the preceding AS along
the path to advertise that route.
And that the originating AS has been
authorized by the owner of each IP
address prefix contained in the update
to advertise these prefixes.
Route Attestation includes
the following information.
The speakers certificate,
the address block and
the list of AS's, the neighbor,
and the expiration date.
The signature guarantees
that the organization
owning the IP address space advertised
in the update was allocated that
address space through a chain of
delegation originating at the eye can.
And this can protect BGP
from incorrect updates.
In order to validate a route, an AS
needs to perform address attestation for
each organization owning
the address block.
And also, route attestation for
each AS along the path.
And of course, all the certificates must
be available, and they must be valid.