At the IP layer, the IP Protocol
routes packet from host a to host b
approaching never
boundaries if necessary.
The routing is connectionless because
it is best effort only and unreliable.
Meaning that, it's not guaranteed that,
all packets from host
a will arrive at host b.
And of course, for each IP packet,
the source IP address and
the destination IP address
must be specified.
The ports are not part of the IP header
because they're for the transport layer.
Here's an example of IP routing.
Suppose, we have a packet with
source and destination IP addresses.
Typically, a route will
involve multiple hops.
An IP routing has no guarantee of the
order or even delivery of the packets.
In this example, the packet
starts from the source IP address
reaches the gateway of its ISP, across
network boundary to reach the gateway of
the destination network and then finally
reaches the destination IP address.
The summary from this example, the IP
host knows how to reach the gateway and
the gateway knows how to
reach other networks.
If a data segment is too large, it may
be fragmented into multiple IP packets.
At the receiving end, these fragments
will be assembled back together.
If the destination did not
receive a packet or fragment,
you can send an ICMP packet to
the source to report the error.
ICMP stands for
Internet Control Message Protocol.
The IP header can also
include a TTL field.
TTL stands for Time to Live and this
field is decremented after every hop and
a packet is dropped if TTL reaches 0.
TTL is useful to prevent infinite loops.