Record it in the IP header,
the source and destination IP
addresses must be specified.
However, one can easily override
the source IP address using raw sockets.
For example, you can use the Libnet
library to format raw packets
with arbitrary IP header information
including the source IP address.
This means that there's no guarantee
that the source ID address is authentic.
This means that anyone who owns
the machine, and knows how to use a tool
like dimnet, can send packets with
arbitrarily sourced IP addresses.
Now of course, a response will be sent
back to the forged source IP address.
For example, host A can send packets
forging the source IP address of
host B and then the response
will be sent back to host B.
The ability to forge arbitrary
source IP addresses enables
anonymous denial-of-service attacks and
anonymous infection and malware attacks.