Lets use an example to illustrate
frequency analysis attack.
Here is encrypted data of the number
of days a patient stays in hospital.
As you can see the data is encrypted
to perform frequency analysis
we first sort the data and
record the frequency.
We also sort and record
the frequency of the auxiliary data.
For example, there's public information
of how frequent a patient will stay for
one day versus two days and so on.
By matching these two histograms
we can link a cyber text value
to a plain text value.
For example, for the first cyber
attack value the frequency is ten.
And we know that from
the auxiliary data,
the plain text value one
has frequency of 11.
Therefore, we can link the ciphertext
value to plaintext value one.
And therefore, with frequency analysis,
we can uncover the plaintext
data without the encryption key.