This attack can be generalized and
optimized.
Again, start with the encrypted data,
we have obtained a frequency histogram.
We also obtain a frequency
histogram from the auxiliary data.
The basic idea is then,
to find an assignment from servertext
to plaintext that minimizes
a gives cost function.
Here the cost function is
the distance between the histograms.
This has the effect of minimizing
the total mismatch in frequencies across
all plaintext- ciphertext pairs.
For example, for this assignment,
the cost is this.
Whereas the assignment on mapping,
it has the minimum cost is this.
There's an algorithm that can find the
assignments that has the minimum cost.
With this algorithm,
we can find the assignment
from ciphertext to plain text and then
decipher the original encrypted data.