We have discussed on equality
preserving inscription.
Now, let's discuss a tax on
order preserving inscription.
We can use sorting attack, but a more
effective attack is cumulative attack.
Given a data column that has been
encrypted using order preserving
inscription.
A nemissary can learn not
only the frequencies, but
also the relative ordering
of the encrypted values.
Combining ordering with frequencies,
the attacker can tell for
each server text C, what fraction of
the encrypted values are less than C.
More formally, this is known
as the empirical cumulative
distribution function of the dataset or
CDF.
In the cumulative attack,
an attacker leveraged the CDF to improve
the ability to match
plaintext to ciphertext.
Intuitively, if a given ciphertext is
greater than 90% of the ciphertext in
the encrypted data, then we shall match
it to a plaintext that is greater
than about 90% of the auxiliary data.
This problem belongs to a category
of Linear Sum assignment Problem.
Therefore, we can use an algorithm
to find the mapping of plaintexts to
ciphertext that minimizes the total
sum of mismatch in frequency plus
the mismatch in CDFs across all
plaintext, ciphertext pairs.