Let's discuss data privacy
issues in a cloud environment.
First let's review how
data breaches happen.
In a cloud environment
the users use applications or
data stored in a cloud provider.
For example,
the users can be doctors and nurses, and
the application can be the electronic
medical record system.
And the data obviously
is the medical records.
And the called EMR here can be
a private called such as UCLA Health.
As another example,
the users can be average consumers.
And the application can online dating.
And of course,
the data can be the dating profiles.
In most cases, including
the examples that we just discuss,
data is the most valuable
target to the attacker.
For example,
the attacker may want to steal the data.
Now the question is,
how do we protect the data?
Obviously we can encrypt the data.
For example,
the users can have their own secret
encryption key for their data.
And once the data is encrypted the
adversary can no longer read the data.
The problem when the data is
encrypted the applications
can no longer use the data as it is.
For example if the application
is a word processing programm
such as Microsoft Word, it cannot
process encrypted data directly.
Therefore, the real question
is can we protect the data
while we also let the application work?
In other words, we want to protect
the data by encrypting the data, so
that the adversary cannot read our data.
On the other hand, we also want
the application to continue to work.