To understand the potential
security issues of
Property Preserving Encryption,
let's do a quiz.
First, let's review standard encryption.
In standard encryption,
there is no preserving of properties.
For example,
suppose we encrypt the age information.
The encrypted data leaks
nothing except the size
of the original plain text data.
For example,
we know that there are four entries.
Now let's take a look at an example
of property preserving encryption.
Again, we want to encrypt the age
information, but we preserve equality.
Therefore in encrypted data, we see
that these two values are the same,
because the original paying
tax values are the same.
So what is preserved?