Before we discuss the details of notice and coppice,
let's go over some of the notations and terminologies.
We use RR to represent resource record.
It's a tuple of domain name and its reserved IP address.
For domain, www.example.com.
2LD is example.com, and 3LD is www.example.com.
The related historic IPs of a domain are
all the routable IPs historically mapped with this domain name,
and any other domain name,
within the same 2LD and 3LD.
Related historic domains of an IP address are
all the fully qualified domain names that historically had been linked with this IP,
and also, all the IPs with this address box,
and the autonomous systems.
The authoritative domain name tuple is the requester for example,
that because of DNS, the domain name and RDATA,
which includes all information about this domain.
Notos uses passive DNS data collected at a recursive DNS server.
For example, this can be your ISP.
In our study, we use data from multiple ISPs and data repositories.
For coppice, we use data from two large authoritative DNS servers,
and the Canadian top-level domain server.