Now, let's discuss the temporal and statistical features of Notos.
Given a resource record,
and that is a tuple of domain name and its resolve IP,
Notos uses the passive DNS data to extract network based features.
These features are based on the related historic IPs.
It also extracts the zone features.
These features are based on the related historic domains.
Notos also constructs the so-called evidence features
by analyzing the blacklist and honeypot data,
and look for evidence associated with these IPs and domains.
These features are then combined and forwarded to
the reputation engine which computes a reputation score for this domain.