Here's a summary of Notos statistical and temporal features.
The network-based features are extracted from the set of related historic IPs.
The features include, the total number of IPs historically associated with a domain,
the diversity of their geographical locations,
the number of distinct autonomous systems, and so on.
The zone-based features are extracted from the set of related historic domains.
The features include, the average length of domain names,
the number of distinct top-level domains,
the occurrence frequency of different characters, and so on.
The evidence-based features include,
the number of distinct malware samples that contacted the domain,
and the same for any of its resolved IPs.
Here we show the result of clustering 250,000 domains using the Noto features.
As we can see, the clusters don't overlap.
This tells us that the Notos features are very good
at separating domains of different types into different clusters.