Now, let's discuss how Notos computes reputation of a domain.
First, Notos needs to chain a repetition function,
given a set of domains known to be legitimate or malicious.
Notos extract features for each of these domains and give label 1 to malicious domains,
and label 0 to legitimate domains.
Then, given this training data set,
Notos can use a machine learning algorithm to learn a function that,
given the Notos feature vector of a domain,
it will output a label,
meaning 0 or 1,
and the reputation score of this domain is simply the confidence of this label.
That is, the probability that this domain is malicious.
As we can see here,
this function is very accurate.
That is, it has a very high true positive array and very low false positive rate.
Here, we show that Notos can detect
many malicious domains days or weeks before they show up in any blacklist.
Sometimes that's even months before they show up in any blacklist.
This is true for all the malicious domains
and also for different types of malicious domains