Now, let's take a look at Kopis.
Recall that Kopis is similar to Notos except that
Kopis is deployed at the upper level of the DNS hierarchy.
Therefore, the main difference between Kopis and Notos is in their features.
In particular, Kopis analyzes requester diversity.
This requester diversity features characterize if the machines that
query a given domain name are localized or are globally distributed.
The requester profile features distinguish request from a small network
versus a large network because
a larger network would have a larger number of infected machines.
The resolved IP reputation futures look at whether the IP address space pointed
to by a given domain name has been historically linked with known malicious activities.