Now, let's discuss a study of mobile malware prevalence using domain amputation.
The motivation of our study is that most research
has been focusing on analyzing malicious mobile apps,
but the question remains,
how prevalence are the infections on mobile devices?
Our intuition is that mobile web is actually part of
the regular web and therefore
mobile malware will use similar command control infrastructure
and therefore our approach is to analyze DNS traffic obtained
from cellular network providers and identify domains looked up by mobile apps.
Then for the internet machines that host these domains,
we analyze their reputation.