In our study, we first identified the mobile devices,
and then we attribute each DNS query to a device.
We then analyze the repetition of the resource records associated with the DNS query.
We use the Notos features to analyze
the hosting infrastructures of mobile domains and compute repetition scores.
The difference is that we use different features.
In particular, for mobile domain,
we first find the IP address of the machine that hosts this domain.
Then for each of these IP addresses,
we extract the following features: the historic non-cellular domains,
the related historic mobile domains,
any evidence of malware association with these domains,
as well as URLs for phishing and drive-by download associated with these domains,
and evidence that these domains have been blacklisted before.
With these features and examples of malicious and legitimate mobile domains,
Notos can then use machine learning algorithm to learn a scoring function.
This scoring function can tell us how likely a mobile domain is malicious.
Here are some results from our study.
This column is the breakdown of total number of DNS requests for mobile devices.
As you can see, there are lot more Android devices than iOS devices.
When a machine on Internet has filed a petition,
we call it as machine tainted.
Some mobile domains are hosted on these tainted machines.
This column shows the percentage of requests to this tainted hosts.
As we can see, the iOS and Android devices
are equally likely to connect to these tainted hosts.
We also measure the number of devices,
their lookup domains that are associated with known malware families.
As you can see, the number of devices we've known,
malware infection is small.