The first statement, one of the most successful methods to taking down
a botnet requires investigators to find and target each bot in the net.
This is false because typically,
it is not possible to enumerate all paths in the net.
The second statement, a proven method to stop botnets require
isolating the C&C domain from the bot net. This is true.
If you take down the command control infrastructure,
the bot net will cease to function.
The third statement, with regards to take downs,
P2P-based networks are much easier than centralized C&C networks.
This is false because P2P-based networks use
distributed C&C and that's much harder to take down than centralized C&C.