To motivate our study,
we observed that currently Botnet Takedowns are ad hoc,
and performed without oversight and sometimes are not successful.
Our goal is to develop a system and framework to reason
about Takedowns and recommend the best Takedown strategies.
The goal of our study is to develop a system to reason about Takedowns,
evaluate previous takedown attempts,
and recommend future directions.
The high-level idea is that we need to have
as complete knowledge of the Botnet infrastructure as possible.
We use both passive DNS analysis and
malware analysis to expand our knowledge of the Botnet infrastructure.
Here's an overview of our system called RZA.
We start with a set of seed domains.
These domains are known to be associated with Botnet infrastructure.
They may use passive DNS data to analyze domains related to
these seed domains including the reputation
and malware samples associated with these domains.
For the malware samples,
we perform malware analysis to find out more domains,
and that is how our system now has
a much more complete knowledge of the Botnet infrastructure.
Based on this knowledge, we can perform analysis of previous takedowns,
and also recommend takedown strategies of a current Botnet.
To summarize, we start with a set of
seed domains they are known to be associated with Botnet infrastructure,
then we enumerate all related domains.
Some of these domains have low reputation,
and some are associated with malware.
For the malware samples,
we further interrogate to find out more domains.
Here's a high level idea of how we interrogate a malware.
Suppose this is domain that are malware would use by default.
So, the malware is going to perform a lookup of this domain,
and then connect with CNC server.
To force the malware to tell us more domains that you may use,
we can intercept the DNS query and respond with no such domain.
Then, if there's a backup domain,
the malware is going to look it up.
Therefore, by analyzing the malware DNS traffic
we can find out more domains that a malware might use.