Here is our infrastructure to interrogate malware.
You run the malware image machine and have a gateway between the malware and Internet.
Therefore, we can control how the malware can connect to its infrastructure.
For example, we can play with DNS, no such domain,
or TCP reset to force the malware to exhibit backup behaviors.
Such a backup behaviors can include
using additional domains or switching to a Peer-2-Peer.
We observe that a malware typically would use
hard-coded domains or when these domains are becoming not available,
it may we try again and then it may try the next set of domains and IPs as a backup.
When those are not available,
they may switch to Peer-2-Peer,
or the so-called, domain generation algorithm,
to use randomly generated domains.
The intuition behind our approach is that malware will use
an increasing number of domains and IPs when the infrastructure becomes now available.
The easiest manipulation is by DNS and TCP.
Of course, we can easily add more protocols.