Now, let's discuss an ideal takedown procedure.
Again, we start with a set of seed domains.
These domains are known to be associated with partner infrastructure.
We enumerate the infrastructure using passive DNS.
We get the malware associated with the domains and interrogate a malware.
If the malware tells us additional domains, we look back.
On the other hand, if there is no addition no domains,
then we take the set of domains that we know so far and revoke all of them.
That's how we take down the botnet.
If you find that the malware is using dynamically-generated domains,
then we need to first reverse engineer the algorithm,
then we need to tell the TLD operators and
DNS registrars to stop hosting or adjusting these new domains.
We will also revoke the set of non CNC domains.
If the malware exhibits behavior of using peer-to-peer network,
then we need to take down the peer-to-peer protocol.
For example, by penetrating into the peers.
We also need to revoke the set of non CNC domains.