Now, let's discuss some case studies.
We perform analysis of previous takedowns.
We also analyze how we can take down some of the active botnets.
Here we showed a log scale of lookup volumes to different set of domains.
This is the date of takedown.
As we can see, lookups to the seed domains,
the intogrey domains, and malware domains stop immediately at takedown or soon after.
This means that, this takedown is very effective.
In the case of Zeus,
although there are multiple groups including Microsoft and
several research groups taking place in takedowns,
their efforts were not coordinated.
More importantly, none of them had complete knowledge of the botnet infrastructure.
Therefore, even after the takedown effort,
the botnet continue to connect to its infrastructure.
This takedown was accomplished by transferring the entire 3322.org name
server authority to Microsoft and
domains the malicious result to a set of long single IP addresses.
That is, domains were sunk on a day of
takedown and were limited to the 3322.org domain names.
Unfortunately, this only accounted for a fraction of domains associated with malware.
Therefore, lookups to this malware associated domains remain frequent.
In other words, this is not an effective takedown.