Of the 45 active Botnet,
we find that too had TGA based backup mechanisms,
and one had a peer-to-peer based backup mechanism.
On the other hand, 42 of them are subject to DNS only Takedown.
To summarize the drawbacks of current Takedown efforts,
there ad hoc meaning that they don't
have complete knowledge of the Botnet infrastructure.
There's a valid oversight,
meaning that different groups may step on each other,
and the success rate is not high.
Therefore, we believe that
a central authority to coordinate Takedown efforts is necessary.
Icons policies can provide an example framework.
For example, there is policy for domain name dispute resolution.
There's also system for rapid suspension.
Therefore, we should study policy criteria for Takedowns,
and have the community to review such criterias.
We can test the policy with the newly created top-level domains.