Traditionally, when an IP address is discovered to have been used to send spam,
it is added to a blacklist.
This is called a static blacklist.
If an IP address is in a blacklist,
then emails coming from this IP address can be blocked.
This is a great idea except that attackers also know about the blacklist.
So spammers can circumvent the blacklist by using new IP addresses,
and by the time an IP address is discovered
to have been used to send spam and edit to blacklist,
the spammers can then move on to use a new IP address.
We need to change this model to be in line with our philosophy about network security,
and that is an IP address should not be trusted by default.