Now, let's discuss a new blocklist model.
We know that static blocklist are increasingly ineffective.
What we need is a dynamic reputation system that
outputs the reputation score or the trustworthiness of a domain.
The intuition of this new model is
that legitimate use of domains and sites are different for malicious use.
The question is, how do we observe such differences?
Our intuition is that such differences can be observed in DNS traffic.
For example, we can look at the patterns of requests and the reputation of the requester,
the resolved IPs, and the network providers for these domains.
Therefore, our approach is to analyze DNS traffic,
extract temporal and statistical features and then apply machine learning
algorithms to learn models that can provide the dynamic score of a domain.