Now, let's discuss two DNS repetition systems.
The first one is NOTOS.
NOTOS is a system that dynamically assigns repetition score to a domain name.
It uses features that capture the characteristics of resource provisioning,
usages, and management of DNS domains.
Given examples of legitimate and malicious domains,
NOTOS uses machine learning algorithm to
compute a scoring function based on these features.
This scoring function can output a repetition score for new domain.
In our study, we are shown that NOTOS has very high accuracy.
That is, it has a very low false positive rate and very high true positive rate.
That is, NOTOS can detect
a fraudulent or malicious domain weeks or days before it is widely used.
NOTOS can be applied to a large network,
for example, a particular ISP.
Whereas another system called Kopis has
Internet-wide visibility because it performs
monitoring at the upper levels of the DNS hierarchy.
That is, Kopis uses DNS traffics at authoritative DNS or top-level domain DNS service.
Similar to NOTOS, Kopis also extract a set of
statistical and temporal features from
the traffic and then uses machine learning algorithm to chain a scoring function.
Similar to NOTOS, Kopis also has very high accuracy rate.
Similar to NOTOS, Kopis can also detect
malicious domains weeks before they were listed in any blacklist.
Since Kopis has the Internet-wide visibility,
it can detect that a domain is being used by malware within
one country months or weeks before the malware begin to spread to other countries.
For example, in our study,
Kopis was able to detect a DDoS botnet rising in networks within
China almost one month before it propagated to other countries.