Now, let's discuss bitcoin exchange.
Bitcoin exchange accepts deposits of Bitcoins and fiat currency.
For example, dollars, pounds,
euros, and so on.
These exchanges let customers make and receive bitcoin payments,
and buy and sell bitcoins using fiat currency.
You would typically match a bitcoin buyer with a bitcoin seller.
Of course, it promises to give the money back to the customer,
therefore, bitcoin exchanges are similar to banks.
As a result, bitcoin exchanges need to
meet a number of minimal requirements or expectations.
For example, bitcoin exchanges should meet the minimum reserve requirements,
that means they must hold some fraction of deposits in reserve.
A Bitcoin exchange needs to provide a proof of reserve to
give customers some comfort about the money that they have deposited.
The goal is for the exchange to prove that he has a fraction or reserve,
for example, from 35 percent to even 100 percent of the deposits that people have made.
We can break the Proof of Reserve problem into two pieces.
The first is to prove how much reserve you are holding.
The exchange can simply publish a valid
payment-to-self transaction of the claimed reserve amount.
That is, if he claims to have 100,000 bitcoins,
it creates a transaction in which he pays 100,000
bitcoins to herself and show that the transaction is valid.
Strictly speaking, this is not a proof that the exchange really owns this amount,
but only that whoever does own this amount is willing to support the exchange.
The second piece of the Proof of Reserve problem
is to prove that how many demand deposits you hold.
We will discuss this next.