The second piece of proval reserve is to prove how many demand deposits you hold,
and here is a scheme.
Recall that a Merkle tree is a binary tree that is built with hash pointers,
so that each of the pointers not only sets where we can get a piece of information,
but also what a cryptographic hash of that information is.
A bitcoin exchange executes a prove of
how many demand deposits it holds by constructing Merkle tree.
In this Merkle tree,
each hash pointer also includes an attribute.
This attribute is a number that represents the total value in
bitcoins of all of the deposits that are in a subtree underneath this hash pointer.
For this to be true, the attribute value of
each hash pointer has to be the sum of the values of the two hash pointers beneath it.
A bitcoin exchange constructs this tree and size
the root pointer along with the route attribute value and publishes it.
The root value is, of course.
The total liabilities. That is,
by constructing this tree and publishing its root value,
the exchange is making the claim that all users are represented in
the leaves of the tree and that the deposit values are represented correctly.
Furthermore, the deposited values are propagated correctly up the tree,
so that the root value is the sum of all the users' deposit amounts.
Now, each customer can go to the exchange and ask
for proof of correct inclusion of his deposit.
The exchange must then show the customer
the puzzle tree from the user's leaf up to the root.
The customers then verifies that first.
The root hash pointer and root value are the
same as to what exchange has signed and published.
Second, the hashpointers are consistent all the way down.
That is, each hash value is indeed the cryptographic hash of the node it points to.
Third, the leaves contains correct use account information.
For example, user ID and the deposit amount.
Fourth, each value is the sum of the values of the two values beneath it.
The good news here is that if every customer does this,
then every branch of the tree will get explored,
and someone will verify that for every hash pointer,
its associative value equals the sum of the values of its two children.
It's very important that the exchange cannot
present different values in any part of the tree to different customers.
That's because doing so would either imply that the ability to find
a hash collision or presenting
different root values to different customers which we assume is not possible.
The customer then verifies that, first,
the root hash pointer and root value are the
same as what the exchange has signed and published.
Second, the hash pointer are consistent all the way down.
That is, each hash value is indeed the cryptographic hash of the node it points to.
Third, the leaf contains correct user account information.
For example, user ID and a deposit amount.
Fourth, each value is the sum of the values of the two values beneath it.
The good news is that if every customer does this,
then every branch of the tree will get explored,
and somehow we verified that for every hash pointer it's
associative value equals the sum of the values of its two children.
It is very important to note that the change
cannot present different values in any part of a tree to
different customers because that will imply
that either the exchange can find a hash collision,
or it can present different root values to different customers,
which we think is not possible.