Now, let's discuss anonymity in Bitcoin.
Some, including WikiLeaks, claims that BitCoins provide anonymity.
Others, believe that Bitcoin does not provide anonymity.
So, what is anonymity?
Literally, anonymous means without a name.
Bitcoin, an ID is an address,
which is the hash of a public key.
In computer science, we call this pseudonymity.
In computer science, an anonymity means pseudonymity plus unlinkability.
We know that Bitcoins provides pseudonymity.
Now, the question is does Bitcoin provide unlinkability.
That is, can we be sure that in Bitcoin,
different transactions of the same users can be linked together.
More precisely, unlinkability in Bitcoin means that,
it is also hard to link different transactions of the same user.
Furthermore, it should be hard to link the sender of a payment to its recipient.