We know that in Bitcoin,
it is trivial to create a new address.
That is, all you need to do is to create
a new public key public key pair and a hash of the public key becomes a new address.
That is, a single user can own many addresses or many IDs.
In fact, the best practice is to use
a fresh new address for the recipient in any new transaction.
So, the question is, can the addresses and the transactions still be linked?
Let's consider an example.
Suppose Alice wants to buy a teapot from a store and a teapot cost eight Bitcoins.
Let's further assume that Alice has some Bitcoins in her different addresses.
In order to pay for this teapot,
Alice has to create a single transaction that includes input from two addresses.
But in doing so, Alice has revealed that these two addresses belong to the same user.
In other words, two previous transactions that
use these two addresses as recipients must be to the same user.
This example that if you're sure to spending for multiple addresses,
we're linking these addresses together.
This example shows that if multiple addresses are using the same spending transaction,
that means that these addresses are under joint control.
In other words, we can link these addresses together.
Further, address linkability is tentative.
Furthermore, we can propagate such linkability.
Let's consider another example.
Suppose now, the price of the teapot has gone up from eight Bitcoins to 8.5 bitcoins.
So, Alice will create a transaction where she will transfer Bitcoins from two of
her addresses to pay for the teapot and also send the change to her own address.
Therefore, Alice will create transaction where she transfers Bitcoins
from two of her addresses but also send a change to one of her addresses as well.
So, Alice will create a transaction where she would transfer Bitcoins from two of
her addresses to pay for a teapot but also send a change to another address of hers.
Now, let's consider the transaction from the viewpoint of an adversary.
He can deduce that these two input addresses belong to the same user.
The attacker might also suspect that one of
these output addresses also belongs to the same user.
If the attacker knows that a teapot cost more than 0.5 Bitcoin,
then he would know that this address also belong to the same user.
Therefore, in this example,
the attacker can know that these three addresses belong to the same user.
We can only link or cast the addresses that belong to the same user.
We can also see if any of these addresses reveals the real identity of a real user.
For example, an address may be used in transaction through a provider that is legally
required to know the true user behind
the address or a user may have posted an address in a public forum.
For example, because he's making a donation.