One mechanism to make transaction link analysis less effective,
and let's protect unlinkability,
is to use mixing.
The main proposal for decentralized mixing.
Since bitcoin is a decentralized system is called coinjoin.
In this protocol, different users joining,
create a single bitcoin transaction that combines all the inputs.
Furthermore, in a transaction that has multiple inputs coming from different addresses,
the signatures corresponding to each input
are separate from and independent of each other.
This allows a group of users to mix their coins with a single transaction.
Each user supplies an input address and
an output address and form a transaction with these addresses.
The order of input and output addresses is randomized,
so that an outsider will be unable to determine the mapping between inputs and outputs.
All the participants check that it's outgoing address has been included in
the transaction and that it receives the same amount of bitcoin that they are inputting.
Once they have confirmed this,
they sign the transaction.
Somebody, say an attacker looking at this transaction on the blockchain,
even if they know that it is a coinjoin transaction,
would be unable to determine the mapping between the inputs and outputs.
From an outsider's perspective,
the coins have been mixed and this is the essence of coinjoin.
Here's the procedure to create coinjoin.
First, a participant needs to find peers who want to mix.
Then, they exchange the input and output addresses to be included in the transaction.
Then, they construct the transaction by mixing the orders.
Then, the transaction is sent around and each peer can check
that his or her input and output have been included.
Then, the signatures are collected in a transaction.
Finally, this coinjoin transaction is broadcast to the bitcoin system.
It is important for the participants to
exchange these input and output addresses in such a way
that even the other members of the peer group
do not know the mapping between input and output addresses.
To exchange these addresses in unlinkable way,
we need an anonymous communication protocol.
For example, we can use Tor or special purpose protocol.
For example, the peers can use Tor to exchange the input addresses.
Therefore, no one knows what input address each other is using.
Once that is accomplished,
it is not necessary to communicate the output addresses in a secure way.
there's no way to link an output address with an input address.