The Bitcoin system can be used for other applications.
For example, secure timestamping.
For example, we can prove knowledge of x or we know the value of x at a time
t. But we can do so without revealing
the actual value or knowledge of x at time t. Of course,
if we choose to, we can review x at some later time.
Recall that hash function is a one-way function.
That is, if you publish the hash value of x,
you're announcing a commitment to x.
Recall that a cryptographic hash function is
a one-way function and also loses in to collision.
Therefore, if we publish the hash value of x,
we essentially announcing the commitment to x.
In other words, everyone will know that we actually know
the true value of x by publishing the hash value of x,
and we don't have to reveal x to anyone.
In other words, we can later prove that we actually knew
the value of x because we had published the hash value of x.