Secure timestamping has many applications.
We have discussed proof of knowledge.
We can also use it as proof of receipt and so on.
As we have discussed,
to make a commitment, we need to publish the hash value of the data.
The simplest solution in bitcoin system is
that instead of sending money to the hash of a public key,
just send it to the hash of your data,
and then by announcing the transaction,
you're announcing the hash of your data.
The caveat here is that the coin you sent can be lost forever because you
don't know who actually happens to own
the address that corresponds to the hash of your data.
This approach is indeed very simple,
but we have to burn coins.
More importantly, the bitcoin miners don't know
that the coin you send to this address is lost forever.
So, they must check it forever just like any other legitimate bitcoins.
A more sophisticated approach is called CommitCoin.
It allows you to encode your data into the private key.
Recall that elliptic curve public key is used in bitcoin.
Just like other public key systems,
we need good randomness,
otherwise the private key can be leaked.
A property of elliptic curve is that if you use bad randomness in making a signature,
it will leak the private key.
CommitCoin exploits this property.
CommitCoin generates a new private key that
encodes a commitment and derive its corresponding public key.
We can then send a tiny transaction to
that address that corresponds to the public key and then
the address also sends back another transaction and we
use the same randomness in signing both of these transactions.
In CmomitCoin, we generate a new public key that encodes our commitment,
and we derive its corresponding public key.
We then send a tiny transaction to the address that corresponds
to the public key and we then send it back two chunks of bitcoins.
When doing so, we'll use the same randomness to sign
both chunks in the transaction and when sending it back,
we'll use the same randomness both times for signing the transaction.
This allows anyone looking at the blockchain to compute the public key
using these two signatures and the private key contains the commitment.
CommitCoin avoids the need to burn coins and
the miners don't have to keep track of unspendable output forever.
However, it is quite complex.
As of 2014, the preferred way to do
bitcoin timestamping is with the OP_RETURN transaction.
The OP_RETURN instruction returns immediately with an error,
so that this script can never be run successfully,
and the data that is encoded in the transaction is ignored.
This can be used to encode arbitrary data.
As of 2015, OP_RETURN allows 80 bytes of data to be pushed,
which is more than enough for a hash-function output.
For example, shot to 56,
the output length is 32 bytes.
As of late 2014,
there are already several websites that help with this.
They collect a bunch of commitments from
different users and combine them into a large Merkle tree,
then they publish one unspendable output containing the Merkle tree root.
This acts like a commitment for all the data that users wanted to timestamp that day.