Since we can write whatever data we want into Bitcoin,
we can also view an entirely new currency system on top of Bitcoin,
without needing to develop a new consensus mechanism.
That is, we can simply use Bitcoin as it exists today as an append-only
log and write all the data that we need for
our new currency system directly into the Bitcoin blockchain.
We call this approach an overlay currency.
That is, Bitcoin serves as the underlying substrate,
and the data of the overlay currency is written into
the Bitcoin blockchain using unspendable transaction outputs.
Of course, Bitcoin miners will not actually validate what you're
writing into the blockchain because they don't know the new currency system.
Also, anyone can write anything as long as they're willing to pay the transaction fees.
Since this is a different new currency system,
you must develop your own logic for validating transactions.