Recall that in bitcoin.
A valid transaction has information store in the blockchain,
but also the transactional information has to
also be signed by the owner's secret signing key,
or that's the private key of the public key pair.
Recall that in bitcoin,
a transaction information is store in the blockchain and it
also contains a signature signed by the owner's private key.
The owners need to keep their private key a secret.
So, this is about key management.
That is, how do you keep your private key secret and secure?
Of course, you can store your public key in a file on your computer or on your phone.
This is a very convenient approach.
On the other hand, if you're KeyStore is lost,
that means your private key is lost,
which means all your bitcoins are lost.
This is because without the private key,
you cannot prove that you're the owner of the matching public key.
Remember, all your coins are associated with that public key.
That is, your public key is your ID or address in bitcoin.
But, you have to use the private key to
prove that you're the owner of the public key or the ID.
Of course, your KeyStore can be compromised,
which means your public key can be stolen,
which means all the bitcoins can also be stolen because now
the attacker can claim that he's the owner of that public key or the ID.
Therefore, he has all your bitcoins.
For example, the stolen private key,
now the attacker can claim that he's the owner
of the ID that the bitcoins are associated with.
He can then pay those bitcoins to another address that he owns.
That way, he can steal all the bitcoins.