The so-called hot storage is online,
and the so-called cold storage is offline.
Hot storage is online,
for example, on your computer or on your phone.
It's very convenient, but it's not very secure.
On the other hand, cold storage is offline,
not convenient, but it's safe.
The reason is obvious,
if the storage is offline,
then a cyber attacker cannot get to it easily.
In general, we can keep a top secret in
a cold storage and put the most frequent used keys.
Here's another way to look at the difference between hot storage and cold storage.
We can put a top secret or the less frequently used master secret in a cold storage.
We can put the most frequently used keys in hot storage.
As we just discussed,
storing your keys of Bitcoins on computers is storing them in a hot storage.
It is online, convenient, but somewhat risky.
On the other hand, you can put your keys of Bitcoins offline.
This is less convenient, but much safer.
You can have the best of both worlds by having both hot storage and cold storage.
For example, you can move coins back and forth,
but then you need to use separate keys and each side
needs to know each other's keys or the addresses.
You need to use separate keys because otherwise,
the coins in cold storage will be vulnerable if the hot storage is compromised.
the coins in a cold storage will be vulnerable if the hot storage is compromised.
You will want to move the coins back and forth between the hot side and the cold side.
So, each side will need to note the others' addresses or public keys.