Suppose for privacy or other reasons,
we won't to be able to receive each bitcoin at a separate address.
So, whenever we transfer coin from the hot side to the cold side,
we would like to use a fresh cold edges for that purpose.
But, since the cold side is offline,
how do the hot side find out those addresses?
The blunt solution is for the cold side to generate
a big batch of addresses and send those over to the hot side.
The drawback is that the hot side need to reconnect with
the cold side periodically in order to transfer more addresses.
A better solution is to use the so-called hierarchical wallet.
To review, previously we discussed key generation and digital signatures,
and we looked at a function called generateKeys.
This function generates a public key which acts
as an address and a secret or private key.
In a hierarchical wallet,
key generation works in different way.
Instead of generating a single address,
we generate what we called address generation information.
Rather than private key,
we generate what we call private key generation information.
Given the address generation information,
we can generate a sequence of addresses.
Likewise, we can generate a sequence of
public keys using the private key generation information.
The cryptographic magic that makes this useful is that for every i,
the ith address and the ith secret key match up.
That is, the ith secret or private key
controls and can be used to spend bitcoins from the ith address.
That is, the ith private key is paired up with ith address.
In other words, we have a sequence of regular key pairs.
The other important cryptographic property here is security, that is,
the address generation information here does
not leak any information about the private keys.
On the other hand, not all digital signature schemes can
be modified to support hierarchical key generation.
The good news is that the digital signature scheme used by bitcoin,
elliptic curve, does support hierarchical key generation.
As a result, the cold side can generate as many keys as it
wants and the hot side can generate the corresponding addresses.
To summarize, the cold side create and saves
private key generation information and address generation information.
It has a one-time transfer of the address generation information to the hot side.
The hot side generates a new address
sequentially every time it wants to send a coin to the cold side.
When a cold side reconnects,
it generates addresses sequentially and
checks the blockchain for transfers to these addresses.
It can also generate private keys
sequentially if it wants to send some coins back to the hot side.