The key to a botnet success is efficient
and robust command and control.
And this is not always easy.
The simplest,
most efficient way to perform command
control is through centralized control.
For example through IRC command or
command, he can instruct
the bots to send spam.
However this kind of command
control is not robust.
Even though it's very efficient, because
it has a single point of failure.
There's only one command
channel from the attacker.
For example the IRC
channel can be taken down.
Or the twitter account can be shut down.
A more robust command control structure
is to use peer to peer network.
Here, the botmaster can
connect to a number of bots
in this peer to peer network.
And upload his commands,
and update to the malware.
And make advertisements, so
that other bots can get the command and
updates from the peers.
The drawback is that the botmaster
does not have direct
synchronized communication with autobot.
In fact, the Botmaster does not know how
many bots get it's commands and when.
Nowadays, the most popular approach for
command control is for
all the bots to connect to
a command control website.
Obviously, this is very efficient.
And the Botmaster can make
this set up more robust.
For example, the Botmaster can map this
website to different IP addresses.
The website is not always
fixed on one physical server.
It can be moved to different servers.
In fact, in Fast Flux, the Botmaster
can change the DNS IP mapping for
the website every ten seconds.
This can defeat detection or
blocking, based on IP addresses.
But since the domain
name is not changed,
this domain can still be detected as
using for botnet command control.
And the ISPs can't block
access to this domain.
Instead of using fixed domains
that can be detected and blocked.
Botmaster's now used
random domain generation.
On each day, a bot will generate a large
number of random looking domain names
and lock them up.
The Botmaster will knows exactly
the same set of random domain each day.
Because each domains are generated
using the same algorithm.
And same random seeker seed
straight between the botmaster and
the bot malware.
In the botmaster, only register
a few of these random domains.
Although each bot generates many random
domain names, and look up each of them.
Only few of them will actually
connect to the websites.
These are the sites that
are registered to the botmaster.
And of course, these sites can use fast
flux to move around on the internet.
By mapping to different IP
addresses every ten seconds.
This command and
control approach is very robust,
because it is hard for detection.
This is because each of these command
control domains are randomly looking.
And they're new.
And they are only used for
a very short period of time.
Say, one day.