It is estimated that more than 90%
of our email are actually spam.
That will translate into hundreds of
billions of spam messages every day.
Spammers play a very key role in
the underground economy and cybercrime.
They have contacts of many many
people and many organizations.
They send messages on
behalf of other bad actors.
They can be used to push malware or
phish to steal information.
Spammers typically use
botnets to send spam.
They need a large number of IP addresses
because otherwise, sending a large
number of emails from a few IP addresses
will easily trigger detection and
blocking by spam filters.
Let's start via few examples of how
spam works in the underground economy.
Many spammers are affiliates of
various kinds of scam campaigns.
Scammers typically set up websites
to sell counterfeit goods.
The scammers try to act legitimately
by delivering goods and
collecting payments.
They can even have customer services.
But how do the scam
websites attract traffic?
They need the spammers to advertise for
them.
And in return,
the spammers collect commissions.
For example,
the commission can be as high as 30
to 50% of the final sales price.
Now the key to the success
of both the scammers and
the spammers is the spam
conversion rate.
The spam conversion rate is
the percentage of spam messages
that result in a final sale.
We know that there
are spam filters around.
And we have the feeling that
a lot of them are very effective.
So why do spammers
continue to send spam?
And how many messages
get past spam filters?
We heard numbers such as more than
99% of the spams are filtered.
Any spam leads to
a successful transaction.
How much money can be made?
The only way to precisely answer
these questions is to infiltrate and
instrument the spam generation and
monetization process.
Because by doing so
we can find out exactly what's going on.