Let's discuss a case
study on Storm botnet.
This botnet was used to send spams.
And this research was performed by the
University of California in San Diego,
where the researchers penetrated
into the Storm botnet.
The researchers were able to
measure the percentage of spam
that got through the spam filters.
Here are different campaigns
carried out by the spams.
Pharmacy is a spam advertising
an online pharmacy.
The postcard and April Fool campaigns
are for installing malware.
As we can see here from data that's
available, there are spam filters
that can actually filter out more
than 99% of the spam messages.
On average, only 0.014% of
the spam messages that can get
through the filters, which translates
into 1 in more than 7,000.
Looking at the whole lifecycle of
a spam message, some get not delivered,
some get blocked by spam filters,
some are ignored by the users, and
users may just leave the sites.
Of course, some of them will
actually commit a transaction.
But some of these traffics
are due to crawlers,
meaning that they're not actual users.
This table shows that for each campaign,
what's the percentage of
spams that can be delivered,
filtered, result in user visiting
the website, and user conversion.
Obviously, user conversion is
the most interesting number
that we should look at.
For pharmacy, it's 1 in 1,737.
For postcard, it's 1 in 37.
For April Fool, it's 1 in 25.
This conversion rate is computed for the
spams that got into the user's inbox.
How many of them result
in user transactions?
The pharmacy campaign advertise
a fake online pharmacy.
The researchers observed that there
were 28 purchases in 26 days.
The average price per purchase is $100.
But the researchers only controlled
1.5% of the bots sending the spams.
If we extrapolate this amount
to the whole botnet population,
then we get close to $9500 a day,
or $3.5 million a year.
Of course, the scammer and
spammer will divvy up this money.
So the Storm operators or the spammers
will get $1.7 million a year.