With the example storm botnets,
you may think that making money
is easy in the underground.
Actually, it is not easy.
In fact, scamming is supported by
a whole ecosystem that includes
network infrastructure and
payment system.
For example, we're going to
start the pharmaceutical scams.
Suppose you want to set up a website
called canadianpharma.com.
The question is that how do you do this?
What sort of infrastructure do you need?
Because obviously you should worry
about law enforcement agencies
shutting down your website.
Even before that, you should worry
about that legitimate registers
may not even let you
register your domain name.
So you go to the shady registrars,
but they would charge you more.
After you obtain your domain,
you want a DNS server that map
the domain name into an IP address.
Some DNS providers will shut down
your domain if they hear complaints.
So you go to the so-called
bulletproof DNS providers,
that operates in lawless land,
but they are expensive.
Now to set up your website,
you need to stand up a web server.
For example, a machine in ISP.
But, the ISP or law enforcement
can shut down your website.
So, you want to go to
the bulletproof network providers.
Again, they're expensive.
There are indeed service providers that
offer very low priced, resilient hosting
services, but obviously they
are very expensive after you set up
the network infrastructure, now you need
to consider how do you receive payments.
Basically you need to handle
credit card payments and
get money out of these accounts.
The trouble is that most banks and
credit card processors won't
do business with scammers.
Again your solution is to go to a few
banks in some lawless countries
to handle your payment.
To be successful in scamming,
you almost have to learn it
like a legitimate business.
For example, you should ship
products to customers, why?
Because if the customers are not happy,
they will complain and
the processors and
banks will shut down your accounts.