As we have discussed, there are quite a
few types of bad actors in a cyber space
and they form
an interconnected ecosystem.
For example, a botnet is created
when computers are compromised,
a malware is installed and
a botnet is used to launch a number of
malicious and fraudulent activities.
For example these are activities
that can be launched by botnet,
in particular spam.
Spam can be used to facilitate a number
of other activities such as phishing,
selling counterfeit goods or
malware installation.
Again, the point here is that the bad
actors form an interconnected
ecosystem because their activities or
even structures support each other.