Underground forums are one
the entry points of the bad guy's
communication systems, especially for
those new to the underground.
There are many underground
forums on the Internet.
And they're just one search and
one click away.
And there are a large number
of illicit activities
being advertised on these forums.
Obviously law enforcements are watching
and can shut down these sites.
However, new forums can always
pop up and fill the void.
These forums also provide valuable
data sources to researchers.
For example, researchers can study
the data to learn about new trends and
detect unfolding attacks.
The forums are full of buyers,
sellers, and the rippers.
There are honest deal makings but
there are also rip-offs of the buyers.
Basically, these forums are as regulated
as what administrators can handle.
Most messages on the forums
are just advertisements.
For example, one can advertise that
he has stolen bank accounts or
access to computers or email lists.
One can ask for
stolen credit card numbers in exchange
for access to a hacked LINIX machine.
Many of these advertisements
include evidence
of the advertisers capabilities.
For example, to demonstrate that
the stolen accounts are valid or
show a sample of the stolen information.
Again, the forum is typically
useful just advertisement.
The actual due-making is typically
done via private messaging.