Now let's discuss a few
underground activities.
The first is Exploits-as-a-Service.
In the past, compromising
computer systems and use them for
profit are typically done by the same
criminal or criminals gangs.
For example, the same criminal gangs
will develop their own exploits,
launch them, and then use
the hacked machines to make money.
Nowadays the bad guys are specialized
and do different functions.
For example, there are developers who
develop exploit kits and packets, and
sell them to other bad guys.
And the other bad guys
are responsible for
using these exploit kits
to compromise computers.
For example, they can send out
spam with malware attachment.
Or they can put the malware in
a compromised web servers, so
that when a victim's computer visit
those servers, they will be compromised.
These compromised computers are then
sold on the black market so that
other bad guys can use them to launch
malicious and fraudulent activities.
And the bad actors here are being
paid using the pay-per-install model.
Let's discuss exploits-as-a-service,
and in particular,
the pay-per-install
model in more details.
One way to distribute malware, or
causing computers to be compromised
by the malware, is through so
called drive-by-download.
Basically a website is compromised to
have malware embedded in their scripts.
And then when a client
computer visits the website,
the malware will be
installed on their computer.
The number of exploit kits
that package the malware, and
install the malware on
the client computers.
There are two components in this
malware distribution model.
The first is that the bad guy needs
the exploit kit because the exploit kit
will be responsible for installing
the malware on the victim computers.
The bad guys can buy an exploit kit and
deploy it themselves.
Or, they can simply rent
access to exploit server
that hosts the exploit kit.
In the first option,
the bad guy needs to figure out how to
distribute the malware themself, and
typically that means at least he has
to set up a server with exploit kits.
A more convenient option is for
the bad guy to rent access to a server
that already hosts an exploit kit.
The second component of this
malware distribution model is that
the bad guy needs to have the kind
computers visit the exploit server so
that malware will be
installed on these computers.
The most common way to accomplish
this is to use spam or
phishing to attract traffic
to this exploit server.
Traffic paper install simplifies
this malware dispersion process.
It essentially combine the two
elements into a single service.
And pay-per-install is now the most
popular way of distributing malware.